[
  {
    "Question_Text": "When the time is 5:40, then what is the angle between the hour hand and the minute hand of a clock?",
    "choice_1": "70°",
    "choice_2": "60°",
    "choice_3": "74°",
    "choice_4": "80°",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "θ=(11/2)M -30H \n θ=(11/2)40 -30×5 = 70°",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "At what time between 7 and 8 o'clock will the hands of a clock be in the same straight line but, not together?",
    "choice_1": "5 min past 7",
    "choice_2": "5 2/11 min past 7",
    "choice_3": "5 3/11 min past 7",
    "choice_4": "5 5/11 min past 7",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Formula : | (11/2) * min – 30 * hr |\n \n 180 = 30 x 7- 11x/2\n 180 = 210- 11x/2\n 30 = 11x/2\n x = 60/11\n x=5 5/11",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "How many times hr and minute hands in the straight line in a day?",
    "choice_1": 21,
    "choice_2": 22,
    "choice_3": 42,
    "choice_4": 44,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "-",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "How many times hour and minute hands at the right angle in a day?",
    "choice_1": 21,
    "choice_2": 22,
    "choice_3": 42,
    "choice_4": 44,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "-",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "At what time between 7 and 8 ‘o’clock are the hands of a clock at an angle of 45 degree?",
    "choice_1": "7:30",
    "choice_2": "7:45",
    "choice_3": "7:50",
    "choice_4": "7:15",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "45 = 60 * 7 – 11M / 2\n 90 – 420 / 11 = M\n M = 330 /11 \n Min = 30\n Angle 45 degrees is at 7 : 30",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Consider the following statements: \n 1. Between 3:16 pm. and 3:17 pm, both hour hand and minute hand 'coincide. \n 2. Between 4:58 pm. and 4:59 p.m.. both minute hand and second hand coincide. \n Which of the above statements is/are correct?",
    "choice_1": "1 only",
    "choice_2": "2 only",
    "choice_3": "Both 1 and 2",
    "choice_4": "Neither 1 nor 2",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Coincide at 3 past 15. As per the formula, 15*12/11 = 3:16 to 3:17. Every minute, second hand and minute hand coincide.",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A bell rings every 18 minutes. A second bell rings every 24 minutes. A third bell rings every 32 minutes. If all the three bells ring at the same time at 8 0'clock in the morning, at what other time will they all ring together?",
    "choice_1": "12:40 hrs",
    "choice_2": "12:48 hrs",
    "choice_3": "12 : 56 hrs",
    "choice_4": "13 : 04 hrs",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "LCM 18,24,32 = 288. If convert in to hrs = 288/60 = 4 hrs 48 min",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The minute hand of a clock overtakes the hour hand at intervals of 64 minutes of correct time. How much does the clock gain or lose in 12 hours?",
    "choice_1": "16(5/11) min",
    "choice_2": "16(4/11) min",
    "choice_3": "16(6/11) min",
    "choice_4": "16(7/11) min",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Formula: (720/11 - M)(24 x 60/M) mins.\n \n here, M is the intervals of n minutes of the correct time. 1day = 24 hr,\n Given n = 64\n Substituting in the formula:\n (720/11 - 64)(12x 60)/64\n 720-704/11 * (12*60)/64\n 16/11 * 45/4\n 4/11*45\n 180/11\n 16 4/11 min",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the water image of 4:40?",
    "choice_1": "12:50",
    "choice_2": "1:50",
    "choice_3": "2:55",
    "choice_4": "1:55",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "18:30 17:90 - \n 4:40 = 13:50\n 13:50 - 12:00 = 1: 50",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A digital wristwatch was set accurately at 8.30 a.m. and then lost 2 seconds every 5 minutes. What time was indicated on the watch at 6.30 p.m. of the same day if the watch operated continuously till that time?",
    "choice_1": "5: 56p.m",
    "choice_2": "5:58 p.m.",
    "choice_3": "6.26 p.m.",
    "choice_4": "6.00 p.m.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "1hr = 60 min \n 5min = 2 sec lose\n 60 min = 24 sec \n \n 8:30 – 6:30 è 10 hrs è 24* 10 = 240 sec è 240/60 min è 4 min",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man started from home at 14:30 hours and drove to village, arriving there when the village clock indicated 15:15 hours. After staying for 25 minutes, he drove back by a different route of length 1.25 times the first route at a rate twice as fast reaching home at 16:00 hours. As compared to the clock at home, the village clock is",
    "choice_1": "10 min slow",
    "choice_2": "10 min fast",
    "choice_3": "5 min slow",
    "choice_4": "5 min fast",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Speed of man - x km/hr;distance b/w village and home - y km;\n total time during travel = 3/2 hrs - 25/60 hrs = 13/12 hrs. Use of Time, speed, distance equation\n y/x + 1.25y/2x = 13/12.\n y/x = 40 min.The time to reach village is actually 15:10. Therefore village clock is 5 mins fast.",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A wall clock moves 10 minutes fast in every 24 hours. The clock was set right to show the correct time at 8:00 am. on Monday. When the clock shows the time 6:00 p.m. on Wednesday, what is the correct time?",
    "choice_1": "5 hrs 36 min",
    "choice_2": "6 hrs 36 min",
    "choice_3": "4 hrs 36 min",
    "choice_4": "3 hrs 36 min",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "For every 24 hrs, 10 mins fast, there are 82 hrs ahead from Monday 8:00 am to Wednesday 6:00 pm. for 24 hrs, 10 mins fast, for 82 hrs 10/24 * 82 = approx 34 mins fas, The clock shows 6:00 pm on Wednesday, that is 34 mins fast, the actual time is 6:00 - 00:34 = 5 hrs 36 min",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Assume that \n 1. the hour and minute hands of a clock move without jerking. \n 2. the clock shows a time between 8 0'clock and 9 0'clock. \n 3. the two hands of the clock are one above the other. \n After how many minutes ( nearest integer) will the two hands be again lying one above the \n other?",
    "choice_1": 67,
    "choice_2": 62,
    "choice_3": 65,
    "choice_4": 63,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "At 8:45, the hands are one above other. The exact time is 45*12/11 = 8:43:40\n Next coincidence will be at 9:45; The exact time is 45*12/11 = 9:49:01\n the time difference is around 65 minutes",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A watch loses 2 minutes in every 24 hours while another watch gains 2 minutes in every 24 hours. At a particular instant, the two watchers showed an identical time. Which of the following statements is correct if 24 - hour clock is followed?",
    "choice_1": "The two watches show the identical time again on completion of 30 days.",
    "choice_2": "The two watches show the identical time again on completion of 90 days.",
    "choice_3": "The two watches show the identical again on completion of 120 days.",
    "choice_4": "None of the above statements is correct.",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "A watch loses 2 minutes in every 24 hours, while another watch gains 2 minutes in every 24 hours. \n Therefore, every day(24 hours) the time difference between the two watches will keep on \n increasing by 4 minutes. This means that the two watches will again show the same \n identical time when this difference increases to 24 hours, i.e. \n 24 x 60 minutes 1440 minutes. \n By unitary method, \n The difference of 4 minutes is reached in 1 day. \n The difference of 1 minutes is reached in 1/4 day. \n The difference of 1440 minutes is reached in 1440/4 — 360 days. \n Hence, None of the above statements is correct.",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The minor angle between the hours hand and minutes hand of a clock was observed at 8:48 am. The minimum duration, in minutes, after 8.48 am when this angle increases by 50% is",
    "choice_1": "36/11",
    "choice_2": "26/11",
    "choice_3": "24/11",
    "choice_4": "31/11",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "FINDING ANGLES\n If ‘HH:MM’ given,\n HH x 30˚ - HH x 11/2˚\n 08 x 30˚ - 48 x 11/2˚ \n 240 ˚ - 264 ˚ = 24˚ (angle < 180˚)\n ∴ angle increases by 50% \n 150% of 24 = 36˚\n Increase angle from 264˚ to 276˚\n 48 x 11/2˚ = 264 and X x 11/2˚ =276\n 264/48 = 276/x;\n By solving the above two terms, we get\n X = 552/11 ~ 50 (2/11) min\n minimum duration, in minutes, after 8.48 am when this angle increases by 50% is = 50 (2/11) min – 48 min = 24/11",
    "Topic": "Clocks"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "It was Tuesday on Feb 8, 2005. What was the day of the week\n  on Feb 8, 2004?",
    "choice_1": "Sunday",
    "choice_2": "Monday",
    "choice_3": "Tuesday",
    "choice_4": "Friday",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The year 2004 was a leap year. So, it had 2 odd days. The day on Feb 8, 2004 must be 2 days before the day on Feb 8, 2005. Hence, this day was Sunday",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "How many odd days are there in a leap year?",
    "choice_1": 2,
    "choice_2": 1,
    "choice_3": 3,
    "choice_4": 0,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "366 ÷ 7 = 52 weeks + 2 days → 2 odd days in a leap year",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "How many odd days are there in 100 years?",
    "choice_1": 3,
    "choice_2": 5,
    "choice_3": 1,
    "choice_4": 2,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "76 normal years = 76 odd days, 24 leap = 48. Total = 124 → 124 ÷ 7 = 17 weeks + 5 odd days",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What was the day of week falls on 29th May 2021?",
    "choice_1": "Saturday",
    "choice_2": "Sunday",
    "choice_3": "Thursday",
    "choice_4": "Wednesday",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "21+ 5 + 29 + 1 + 6 = 62/7 è= 6(SATURDAY)",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What dates of April 2001 did fall on Wednesday?",
    "choice_1": "1,8,15,22,29",
    "choice_2": "2,9,18,23,30",
    "choice_3": "3,10,17,24",
    "choice_4": "4,11,18,25",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "April 1 2001 à 1+0+1+6+6=14/7=0 (sunday)\n \n  April 1, 2001 was Sunday → April 4 = Wednesday → add 7 days",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "How many seconds in total are there in x weeks, x days, x hours, x minutes, x seconds?",
    "choice_1": "544860 x",
    "choice_2": "544861 x",
    "choice_3": "694860 x",
    "choice_4": "694861 x",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "If we go in revers, 1 sec + 3600 sec (1 hr) +86400 (1 day) + 604800(1 week) = 694861.\n We took x = 1, the the answer will be 694861 x",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If second and fourth Saturdays and all the Sundays are taken as only holidays for an office, \n what would be the minimum number of possible working days of any month of any year?",
    "choice_1": 22,
    "choice_2": 23,
    "choice_3": 261,
    "choice_4": 24,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Take february of an ordinary year. There are four Sunday and Four Saturday. Here there are 6 holidays. (4 Sunday and 2 saturdays). So The total is 22 days",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which date of June 2099 among the following is Monday?",
    "choice_1": 4,
    "choice_2": 5,
    "choice_3": 6,
    "choice_4": 7,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Find the day of June 4, 2099.\n Last two digit of year = 99\n Quotient = 24\n Date = 4\n month code = 4\n Year code = 6\n Total = 137\n remainder 4 = Thursday, then 7th is Sunday",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Mr 'X' has three children. The birthday of the first child falls on the 5th Monday of April, that of the second one falls on the 5th Thursday of November. On which day is the birthday of his third child, which falls on 20th December?",
    "choice_1": "Friday",
    "choice_2": "Thursday",
    "choice_3": "Sunday",
    "choice_4": "Monday",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "5th Monday may be falls on 29th or 30th April. If 29th April is Monday, then the second child birthday falls on 29th November, that is Friday. If 30th April is 5th Monday, then November 29th will be Thursday. Then December 20th will be Thursday.",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In 2016, Mohan celebrated his birthday on Friday. Which will be the firstyear after 2016 when Mohan will celebrate his birthday on a Wednesday? (He was not born in January or February)",
    "choice_1": 2021,
    "choice_2": 2023,
    "choice_3": 2020,
    "choice_4": 2025,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Since it has been mentioned that Mohan was not born in February, so he can’t be born on 2 \n 9th Feb. Hence He will celebrate his next birthday on a Wednesday in the year for which th \n e sum of the odd days becomes 5 or a multiple of 5. \n By his birthday in 2017, there will be 1 odd day. \n By his birthday in 2018, there will be 2 odd days. \n By his birthday in 2019, there will be 3 odd days. \n By his birthday in 2020, there will be 5 odd days, as 2020 is a leap year. \n So in 2020 He will celebrate his birthday on Wednesday.",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "John was born on Feb 29th of 2012 which happened to be a Wednesday. If he lives to be 101 years old, how many birthdays would he celebrate on a Wednesday?",
    "choice_1": 3,
    "choice_2": 4,
    "choice_3": 5,
    "choice_4": 1,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Let us do this iteratively. Feb 29th 2012 = Wednesday => Feb 28th 2012 = Tuesday\n Feb 28th 2013 = Thursday (because 2012 is a leap year, there will be 2 odd days)\n Feb 28th 2014 = Friday, Feb 28th 2015 = Saturday, Feb 28th 2016 = Sunday, Feb 29th 2016 = Monday\n Or, Feb 29th to Feb 29th after 4 years, we have 5 odd days.\n \n So, every subsequent birthday, would come after 5 odd days.\n 2016 birthday – 5 odd days\n 2020 birthday – 10 odd days = 3 odd days\n 2024 birthday – 8 odd days = 1 odd day\n 2028 birthday – 6 odd days\n 2032 birthday – 11 odd days = 4 odd days\n 2036 birthday – 9 odd days = 2 odd days\n 2040 birthday – 7 odd days = 0 odd days. So, after 28 years he would have a birthday on Wednesday\n \n The next birthday on Wednesday would be on 2068 (further 28 years later), the one after that would be on 2096. His 84th birthday would again be a leap year.\n \n Now, there is a twist again, as 2100 is not a leap year. So, he does not have a birthday in 2100. His next birthday in 2104 would be after 9 odd days since 2096, or 2 odd days since 2096, or on a Thursday.\n \n From now on the same pattern continues. 2108 would be 2 + 5 odd days later = 7 odd days later. Or, 2108 Feb 29th would be a Wednesday.\n So, there are 4 occurrences of birthday falling on Wednesday – 2040, 2068, 2096 and 2108.\n \n The question is \"How many birthdays would he celebrate on a Wednesday?\"\n \n Hence, the answer is \"4\".",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "How many of the following statements have to be true?\n i. No year can have 5 Sundays in the month of May and 5 Thursdays in the month of June.\n ii. If Feb 14th of a certain year is a Friday, May 14th of the same year cannot be a Thursday\n iii. If a year has 53 Sundays, it can have 5 Mondays in the month of May.",
    "choice_1": 0,
    "choice_2": 1,
    "choice_3": 2,
    "choice_4": 3,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "If Feb 14th of a certain year is a Friday, May 14th of the same year cannot be a Thursday\n From Feb 14 to Mar 14, there are 28 or 29 days, 0 or 1 odd day\n Mar 14 to Apr 14, there are 31 days, or 3 odd days\n Apr 14 to May 14 there are 30 days or 2 odd days\n So, Feb 14 to May 14, there are either 5 or 6 odd days\n So, if Feb 14 is Friday, May 14 can be either Thursday or Wednesday. So, statement II need not be true.",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The last day of a century cannot be",
    "choice_1": "Monday",
    "choice_2": "Wednesday",
    "choice_3": "Friday",
    "choice_4": "Tuesday",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Dec 31, 100 – 5 odd days - fri\n Dec 31, 200 – 3 odd days - Monday\n Dec 31 – 1 odd day - Monday\n Dec 31 – 400 – 0 odd days – Sunday.\n The above cycle repeats, Tuesday, Saturday, Thursday will not come",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A year 1895 is having a same calendar as that of the year X. \n Which of the following is a possible value of X.",
    "choice_1": 1900,
    "choice_2": 1901,
    "choice_3": 1902,
    "choice_4": 1903,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "1895 is not a leap year. It has 1 odd day.\n Since 1896 is a leap year, it will add 2 odd days.\n Similarly 1987, 1898, 1899, 1900 will add 1,1,1,1 odd days.\n Now the total number of odd days add up to 7.\n So the next year 1901 will have the same calendar as 1895.",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "For a certain month, the dates of three of the Sundays are even numbers. Then, the 15th of the that month falls on",
    "choice_1": "Thursday",
    "choice_2": "Friday",
    "choice_3": "Saturday",
    "choice_4": "Sunday",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "The dates of three of the Sundays are even number is\n 2, 9, 16, 23, 30.\n So, on 16th of that month = Sunday, 15th of that month\n falls on a Saturday",
    "Topic": "Calendar"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "One morning Udai and Vishal were talking to each other face to face at a crossing. If Vishal's shadow was exactly to the left of Udai, which direction was Udai facing?",
    "choice_1": "East",
    "choice_2": "West",
    "choice_3": "North",
    "choice_4": "South",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "In the morning, shadows fall towards the west. If Vishal’s shadow is to the left of Udai, then Udai is facing North.",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Y is in the East of X which is in the North of Z. If P is in the South of Z, then in which direction of Y, is P?",
    "choice_1": "North",
    "choice_2": "South",
    "choice_3": "South-East",
    "choice_4": "None of these",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "P is in the South of Z, and Z is South of X, which is West of Y. So P is South-West of Y → Answer: None of these.",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If South-East becomes North, North-East becomes West and so on. What will West become?",
    "choice_1": "North-East",
    "choice_2": "North-West",
    "choice_3": "South-East",
    "choice_4": "South-West",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Direction rotation pattern shifts 135° clockwise, so West becomes South-East.",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "One evening before sunset Rekha and Hema were talking to \n each other face to face. If Hema's shadow was exactly to the right\n  of Hema, which direction was Rekha facing?",
    "choice_1": "East",
    "choice_2": "West",
    "choice_3": "North",
    "choice_4": "South",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "If hema face north during sunset, her shadow will be right side.\n Hence Rekha is facing south",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": ". K is 40 m South-West of L. If M is 40 m South-East of L, \n  then M is in which direction of K?",
    "choice_1": "East",
    "choice_2": "West",
    "choice_3": "North",
    "choice_4": "South",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "From K to M = 40 m East direction.",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Rasik walked 20 m towards north. Then he turned right and\n  walks 30 m. Then he turns right and walks 35 m. Then he turns \n left and walks 15 m. Finally he turns left and walks 15 m. In which\n  direction and how many metres is he from the starting position?",
    "choice_1": "15 m west",
    "choice_2": "30m east",
    "choice_3": "30m West",
    "choice_4": "45 m East",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "N20 E30 S35 E15 N15\n \n N35 E45 S35\n \n E 45",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A boy rode his bicycle Northward, then turned left and rode \n 1 km and again turned left and rode 2 km. He found himself \n 1 km west of his starting point. How far did he ride northward \n initially?",
    "choice_1": "1 km",
    "choice_2": "2 km",
    "choice_3": "3 km",
    "choice_4": "4 km",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Given : N W1 S2 W1\n Rules : SAME è ADD\n  OPPOSITE è CANCEL\n \n W2 à 2 km \n \n Solution: He ended up 1 km west of start → Rode north 2 km, west 1 km, then south 1 km → Net north = 2 km.",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A girl leaves from her home. She first walks 30 metres in North-west direction and then 30 metres in South-west direction. Next, she walks 30 metres in South-east direction. Finally, she turns towards her house. In which direction is she moving?",
    "choice_1": "North-East",
    "choice_2": "North-West",
    "choice_3": "South-East",
    "choice_4": "South-West",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "So, as the girl is moving towards her house, she is moving towards point 'O' from point 'C' which is in the 'north-east' direction.\n \n Hence, \"north-east\" is the correct answer.",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Ramesh starting from a fixed point goes 15 km towards North and then after turning to his right he goes 15 km. then he goes 10, 15 and 15 metres after turning to his left each time. How far is he from his starting point?",
    "choice_1": "5 km",
    "choice_2": "7 km",
    "choice_3": "10 km",
    "choice_4": "15 km",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Somalia goes 12 km towards North from a fixed point and then she goes 8 km towards South from there. In the end she goes 3 km towards east. How far and in what direction is she from her starting point?",
    "choice_1": "5 km , NE",
    "choice_2": "7 km NW",
    "choice_3": "10 km SW",
    "choice_4": "15 km SE",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two cars start from the opposite places of a main road, 150 km\n  apart. First car runs for 25 km and takes a right turn and then runs \n 15 km. It then turns left and then runs for another 25 km and then\n  takes the direction back to reach the main road. In the mean time, \n due to minor break down the other car has run only 35 km along\n  the main road. What would be the distance between two cars at \n this point?",
    "choice_1": "65 km",
    "choice_2": "80 km",
    "choice_3": "75 km",
    "choice_4": "85 km",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Distance between starting points = 150 km.\n \n Journey of first bus = 25 km, then takes a right turn and then runs for 15 km, then turns left and runsfor another 25 km and takes the direction back to reach the main road.\n \n \n Journey of second bus = 35 km along the main road\n \n Calculations:\n \n Let first bus started from point X.\n \n After running for 25 km, it reaches point A.\n Then took a right turn and then runs for 15 km.\n  After reaching point B, turns left and runs parallel to main road for another 25 km.\n After reaching point C, takes the left turn and reached the main road at point D\n \n Total distance covered by the first bus along main road = 25 + 25 = 50 km\n \n Let second bus started from point Y.\n \n  Due to a minor breakdown, the second bus has run only 35 km along the main road and reached point E.\n \n Total distance covered by the second bus along main road = 35 km\n \n Distance between both the buses = 150 - (50 + 35)= 150 - 85= 65 km\n \n :. The distance between the two buses at the end is 65 km.",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Devika started from point A in North direction. After walking for 5 m she turned to her left and walked 6 m. Now she turned to her left and walked4 m after which she turned to her left again. Now she walked 5 m andturned to her right and walked 15 m. Now finally she turned to her left.In which direction is she heading?",
    "choice_1": "North-East",
    "choice_2": "South-West",
    "choice_3": "East",
    "choice_4": "West",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "SAME è ADD\n OPPOSITE è CANCEL\n \n N L L L R L è N L L L è FROM NORTH TURN 270 DEG è EAST\n \n [1 TURN EITHER RIGHT OR LEFT ITS 90 DEG]",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man walks in the directions given below(i) 50 m to East (ii) then 50 m to South (iii) and then 120 m to West (iv)later 25 m to North (v) and finally 70 m to East Then the distance (in meters) between the starting point and the last point is?",
    "choice_1": 50,
    "choice_2": 25,
    "choice_3": 30,
    "choice_4": 40,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Suresh walked 90 metres towards South and moves 85 m towards East and then moves a distance of 50 m towards North and then moves 45 m towards West. The distance from the starting point is?",
    "choice_1": 30,
    "choice_2": "60√ 2",
    "choice_3": "50 √2",
    "choice_4": "40 √ 2",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Here's the journey:\n - South: 90 m\n - East: 85 m\n - North: 50 m\n - West: 45 m\n Vertical (North-South):\n - South: 90 m\n - North: 50 m\n - Net vertical movement:\n 90 - 50 = 40 m South\n ➡️ Horizontal (East-West):\n - East: 85 m\n - West: 45 m.\n So, he ends up 40 meters south and 40 meters east of the starting point.\n Total Distance from Starting Point\n Using the Pythagorean theorem:\n \\text{Distance} = \\sqrt{(40)^2 + (40)^2} = \\sqrt{1600 + 1600} = \\sqrt{3200} \\approx \\boxed{56.57 \\text{ meters}}\n \n ✅ Final Answer\n Suresh is approximately 56.57 meters away from his starting point.",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A person starts walking from his house to go to the nearby park. He travels 5 m to the East, then travels 10 m to the left and then travels 8 m to the right. He further travels 2 m North and finally travels 3 m east to reach the park. How far is the park from his house?",
    "choice_1": "20 m",
    "choice_2": "40 m",
    "choice_3": "60 m",
    "choice_4": "80 m",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Using Pythogorous theorm, Answer is 20 m",
    "Topic": "Direction Sense"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the ratio of the total surface area of a cube to its volume?",
    "choice_1": "1:a",
    "choice_2": "2:a",
    "choice_3": "3:a",
    "choice_4": "6:a",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Volume = a³, TSA = 6a² → TSA : Volume = 6a² : a³ = 6 : a",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "How many edges does a cube have?",
    "choice_1": 8,
    "choice_2": 12,
    "choice_3": 16,
    "choice_4": 16,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A cube has 12 edges.",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A cube is cut into 64 smaller equal cubes. How many cuts are made along each dimension (length, width, and height)?",
    "choice_1": 2,
    "choice_2": 4,
    "choice_3": 8,
    "choice_4": 5,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "To get 64 cubes = 4 cuts along each dimension → 4 × 4 × 4 = 64",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If a cube is painted on all its faces and then cut into 27 smaller cubes\n cubes, how many of these cubes will have exactly three painted faces?",
    "choice_1": 4,
    "choice_2": 6,
    "choice_3": 8,
    "choice_4": 12,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "These are corner cubes; a cube has 8 corners.",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If the sum of all the edges of a cube is 144 cm, what is the \n      length of one edge?",
    "choice_1": "10 cm",
    "choice_2": "12 cm",
    "choice_3": "15 cm",
    "choice_4": "18 cm",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Total edge length = 12a → 12a = 144 → a = 12 cm",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If a cube is sliced into 8 smaller equal cubes, how many of these \nwill have exactly one face painted if the original cube was painted \non all its sides?",
    "choice_1": 1,
    "choice_2": 2,
    "choice_3": 4,
    "choice_4": 6,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Each face center cube has 1 face painted → 6 such cubes.",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A cube having an edge of 8 cm each. It is painted red on two opposite faces, blue on one other pair of opposite faces, black on one more face and one face is left unpainted. Then it is cut into smaller cubes of 1 cm each. Then The no. of smaller cubes which are having one-face painted.",
    "choice_1": 252,
    "choice_2": 204,
    "choice_3": 212,
    "choice_4": 216,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "6-1(UNPAINTED SIDE) = 5* 36 => 180 +24(in 4 edges –> 6 cubes is painted one side in extreme bcoz other side is unpainted)",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A cube having an edge of 12 cm each. It is painted red on two opposite faces, blue on one other pair of opposite faces, black on one more face and one face is left unpainted. Then it is cut into smaller cubes of 1 cm each. Then the no. of smaller cubes which are having zero-face painted are",
    "choice_1": 1100,
    "choice_2": 1016,
    "choice_3": 1002,
    "choice_4": 1198,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "1728 – 4-84-540  1100",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A cube of side 125 cm is painted red on all the faces and then cut into smaller cubes of sides 25 cm each. Find the number of smaller cubes having at least two faces painted.",
    "choice_1": 44,
    "choice_2": 48,
    "choice_3": 36,
    "choice_4": 42,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Length of the side of the big cube = 125 cm.\nLength of the side of the smaller cube = 25 cm.\n\nn = No. of parts of each side  Length of the side of the larger cube + length of the side of the smaller cube\n\nn = 125/ 25 = 5\n\nn - 2 = 3\n\nNumber of smaller cubes having at least two faces painted = total no. of cubes - (no. of cubes with no face painted + no. of cubes with only one face painted)\n\n 125 - (3^3 + 6 × 3^2)\n\n 125 - (27 + 54)\n\n 125 - 81= 44\n\nHence, 44 is the correct answer.",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A cube is cut in two equal parts along a plane parallel to one of its faces. One piece is then coloured red on the two larger faces and green on the remaining, while the other is coloured green on two smaller adjacent faces and red on the remaining. Each is then cut into 32 cubes of same size and mixed up. How many cubes have only one coloured face each ?",
    "choice_1": 8,
    "choice_2": 16,
    "choice_3": 12,
    "choice_4": 14,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "One side painted in cube 1 = 8 \nOne side painted in cube 2 = 8  \n\nTotal = 16",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A cuboid shaped wooden block has 6 cm length, 4 cm breadth and 1 cm height. \n(i) Two faces measuring 4 cm x 1 cm are coloured in Black. \n(ii) Two faces 6 cm x 1 cm are coloured in Red. \n(ii) Two faces 6 cm x 4 cm are coloured in Green.\nNow the block is divided into 6 equal cubes of  1 cm each (from 6 cm side) and 4 equal cubes of  1 cm each (from 4 cm side) \nHow many cubes will remain if the cubes having black and green colored are removed?",
    "choice_1": 12,
    "choice_2": 28,
    "choice_3": 22,
    "choice_4": 16,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "No. of small cubes which are black and green are 8 in all. Hence, the number Of remaining cubes = 24 – 8 = 16 \n(2 surface painted)",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A cuboid has six sides of different colours. The red side is opposite to black. The blue side is adjacent to white. The brown side is adjacent to blue. The red side is face down. Which one of the following would be the opposite to brown?",
    "choice_1": "Red",
    "choice_2": "Black",
    "choice_3": "White",
    "choice_4": "Blue",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A large cuboid having dimensions 6 x 5 x 3 are coloured on two of the largest surface and then broken into smaller identical cubes having dimensions 1 x 1 x 1. How many of these smaller cubes will not have colour on them?",
    "choice_1": 36,
    "choice_2": 64,
    "choice_3": 40,
    "choice_4": 30,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Number of cubes which have 1 x 1 x 1 dimension = 6 x 5 x 3= 90\n\nCubes which have colour on them (i.e., the cubes which lie on the two of the largest surface that is coloured) \n\n= 2 x (6 x 5)\n= 2 x 30\n= 60\n\nCubes which do not have colour on them = 90 - 60 = 30",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A cuboid of dimensions 4 in.* 6 in.* 7 in. is painted on all six faces with the same colour. It is then completely cut into identical small cubes, each side 1 in. What is the ratio of the number of cubes with no face painted to the number of cubes with exactly one face painted to those with exactly two faces painted?",
    "choice_1": "10:19:11",
    "choice_2": "11:19:10",
    "choice_3": "20:19:11",
    "choice_4": "20:38:11",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Size of the cuboid = 4 x 6 x 7\n\nFor cubes with no face colored:\n\nWe need to remove a layer of cubes from the top, bottom, left, right, front and back.\nThe resulting figure will have no color.\n\nNumber of cubes with 0 side painted = (a-2) (b-2) (c-2)\n\nThus, number of cubes = (4 - 2) x (6 - 2) x (7 - 2) = 40 cubes\n\nFor cubes with one face colored:\n\nWe need to find the central areas of each face (shown in gray in the image). Thus, there would be:\n\nNumber of cubes with 1 sides painted  = 2[(a-2) (b-2) + (b-2)(c-2) + (a-2)(c-2) ]\n\n2 faces with (4 - 2) x (6 - 2) = 8 *2 cubes each => 16 cubes\n2 faces with (7 - 2) x (6 - 2) = 20* 2 cubes each => 40 cubes\n2 faces with (7 - 2) x (4 - 2) = 10*2  cubes each => 20 cubes\nThus, number of cubes = 16 + 40 + 20 = 76 cubes\n\nFor cubes with two faces colored:\n\nWe need to find the number of cubes along the edges (shown in brown in the image):\n(Note: We should ignore the corners, since the corners are cubes with 3 faces colored)\n\nThere are 12 edges - 4 edges with 7 cubes along it, 4 edges with 6 cubes along it and 4 edges with 4 cubes along it. Thus, we have:\n\nNumber of cubes with 2 sides painted =  4(a+b+c -6)\n\n4 edges with (4 - 2) = 2 cubes each => 8 cubes\n4 edges with (6 - 2) = 4 cubes each => 16 cubes\n4 edges with (7 - 2) = 5 cubes each => 20 cubes\n\nThus, number of cubes = 8 + 16 + 20 = 44 cubes\n\n=> Required ratio = 40 : 76 : 44 = 10 : 19 : 11",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A cuboid shaped wooden block has 6 cm length, 4 cm breadth and 1 cm height. \n(i) Two faces measuring 4 cm x 1 cm are coloured in Black. \n(ii) Two faces 6 cm x 1 cm are coloured in Red. \n(ii) Two faces 6 cm x 4 cm are coloured in Green.\nNow the block is divided into 6 equal cubes of  1 cm each (from 6 cm side) and 4 equal cubes of  1 cm each (from 4 cm side) \nHow many cubes having red, green and black colours on at least one side of the cube will be formed?",
    "choice_1": 2,
    "choice_2": 4,
    "choice_3": 6,
    "choice_4": 8,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Such cubes are related to the corners of the cuboid. Since the number of corners of the cuboid is 4. Hence, the number of such small cubes is 4.",
    "Topic": "Cubes"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the value of ‘x’?\nStatement 1 : x^2 - 5x +6 = 0  \nStatement 2 : x > 0",
    "choice_1": "Statement (1) ALONE is sufficient, but statement (2) alone is not sufficient",
    "choice_2": "Statement (2) ALONE is sufficient, but statement (1) alone is not sufficient",
    "choice_3": "BOTH statements TOGETHER are sufficient, but NEITHER statement ALONE is sufficient.",
    "choice_4": "Statements (1) and (2) TOGETHER are not sufficient",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In which year was Rahul born? \nStatement 1 : Rahul at present is 25 years younger to his mother. Statement 2 : Rahul's brother, who was born in 1964, is 35 years younger to his mother.",
    "choice_1": "Statement 1 alone is sufficient",
    "choice_2": "Statement 2 alone is sufficient",
    "choice_3": "Both statement 1 and statement 2 are sufficient",
    "choice_4": "Both statement 1 and statement 2 even together are not sufficient",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Car A is moving behind car B in the same direction and the distance between them initially is 40 km and the speed of car B is 50 km/hr, then how long would car A take to cross car B.[Assume the length of the cars to be negligible] \n\nStatements 1:  The time taken car B to cover a distance of 200 km is 4 hours.\nStatements 2: If the cars were moving in the opposite directions, towards each other, the relative speed of car A with respect of car B would have been 120 km/hr.",
    "choice_1": "If the data in statement I alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement II alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_2": "If the data in statement II alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement I alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_3": "If the data either in statement I alone or statement II alone is  sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_4": "If the data in both statement I and II together are neccessary to answer the question",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Statement 1  again we are finding speed of car B\n\nSatement 2: \n\nthe sum of their speeds is 120 km/hr.\nSince car B's speed is 50 km/hr, car A's speed is  120−50=70 km/hr.\nNow, with car A's speed (70 km/hr) and car B's speed (50 km/hr), the relative speed when moving in the same direction is 70−50=20 km/hr.\nTo find the time taken for car A to cross car B, we use the formula:\nTime=Distance​/Relative Speed=40 km/20 km/hr​=2 hours",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "`Is the average age of the students of a school less than 17 years?\nStatement I : The strength of the class VIII is less than 25% of the strength of the school.\nStatement II : The average age of the students of class VIII of the school is 18 years and that of the remaining classes is 16 years.",
    "choice_1": "If the data in statement I alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement II alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_2": "If the data in statement II alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement I alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_3": "If the data either in statement I alone or statement II alone is  sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_4": "If the data in both statement I and II together are neccessary to answer the question",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Total number of students in the school = S (ASSUME = 1000)\nNumber of students in class VIII =C (= 25%  250)\nTherefore, number of students in remaining classes = S – C ( 750)\nThe overall average age (A) can be calculated as:\n\u000bA = [250 * 18 + 750* 16] / 1000\nWe can simplify this:\u000bA = 16.5\nWe want to know if A < 17:\u000b\nSince 16.5 is definitely less than 17, combining both statements tells us that the average age is less than 17.",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the two-digit number.\nStatement I : The difference between the digits and the product of the digits of the numbers are 2 and 15 respectively.\nStatement II : The digit at the ten's place is less than the digit at unit's place.",
    "choice_1": "If the data in statement I alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement II alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_2": "If the data in statement II alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement I alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_3": "If the data either in statement I alone or statement II alone is  sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_4": "If the data in both statement I and II together are neccessary to answer the question",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Difference between digits: |3 - 5| = 2 ✔\nProduct of digits: 3 × 5 = 15 ✔\n\nAccording to statement 2: Ten's digit less than unit's digit: 3 < 5 ✔",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Six Professors have been assigned to take up lectures in a week, starting from Monday till Saturday. The six Professors are Mandeep, Nitin, Ondrilla, Pankhuri, Yukti and Rati. How many Professors conduct lectures before Ondrilla?\nStatement I: Pankhuri conducts her lecture at least before three people. Mandeep gave the lecture conducted on Philosophy on Tuesday.\nStatement II: Yukti is given the lecture before at least one of the other lecturers. Ondrilla conducted her Physics lecture immediately on the next day as Pankhuri’s lecture.\nStatement III: A minimum of four lectures were conducted after Nitin’s lecture",
    "choice_1": "If data in only Statement I & III is sufficient",
    "choice_2": "If data in only Statement II & III is sufficient",
    "choice_3": "If data in only Statement III is sufficient",
    "choice_4": "If data in only Statement I & II is sufficient",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Four subjects - physics, chemistry, mathematics and biology - were taught in four consecutive periods of one hour each starting from 8.00 a.m. At what time was the chemistry period scheduled?\nStatement I - mathematics period ended at 10.00 a.m., which was preceeded by biology. \nStatement II - physics was schedules in the last period\nStatement III - mathematics period was immediately followed by chemistry",
    "choice_1": "If data in only Statement II & III is sufficient",
    "choice_2": "If data in only Statement I & II is sufficient",
    "choice_3": "If data in only Statement III is sufficient",
    "choice_4": "If data I and either II & III is sufficient",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Question: What is the curved surface area of a cylinder ( A )?\u000bStatement i: The base area is 45.\u000bStatement ii: The volume is 167.",
    "choice_1": "Statement I alone is sufficient, but Statement II is not",
    "choice_2": "Statement II alone is sufficient, but Statement I is not",
    "choice_3": "If both Statement I and Statement II together are sufficient, but neither statement alone is sufficient",
    "choice_4": "If each statement alone is sufficient.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Among 20 retired persons, is the number of persons, who are having at least 20 years of service, less then 8?\nStatement I : Exactly 17 persons joined the service before 2000 and exactly 14 persons retired after 2020.\n\u000bStatement II : Exactly 14 persons joined the service after 2000 and exactly 6 persons retired before 2020.",
    "choice_1": "If the data in statement I alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement II alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_2": "If the data in statement II alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement I alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_3": "If the data either in statement I alone or statement II alone is  sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_4": "If the data in both statement I and II together are not sufficient to answer the question",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The ratio of monthly incomes of Kapil and Vinay is 4:5 respectively and the ratio of their monthly savings is 1:2, respectively. What is the monthly expenditure of Vinay?\nStatement I : The ratio of monthly income and monthly savings of Kapil is 4:1 respectively\nStatement II : The monthly expenditure of Kapil and Vinay is equal",
    "choice_1": "If the data in statement I alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement II alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_2": "If the data in statement II alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement I alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_3": "If the data in both statement I and II together are not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_4": "If the data either in statement I alone or statement II alone is  sufficient to answer the question",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Sum of ages of Julia, Rani, Amelia and Sonia is 91. What is the present age of Amelia?\nStatement I : Ratio of ages of Sonia and Julia 6 years ago was 9:7\nStatement II : Ratio of ages of Julia and Amelia after 10 years will be 6:7.",
    "choice_1": "If the data in statement I alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement II alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_2": "If the data in statement II alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement I alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_3": "If the data in both statement I and II together are not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_4": "If the data either in statement I alone or statement II alone is  sufficient to answer the question",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What will be the height of three friends Rahul, Robert and Priyanka altogether, if Priyanka's height is 39 cm?\nStatement I : The sum of the heights of Rahul and Priyanka is equal to 160 cm.\nStatement II : The height of Robert is equal to 3 times the height of Priyanka.",
    "choice_1": "If the data in statement I alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement II alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_2": "If the data in statement II alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement I alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_3": "If the data either in statement I alone or statement II alone is  sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_4": "If the data in both statement I and II together are neccessary to answer the question",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "How many children does M have? \nStatement 1: H is the only daughter of X who is wife of M. Statement 2: K and J are brothers of M.",
    "choice_1": "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
    "choice_2": "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
    "choice_3": "Either I or II is sufficient",
    "choice_4": "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What will be the total weight of 10 poles, each of the same weight? \nStatement 1: One-fourth of the weight of each pole is 5 kg. Statement 2: The total weight of three poles is 20 kilograms more than the total weight of two poles.",
    "choice_1": "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
    "choice_2": "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
    "choice_3": "Either I or II is sufficient",
    "choice_4": "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "If one-fourth of the weight of each pole is 5 kg, then the full weight of each pole is 4×5=204×5=20 kg.\nTherefore, the total weight of 10 poles is 10×20=20010×20=200 kg.\n\nStatement 2: The total weight of three poles is 20 kilograms more than the total weight of two poles.\n\nAccording to the statement, 3x=2x+20\n                x=20 kg.\nTherefore, the total weight of 10 poles is 10×20=200 kg.",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Rani, Supriya and Amita work on a project. If each of them is of a different efficiency. Who is the fastest worker among them?\nStatement I : Rani and Supriya take 5 days to complete the project while Supriya and Amita take 10 days to complete the same project\nStatement II : Rani and Amita 30/7 days to complete the project.",
    "choice_1": "If the data in statement I alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement II alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_2": "If the data in statement II alone is sufficient to answer the question, while the data in statement I alone is not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_3": "If the data in both statement I and II together are not sufficient to answer the question",
    "choice_4": "If the data either in statement I alone or statement II alone is  sufficient to answer the question",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Data sufficiency"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A company has three departments: Marketing (M), Sales (S), and Finance (F). The total number of employees is 100. The ratio of employees in M: S: F is 2:3:5.\n \nQuestions:\nHow many employees are in the Sales department?",
    "choice_1": 30,
    "choice_2": 34,
    "choice_3": 45,
    "choice_4": 65,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Total ratio parts: 2 + 3 + 5 = 10 parts\nEmployees in each part: 100 employees / 10 parts = 10 employees per part\nEmployees in Sales: 3 parts * 10 employees/part = 30 employees\nPercentage in Finance: (5/10) * 100% = 50%\nFemale employees in Marketing: (20/100) * (2 * 10) = 4 female employees",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A company has three departments: Marketing (M), Sales (S), and Finance (F). The total number of employees is 100. The ratio of employees in M: S: F is 2:3:5.\n \nQuestion:What percentage of the total employees are in the Finance department?",
    "choice_1": 35,
    "choice_2": 45,
    "choice_3": 50,
    "choice_4": 55,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Total ratio parts: 2 + 3 + 5 = 10 parts\nEmployees in each part: 100 employees / 10 parts = 10 employees per part\nEmployees in Sales: 3 parts * 10 employees/part = 30 employees\nPercentage in Finance: (5/10) * 100% = 50%\nFemale employees in Marketing: (20/100) * (2 * 10) = 4 female employees",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A company has three departments: Marketing (M), Sales (S), and Finance (F). The total number of employees is 100. The ratio of employees in M: S: F is 2:3:5.                                                                                                                                                         If 20% of the Marketing department employees are female, how many female employees are there in the Marketing department?",
    "choice_1": 10,
    "choice_2": 4,
    "choice_3": 7,
    "choice_4": 6,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Total ratio parts: 2 + 3 + 5 = 10 parts\nEmployees in each part: 100 employees / 10 parts = 10 employees per part\nEmployees in Sales: 3 parts * 10 employees/part = 30 employees\nPercentage in Finance: (5/10) * 100% = 50%\nFemale employees in Marketing: (20/100) * (2 * 10) = 4 female employees",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the following information carefully and answer the given questions:\nThere are two boxes A and B that contain the three different colours of balls i.e. red, yellow and green and the total number of balls in both boxes is 80. The ratio of the total number of balls in box A to box B is 5:3. 30% of the total number of balls is red. The ratio of the number of red balls in box A to box B is 7:5. The number of yellow balls in A is 2 more than the number of red balls in A. The ratio of the number of red balls in B to the number of green balls in B is 5:4.                                                                                        Question:   Number of red balls in A is what percent of the number of green balls in A?",
    "choice_1": 70,
    "choice_2": 75,
    "choice_3": 65,
    "choice_4": 60,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Total number of balls in A=5/8 * 80=50               \nTotal number of balls in B=3/8 * 80=30\nTotal number of red balls=30/100 * 80=24\nNumber of red balls in A=7/12 * 24=14\nNumber of red balls in B=5/12 * 24=10\nNumber of yellows in A=14 + 2=16\nNumber of green balls in A=50 – 14 – 16=20\nNumber of green balls in B=4/5 * 10=8\nNumber of yellow balls in B=30 – 10 – 8=12                                                                                                                         Required percentage = 14/20 * 100 = 70%",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the following information carefully and answer the given questions:\nThere are two boxes A and B that contain the three different colours of balls i.e. red, yellow and green and the total number of balls in both boxes is 80. The ratio of the total number of balls in box A to box B is 5:3. 30% of the total number of balls is red. The ratio of the number of red balls in box A to box B is 7:5. The number of yellow balls in A is 2 more than the number of red balls in A. The ratio of the number of red balls in B to the number of green balls in B is 5:4.                                                                                        Question:   What is the ratio of the number of red balls in B to the number of yellow balls in B?",
    "choice_1": "4:5",
    "choice_2": "5:6",
    "choice_3": "2:3",
    "choice_4": "1:2",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Total number of balls in A=5/8 * 80=50               \n  Total number of balls in B=3/8 * 80=30\nTotal number of red balls=30/100 * 80=24\nNumber of red balls in A=7/12 * 24=14\nNumber of red balls in B=5/12 * 24=10\nNumber of yellows in A=14 + 2=16\nNumber of green balls in A=50 – 14 – 16=20\nNumber of green balls in B=4/5 * 10=8\nNumber of yellow balls in B=30 – 10 – 8=12                                                                                                                         Required ratio = 10:12\n= 5:6",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the following information carefully and answer the given questions:\nThere are two boxes A and B that contain the three different colours of balls i.e. red, yellow and green and the total number of balls in both boxes is 80. The ratio of the total number of balls in box A to box B is 5:3. 30% of the total number of balls is red. The ratio of the number of red balls in box A to box B is 7:5. The number of yellow balls in A is 2 more than the number of red balls in A. The ratio of the number of red balls in B to the number of green balls in B is 5:4.                                                                                        Question:   Number of green balls in B is approximately what percent of the total number of green balls in A and B together?",
    "choice_1": 25.52,
    "choice_2": 24.53,
    "choice_3": 28.57,
    "choice_4": 27.52,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Total number of balls in A=5/8 * 80=50               \nTotal number of balls in B=3/8 * 80=30\nTotal number of red balls=30/100 * 80=24\nNumber of red balls in A=7/12 * 24=14\nNumber of red balls in B=5/12 * 24=10\nNumber of yellows in A=14 + 2=16\nNumber of green balls in A=50 – 14 – 16=20\nNumber of green balls in B=4/5 * 10=8\nNumber of yellow balls in B=30 – 10 – 8=12                                                                                                                         \nRequired percentage=8/(20 + 8) *100\n=28.57%",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the following information carefully and answer the given questions:\nIn a company, there are 2000 employees and the company has three different departments i.e. IT, HR and Sales. The total number of employees in the HR department is 30% of the total number of employees in the company. If the ratio of the number of male to female employees in the IT department is 5:3 and the number of female employees in the HR department is 90% of the number of female employees in the IT department. The ratio of the number of employees in IT department to Sales department is 4:3. The number of male employees in the sales department is 80 less than the number of male employees in IT department.\nQuestion:Read the following information carefully and answer the given questions:\nIn a company, there are 2000 employees and the company has three different departments i.e. IT, HR and Sales. The total number of employees in the HR department is 30% of the total number of employees in the company. If the ratio of the number of male to female employees in the IT department is 5:3 and the number of female employees in the HR department is 90% of the number of female employees in the IT department. The ratio of the number of employees in IT department to Sales department is 4:3. The number of male employees in the sales department is 80 less than the number of male employees in IT department.\nQuestion: The total number of female employees in all the departments together is what percent of the total number of male employees in all the departments together?",
    "choice_1": "2:1",
    "choice_2": "7:3",
    "choice_3": "9:5",
    "choice_4": "5:2",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Total number of employees in HR department=30/100 * 2000=600\nRemaining employees=2000 – 600=1400\nTotal number of employees in IT department=4/7 * 1400=800\nNumber of female employees in IT department=3/8 * 800=300\nNumber of male employees in IT department=5/8 * 800=500\nNumber of female employees in HR department=300 * 90/100=270\nNumber of male employees in HR department=600 – 270=330\nTotal number of employees in Sales department=3/7 * 1400=600\nNumber of male employees in sales department=500 – 80=420\nNumber of female employees in sales department=600 – 420=180\nRequired ratio=420:180\n=7:3",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the following information carefully and answer the given questions:\nIn a company, there are 2000 employees and the company has three different departments i.e. IT, HR and Sales. The total number of employees in the HR department is 30% of the total number of employees in the company. If the ratio of the number of male to female employees in the IT department is 5:3 and the number of female employees in the HR department is 90% of the number of female employees in the IT department. The ratio of the number of employees in IT department to Sales department is 4:3. The number of male employees in the sales department is 80 less than the number of male employees in IT department.\nQuestion:Read the following information carefully and answer the given questions:\nIn a company, there are 2000 employees and the company has three different departments i.e. IT, HR and Sales. The total number of employees in the HR department is 30% of the total number of employees in the company. If the ratio of the number of male to female employees in the IT department is 5:3 and the number of female employees in the HR department is 90% of the number of female employees in the IT department. The ratio of the number of employees in IT department to Sales department is 4:3. The number of male employees in the sales department is 80 less than the number of male employees in IT department.\nQuestion: What is the ratio of the number of male to female employees in sales department?",
    "choice_1": 40,
    "choice_2": 60,
    "choice_3": 75,
    "choice_4": 50,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Total number of employees in HR department=30/100 * 2000=600\nRemaining employees=2000 – 600=1400\nTotal number of employees in IT department=4/7 * 1400=800\nNumber of female employees in IT department=3/8 * 800=300\nNumber of male employees in IT department=5/8 * 800=500\nNumber of female employees in HR department=300 * 90/100=270\nNumber of male employees in HR department=600 – 270=330\nTotal number of employees in Sales department=3/7 * 1400=600\nNumber of male employees in sales department=500 – 80=420\nNumber of female employees in sales department=600 – 420=180\nRequired percentage=(300 + 270 + 180)/(500 + 330 + 420) * 100\n=60%",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the following information carefully and answer the given questions:\nIn a company, there are 2000 employees and the company has three different departments i.e. IT, HR and Sales. The total number of employees in the HR department is 30% of the total number of employees in the company. If the ratio of the number of male to female employees in the IT department is 5:3 and the number of female employees in the HR department is 90% of the number of female employees in the IT department. The ratio of the number of employees in IT department to Sales department is 4:3. The number of male employees in the sales department is 80 less than the number of male employees in IT department.\nQuestion:Read the following information carefully and answer the given questions:\nIn a company, there are 2000 employees and the company has three different departments i.e. IT, HR and Sales. The total number of employees in the HR department is 30% of the total number of employees in the company. If the ratio of the number of male to female employees in the IT department is 5:3 and the number of female employees in the HR department is 90% of the number of female employees in the IT department. The ratio of the number of employees in IT department to Sales department is 4:3. The number of male employees in the sales department is 80 less than the number of male employees in IT department.\nQuestion: What is the difference between the number of male to female employees in HR department?",
    "choice_1": 40,
    "choice_2": 50,
    "choice_3": 58,
    "choice_4": 60,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Total number of employees in HR department=30/100 * 2000=600\nRemaining employees=2000 – 600=1400\nTotal number of employees in IT department=4/7 * 1400=800\nNumber of female employees in IT department=3/8 * 800=300\nNumber of male employees in IT department=5/8 * 800=500\nNumber of female employees in HR department=300 * 90/100=270\nNumber of male employees in HR department=600 – 270=330\nTotal number of employees in Sales department=3/7 * 1400=600\nNumber of male employees in sales department=500 – 80=420\nNumber of female employees in sales department=600 – 420=180\nRequired Difference=330 – 270=60",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Study the following information carefully and answer the questions given below:\nA company manufactured some products in the years 2012 and 2013. In 2012, the company manufactured 60% of non-defected products and 30% with minor defects. 30000 units have been completely disposed of due to severe defects. In 2013, the number of non-defective products is 1/3 of the non defective products in 2012, whereas minor defective products is 20% of minor defects products in 2012 and completely disposed products was 10% of the non-defective products in 2012.\nQuestion: What is the ratio of completely disposed product manufactured in 2012 to 2013?",
    "choice_1": "11:6",
    "choice_2": "8:5",
    "choice_3": "3:5",
    "choice_4": "5:3",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "2012:\nCompletely disposed = 10% = 30000\nNon defective = 60% = 180000\nMinor defective = 30% = 90000\nTotal products manufactured = 300000\n2013:\nNon defective = 1/3 x 180000 = 60000\nMinor defective = 20/100 x 90000 = 18000\nCompletely disposed = 10/100 x 180000 = 18000\nTotal products manufactured = 96000\nCompletely disposed product of 2012 = 30000\nCompletely disposed product of 2013 = 18000\nRequired Ratio = 5:3",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Study the following information carefully and answer the questions given below:\nA company manufactured some products in the years 2012 and 2013. In 2012, the company manufactured 60% of non-defected products and 30% with minor defects. 30000 units have been completely disposed of due to severe defects. In 2013, the number of non-defective products is 1/3 of the non defective products in 2012, whereas minor defective products is 20% of minor defects products in 2012 and completely disposed products was 10% of the non-defective products in 2012.\nQuestion: What is the total number of products manufactured by the company on 2013?",
    "choice_1": 102000,
    "choice_2": 96000,
    "choice_3": 52000,
    "choice_4": 45000,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "2012:\nCompletely disposed = 10% = 30000\nNon defective = 60% = 180000\nMinor defective = 30% = 90000\nTotal products manufactured = 300000\n2013:\nNon defective = 1/3 x 180000 = 60000\nMinor defective = 20/100 x 90000 = 18000\nCompletely disposed = 10/100 x 180000 = 18000\nTotal products manufactured = 96000\n2013:\nNon defective = 1/3 x 180000 = 60000\nMinor defective = 20/100 x 90000 = 18000\nCompletely disposed = 10/100 x 180000 = 18000\nTotal products manufactured in 2013 = 60000 + 18000 + 18000 = 96000",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Study the following information carefully and answer the questions given below:\nA company manufactured some products in the years 2012 and 2013. In 2012, the company manufactured 60% of non-defected products and 30% with minor defects. 30000 units have been completely disposed of due to severe defects. In 2013, the number of non-defective products is 1/3 of the non defective products in 2012, whereas minor defective products is 20% of minor defects products in 2012 and completely disposed products was 10% of the non-defective products in 2012.\nQuestion:   By what percentage is the number of non-defective products manufactured in 2012 more than the number of non-defective products manufactured in 2013?",
    "choice_1": 440,
    "choice_2": 200,
    "choice_3": 370,
    "choice_4": 420,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "2012:\nCompletely disposed = 10% = 30000\nNon defective = 60% = 180000\nMinor defective = 30% = 90000\nTotal products manufactured = 300000\n2013:\nNon defective = 1/3 x 180000 = 60000\nMinor defective = 20/100 x 90000 = 18000\nCompletely disposed = 10/100 x 180000 = 18000\nTotal products manufactured = 96000\nNon-defective products in 2012: 180,000\nNon-defective products in 2013: 60,000\nDifference = Non-defective (2012) - Non-defective (2013) Difference = 180,000 - 60,000 = 120,000\nPercentage Increase = (Difference / Non-defective in 2013) × 100 Percentage Increase = (120,000 / 60,000) × 100 Percentage Increase = 2 × 100 = 200%\nAnswer: \u000bRequired difference = 2/8 * 800 = 200",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Study the following information carefully and answer the questions given below.\nThere are four different stores A, B, C and D which sold two different products Shampoo and Soap. Number of soaps sold in B and D is in the ratio of 4:1. Total number of shampoos sold in C is double the total number of shampoos sold in B, which is 200 less than the total number of shampoos sold in A. Number of soaps sold in A is same as the number of shampoos sold in C. Total number of shampoos sold in D is 33(1/3)% of the total number of shampoos sold in A. Average number of soaps sold in all the stores together is 625, which is 175 more than the total number of soaps sold in C. The difference between the number of soaps sold in B and D is 750.\nQuestion: If the ratio of the number of detergent soaps and kitchen soaps sold in A is 5:3 and only detergent soaps and kitchen soaps are sold in A, then what is the difference between the number of detergent and kitchen soaps sold in A?",
    "choice_1": 300,
    "choice_2": 400,
    "choice_3": 100,
    "choice_4": 200,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Explanation\nNumber of shampoos sold in B = x\nNumber of shampoos sold in C = 2 * x = 2x\nNumber of shampoos sold in A = x + 200\nNumber of shampoos sold in D = 100/300 * (x + 200)\nNumber of soaps sold in A = 2x\nNumber of soaps sold in B = 4/3 * 750 = 1000\nNumber of soaps sold in D = 1/3 * 750 = 250\nNumber of soaps sold in C = 625 – 175 = 450\nNumber of soaps sold in A = 625 * 4 – 1000 – 250 – 450 = 800\nNumber of shampoos sold in C = 800\nNumber of shampoos sold in B = 800/2 = 400\nNumber of shampoos sold in A = 400 + 200 = 600\nNumber of shampoos sold in D = 600/3 = 200",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Study the following information carefully and answer the questions given below.\nThere are four different stores A, B, C and D which sold two different products Shampoo and Soap. Number of soaps sold in B and D is in the ratio of 4:1. Total number of shampoos sold in C is double the total number of shampoos sold in B, which is 200 less than the total number of shampoos sold in A. Number of soaps sold in A is same as the number of shampoos sold in C. Total number of shampoos sold in D is 33(1/3)% of the total number of shampoos sold in A. Average number of soaps sold in all the stores together is 625, which is 175 more than the total number of soaps sold in C. The difference between the number of soaps sold in B and D is 750.\nQuestion: What is the ratio of the total number of shampoos to soaps sold in all the stores together?",
    "choice_1": "3:2",
    "choice_2": "6:5",
    "choice_3": "2:1",
    "choice_4": "4:5",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Explanation\nNumber of shampoos sold in B = x\nNumber of shampoos sold in C = 2 * x = 2x\nNumber of shampoos sold in A = x + 200\nNumber of shampoos sold in D = 100/300 * (x + 200)\nNumber of soaps sold in A = 2x\nNumber of soaps sold in B = 4/3 * 750 = 1000\nNumber of soaps sold in D = 1/3 * 750 = 250\nNumber of soaps sold in C = 625 – 175 = 450\nNumber of soaps sold in A = 625 * 4 – 1000 – 250 – 450 = 800\nNumber of shampoos sold in C = 800\nNumber of shampoos sold in B = 800/2 = 400\nNumber of shampoos sold in A = 400 + 200 = 600\nNumber of shampoos sold in D = 600/3 = 200\nRequired ratio = (600 + 400 + 800 + 200):(625 * 4) = 2000:2500 = 4:5",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Study the following information carefully and answer the questions given below.\nThere are four different stores A, B, C and D which sold two different products Shampoo and Soap. Number of soaps sold in B and D is in the ratio of 4:1. Total number of shampoos sold in C is double the total number of shampoos sold in B, which is 200 less than the total number of shampoos sold in A. Number of soaps sold in A is same as the number of shampoos sold in C. Total number of shampoos sold in D is 33(1/3)% of the total number of shampoos sold in A. Average number of soaps sold in all the stores together is 625, which is 175 more than the total number of soaps sold in C. The difference between the number of soaps sold in B and D is 750.\nQuestion:If the total number of soaps and shampoos in rose flavor sold in D is\n270 and only rose and lemon flavor soaps and shampoos are sold in\nD, then what is the ratio of the number of rose to lemon flavor soaps\nand shampoos together sold in D?",
    "choice_1": "2:1",
    "choice_2": "4:5",
    "choice_3": "3:2",
    "choice_4": "5:4",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Explanation\nNumber of shampoos sold in B = x\nNumber of shampoos sold in C = 2 * x = 2x\nNumber of shampoos sold in A = x + 200\nNumber of shampoos sold in D = 100/300 * (x + 200)\nNumber of soaps sold in A = 2x\nNumber of soaps sold in B = 4/3 * 750 = 1000\nNumber of soaps sold in D = 1/3 * 750 = 250\nNumber of soaps sold in C = 625 – 175 = 450\nNumber of soaps sold in A = 625 * 4 – 1000 – 250 – 450 = 800\nNumber of shampoos sold in C = 800\nNumber of shampoos sold in B = 800/2 = 400\nNumber of shampoos sold in A = 400 + 200 = 600\nNumber of shampoos sold in D = 600/3 = 200\nNumber of lemon flavor soap and shampoo in D = 250 + 200 – 270 = 180",
    "Topic": "Caselet Problems"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B, and C together can complete a task in 10 days. A is twice as efficient as B and three times as efficient as C. How long will B and C together take to finish the task?",
    "choice_1": 15,
    "choice_2": 22,
    "choice_3": 25,
    "choice_4": 30,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A, B, and C together can complete the task in 10 days.\u000bLet the total work = W\u000bThe combined efficiency of A, B, and C = 6x+3x+2x=11x\nW=Total Work=Efficiency×Time=11x×10=110x\nThe efficiency of B and C together = 3x+2x=5x\nTime taken B and C = Total Work Efficiency of B and C/{Total Work}=110X/5X=22 days",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A can complete a task in 16 days, and B can complete it in 20 days. They work together for 6 days, and then A leaves. If C, who is twice as efficient as B, joins B, how many more days are required to finish the task?",
    "choice_1": 2,
    "choice_2": 3,
    "choice_3": 4,
    "choice_4": 5,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Total Work= LCM of 16 and 20=80units\nThe efficiency of A = 80 /16=5 units/day\nEfficiency of A and B=5+4=9units/day\nWork done by A and B in 6 days=6×9=54units.\nRemaining Work=80−54=26 units\nC is twice as efficient as B, so the efficiency of C is:\n2×4=8 units/day.\nThe combined efficiency of B and C is:\n4+8=12 units/day\nTime required = Remaining Work/Efficiency=26/12=2.17 days",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "C is 50% more efficient than D, and they together can complete a task in 9 days. How long will D take to complete the same task working alone?",
    "choice_1": "18 days",
    "choice_2": "22.5 days",
    "choice_3": "27.5 days",
    "choice_4": "30 days",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Let the efficiency of D be x\u000bSince C is 50% more efficient than D, the efficiency of C will be 1.5x\nTotal Work=2.5x×9=22.5x\nTime taken by D alone=Efficiency of D/Total Work​=22.5X/X=22.5days.",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A is twice as efficient as B and completes a task in 12 days working alone. If A and B work together for 4 days and then B leaves, how many more days will A take to complete the task?",
    "choice_1": 2,
    "choice_2": 4,
    "choice_3": 6,
    "choice_4": 8,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Efficiency of A=Total work/total time=1/12\nEfficiency of B=1/2×Efficiency of A=1/2x1/12(tasks/day)=1/24\nCombined Efficiency=Efficiency of A+ Efficiency of B=1/12​+1/24​=3/24=1/8\nWork done by A and B together in 4 days=1/8x4=1/2\nRemaining Work=1−1/2=1/2\nTime taken by A to complete remaining work=Efficiency of A/Remaining Work​=12x1/2​​=6 days",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A and B can complete a task in 8 days, and B and C can complete the same task in 12 days. A, B, and C together can complete the task in 6 days. How many days will A and C together take to complete the task?",
    "choice_1": 8,
    "choice_2": 10,
    "choice_3": 11,
    "choice_4": 12,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Total Work= lcm 0f  8,12,6 =24 units.\nEfficiency of A + B=Total Work​/time=24/8​=3 units/day\nEfficiency of B + C=Total Work/total time=24/12​=2 units/day\nEfficiency of A + B + C=Total Work/total time=24/6​= 4units/day\nEfficiency of C=(Efficiency of A + B + C)−(Efficiency of A + B)=4−3=1unit/day\nEfficiency of A=(Efficiency of A + B + C)−(Efficiency of B + C)=4−2=2units/day.\nEfficiency of A + C=Efficiency of A+Efficiency of C=2+1=3units/day\nTime taken by A and C together=Total Work/efficiency of A and C​=24/3=8 days",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A can complete a task in 12 days, while B can complete the same task in 16 days. Both A and B start working together, but after 4 days, C, whose efficiency is equivalent to that of B, joins them. In how many days will the task be completed?",
    "choice_1": "6 days",
    "choice_2": "5.5 days",
    "choice_3": "7.5 days",
    "choice_4": "8 days",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Efficiency of A=Total Work/total time​=1/12​(tasks/day\nEfficiency of B=Total Work/time​=1/16​(tasks/day)\nEfficiency of C=1/16​(tasks/day)\nWork done by A and B in 4 days=Efficiency of( A + B)×114=(1/12+1/16)x4=7/48 x4=7/12\nRemaining Work=1−7/12​=​5/12\nEfficiency of A + B + C=1/12+1/16+1/16​=5/24\nTime taken to complete the remaining work=5/12 /5/24=2\nTotal Time=4+2=6 days",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B, and C can complete a task in 10 days when working together. The efficiency of A is equivalent to twice that of B, and the efficiency of C is equivalent to half that of A. How long will B and C together take to complete the task?",
    "choice_1": "12 days",
    "choice_2": "15 days",
    "choice_3": "18 days",
    "choice_4": "20 days",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Let the efficiency of B be x (work done per day by B).\nThe efficiency of A is twice that of B, so Efficiency of A=2x\nThe efficiency of C is half that of A, so Efficiency of C=1/2 (2x)=x\nEfficiency of A + B + C=2x+x+x=4x=1/10\nX=1/40\nEfficiency of B + C=x+x=2x=2×1/40​=1/20.\nTime taken by B and C=1/1/20​=20 days",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B, and C can complete a task in 6 days when working together. A works for 3 days, and B works for 4 days, after which C completes the remaining work in 2 days. If the efficiency of A is equivalent to that of B, and C’s efficiency is half that of A, how many days would C alone take to complete the task?",
    "choice_1": "12 days",
    "choice_2": "14 days",
    "choice_3": "18 days",
    "choice_4": "30 days",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Let the efficiency of A be x (work done per day by A).\nThe efficiency of B is also x since A and B are equally efficient.\nThe efficiency of C is half that of A, so  efficiency of c=x/2\nCombined Efficiency of A, B, and C=Total work/total time​=1/6​(tasks/day). Thus:\nEfficiency of A + B + C=x+x+x/2=2x+x/2=5x/2=1/6\nX=1/15\nEfficiency of C = x/2=1/30\nthus, time taken by C to complete the entire task in 30 days",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A and B can complete a task in 10 days. C, whose efficiency is equivalent to twice that of B, can complete the same task in 15 days. How many days will A, B, and C together take to complete the task?",
    "choice_1": "4 days",
    "choice_2": "5 days",
    "choice_3": "6 days",
    "choice_4": "7 days",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Efficiency of A + B=Total work/total time​=1/10​(tasks/day).\nEfficiency of C=Total work/total time​=1/15\nEfficiency of A + B + C=1/10+1/15=1/6\nTime taken by A, B, and C together=6 days",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B, and C can complete a task in 12 days, 15 days, and 18 days respectively. Their efficiency is in the ratio of their equivalence relation with another group D, E, and F, where D is twice as efficient as B, E is equivalent to A, and F is 50% more efficient than C. If D, E, and F work together, how many days will they take to complete the same task?",
    "choice_1": "3.3 days",
    "choice_2": "5.3 days",
    "choice_3": "6.2 days",
    "choice_4": "7.2 days",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Total Work=LCM(12,15,18)=180units\nEfficiency of A = Total work/total time=180/12=15 units/d\nEfficiency of B = Total Work/total time=180/15=12 units/day\nEfficiency of C = Total Work/Time =180/18=10 units/day\nEfficiency of D=2×Efficiency of B=2×12=24units/day\nEfficiency of E=Efficiency of A=151units/day\nEfficiency of F=1.5×Efficiency of C=1.5×10=15units/day\nEfficiency of D + E + F=24+15+15=54units/day\nThe time required to complete the task is:\nTime=Total Work/Efficiency of D + E + F=180/54=10/3 days=3.3 days",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "X, Y, and Z together can finish a piece of work in [P/13] days, while X and Y together\ncan do it in [P/10] days. Y alone can complete the same work in [P/4] days. Z takes\n20 days more than X to complete the work alone. What is the value of P?",
    "choice_1": 240,
    "choice_2": 120,
    "choice_3": 180,
    "choice_4": 220,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "One day work of X, Y & Z together = 13/P\nOne day work of X & Y together = 10/ P\nOne day work of Z = 13 / P - 10/ P = 3 /P\nTime taken by Z alone to complete the work = P/3 days\nOne day work of X & Y together = 10/P\nOne day work Y = 4 / P\nOne day work X = 10 /P - 4 /P = 6 /P\nTime taken by X alone to complete the work = P / 6 days\nATQ, P/ 3 - P /6 = 20\nor, P/ 6 = 20\nSo, P = 120",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A,B and C can do a piece of work in 30 days, 40 days and 50 days,\nrespectively. Beginning with A, if A, B and C do the work alternatively then\nin how many days will the work be finished?",
    "choice_1": "38 1/12",
    "choice_2": "36 1/12",
    "choice_3": 36,
    "choice_4": "39 1/12",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "A can do a piece of work = 30 days\nB can do a piece of work = 40 days\nC can do a piece of work = 50 days\nFormula used:\nTotal work = efficiency x time\n\nEfficiency Of a person and timing\n20 - A - 30\n15 - B - 40\n12 - C - 50\nTotal work = 600\nAccording to the question:\n= (20 + 15 + 12) = 47 units = 3 days\n= 47 x 12 = 564 units = 3 x 12 = 36 days\n= (564 + 20 + 15) = 599 units = 38 days\nTotal work = 600 units = 38 + (1/12) = 38 days.The correct answer is 38 1/12 Days",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "To do a certain work, A and B work on alternate days, with B beginning the\nwork on the first day. A alone can complete the same work in 24 days. If\nthe work gets completed in 11 1/3 days, then B alone can complete 7/9th part\nof the original work in:",
    "choice_1": "4 days",
    "choice_2": "6 days",
    "choice_3": "5 1/2 days",
    "choice_4": "4 1/2 days",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Given:\nTime taken by A to finish a task alone = 24 days\nCalculation:\nLet the total work be = 1\nA alone can finish the task in 24 days\n= A's one-day work = 1/24\nA and B complete the whole task in = 11 1/3 days\nA and B work on alternate days, with B beginning so we can say B will work\nonly 6 days \n= A will work only 11 1/3 - 6 = 5 1/3 days\nIf A's one day's work = 1/24 of the work A completes in 1 day\n= A's 5 1/3 days work = 1/24 x 5 1/3 = 1/24 x 16/3 = 2/9\nRemaining work = 1 - 2/9 = 7/9\n:. B does the 7/9th part of the work in 6 days.\nNote-\nB, A, B, A, B, A, B, A, B, A, B, A/3\nB completes 6-day work\nThat's why we have taken the 6-day work by B alone.",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two male workers A and B can complete a piece of work in 20 and 35 hours respectively. A female worker, C can complete\nthe whole work alone in H hours with three - fourth of her original efficiency. If all the three working together with their\nusual efficiency can complete the whole work in 6 hours, then find the value of H.",
    "choice_1": "460/37 hours",
    "choice_2": "560/27 hours",
    "choice_3": "460/17 hours",
    "choice_4": "560/37 hours",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Total units of work = 420\n(A + B + C)'One hour's work = 70 units\nA's one hour's work = 21 units\n B = 12 units\nC's one hour's work = 70 - 33 = 37 units\nC's efficiency to do the work alone = 3 x 37/4\n Time required to complete the work\n= 420 x 4/37 x 3 = 560/37 hours\nHence, option D is correct.",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A can do 3/5th of work in 15 days. Efficiency of B is 25% more\nthan that of A. Both A and B started working together and\nleft the work after five days. C completed the remaining work\nin 11 days. Efficiency of C is what percent more/less than that\nof A ?",
    "choice_1": "20% less",
    "choice_2": "25% more",
    "choice_3": "20% more",
    "choice_4": "25% less",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A does 3/5th of work in 15 days.\n\nTime Taken by A to complete the work\n=5/3 x 15 = 25 days\nThe efficiency of B is 25% more than that of A.\nIf Work done by A in one day = 4, then work done by B in one day = 5\nRatio of time taken by A and B = 5: 4\nTime taken by B to complete the work\n= 4/5 * 25 = 20 days\nA and B worked for five days\nTotal work completed by A and B in 5 days\n= 5 (1/25 + 1/20)\n= 1/5+1/4 = 9/20\nwork left = 11/20, which is done by C in 11 days.\nTime taken by C to complete the whole work 20/11 * 11\nC = 20 days\nThe ratio of Efficiency of C is 25% more than that of A",
    "Topic": "TIME AND WORK (WORK WITH DIFFERENT EFFICIENCIES)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two pipes can fill a tank in 20 and 24 minutes respectively and a waste pipe can empty 3 gallons per minute. All the three pipes working together can fill the tank in 15 minutes. The capacity of the tank is:",
    "choice_1": "60 gallons",
    "choice_2": "100 gallons",
    "choice_3": "120 gallons",
    "choice_4": "180 gallons",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Solution:\nWork done by the waste pipe in 1 minute = (1/15) - [(1/20)+(1/24)] \n                                                                    = -1/40. \nVolume of 1/40 part = 3 gallons.\n Volume of whole = (3 x 40) gallons \n                              = 120 gallons.",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A tank is filled in 5 hours by three pipes A, B and C. The pipe C is twice as fast as B and B is twice as fast as A. How much time will pipe A alone take to fill the tank?",
    "choice_1": "20 hours",
    "choice_2": "25 hours",
    "choice_3": "35 hours",
    "choice_4": "cannot be determined",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Solution:\nLet A takes x hours. \nThen B = x/2, C = x/4. \n1/x + 1/(x/2) + 1/(x/4) = 1/5 \n=> 7/x = 1/5 \n=> x = 35 hrs.",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two pipes A and B together can fill a cistern in 4 hours. Had they been opened separately, then B would have taken 6 hours more than A to fill the cistern. How much time will be taken by A to fill the cistern separately?",
    "choice_1": "1 hour",
    "choice_2": "2 hour",
    "choice_3": "6 hours",
    "choice_4": "8 hours",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Solution:\nLet A fill in x hrs, \nthen B in x+6 hrs. \n1/x + 1/(x+6) = ¼\n => (x + x + 6)/(x(x + 6)) = 1/4 \n=> x^2 - 2x - 24 = 0 \n=> (x+4) (x-6) = 0\n=> x = 6",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two pipes A and B can fill a tank in 20 and 30 minutes respectively. If both the pipes are used together, then how long will it take to fill the tank?",
    "choice_1": "12 min",
    "choice_2": "15 min",
    "choice_3": "25 min",
    "choice_4": "50 min",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Solution:\n\nxy/x+y  20*30/20+30  600/50  12\n\nor\n\nPart filled by A in 1 min = 1/20\nPart filled by B in 1 min = 1/30\nPart filled by (A + B) in 1 min = (1/20 + 1/30) = 1/12\nBoth pipes can fill the tank in 12 minutes",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two pipes A and B can fill a tank in 15 minutes and 20 minutes respectively. Both the pipes are opened together but after 4 minutes, pipe A is turned off. What is the total time required to fill the tank?",
    "choice_1": "10 min. 20 sec.",
    "choice_2": "11 min, 45 sec.",
    "choice_3": "12 min. 30 sec.",
    "choice_4": "14 min. 40 sec",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Solution:\nPart filled in 4 minutes = 4(1/15 + 1/20) = 7/15\nRemaining part = 1 - 7/15 = 8/15\nPart filled by B in 1 minute = 1/20\nTime to fill 8/15 = (8/15) × 20 = 10 min 40 sec\nTotal time = 4 min + 10 min 40 sec = 14 min 40 sec",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "One pipe can fill a tank three times as fast as another pipe. If together the two pipes can fill the tank in 36 minutes, then the slower pipe alone will be able to fill the tank in",
    "choice_1": "81 min",
    "choice_2": "108 min",
    "choice_3": "144 min",
    "choice_4": "192 min",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Ratio of efficiency of two pipes = 3 : 1\n\nTotal work = (3+1)*36  4*36  144 \n\nTime take by slower pipe = 144/1  144\n\n\nOr \n\n\nLet the slower pipe alone fill the tank in x minutes.\nThen, faster pipe will fill it in x/3 minutes.\n(1/x + 1/(x/3)) = 1/36\n=> (4/x) = 1/36 => x = 144 minutes",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A large tanker can be filled by two pipes A and B in 60 minutes and 40 minutes respectively. How many minutes will it take to fill the tanker from empty state if B is used for half the time and A and B fill it together for the other half?",
    "choice_1": "15 min",
    "choice_2": "20 min",
    "choice_3": "27.5 min",
    "choice_4": "30 min",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Solution:\nPart filled by (A + B) in 1 minute = 1/60 + 1/40 = 1/24\nLet total time be x mins\nThen, \n(x/2) * (1/24) + (x/2) * (1/40) = 1 \nx/48 + x/80 = 1\n3x+5x/240 = 1\n8x =240\nX=30",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A tap can fill a tank in 6 hours. After half the tank is filled, three more similar taps are opened. What is the total time taken to fill the tank completely?",
    "choice_1": "3 hrs 15 min",
    "choice_2": "3 hrs 45 min",
    "choice_3": "4 hrs",
    "choice_4": "4 hrs 15 min",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Solution:\nTime to fill half tank with one tap = 3 hrs\nRemaining = 1/2 tank\nFour taps together fill 4 × (1/6) = 2/3 tank/hour\nTime = (1/2) ÷ (2/3) = 3/4 hrs = 45 mins\nTotal time = 3 hrs + 45 mins = 3 hrs 45 mins",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Three pipes A, B and C can fill a tank in 6 hours. After working at it together for 2 hours, C is closed and A and B can fill the remaining part in 7 hours. The number of hours taken by C alone to fill the tank is:",
    "choice_1": 10,
    "choice_2": 12,
    "choice_3": 14,
    "choice_4": 16,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Solution:\nPart filled in 2 hrs = 2/6 = 1/3\nRemaining = 1-1/3 = 2/3\nA + B fill 2/3 in 7 hrs \n=> A + B in 1 hr = 2/21\n\nA + B + C = 1/6\nC = (A+B+C) –(A+B)\nC = 1/6 - 2/21 = 1/14 \n=> C alone fills in 14 hrs",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A tank is filled by three pipes with uniform flow. The first two pipes operating simultaneously fill the tank in the same time during which the tank is filled by the third pipe alone. The second pipe fills the tank 5 hours faster than the first pipe and 4 hours slower than the third pipe. Time required by the first pipe to fill the tank is",
    "choice_1": "6 hr",
    "choice_2": "15 hr",
    "choice_3": "10 hr",
    "choice_4": "30 hr",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Solution:\nLet first pipe fill in x hours. \nThen second in (x - 5), third in (x - 9)\n\n1/x + 1/(x - 5) = 1/(x - 9)\n\n(x-5) + x /x(x-5) = 1/(x-9)\n(2x - 5) (x -9)=x(x -5)\n2x^2 - 5x - 18x +45=x^2-5x\nX^2 - 18x +45=0\n(x - 15) (x -3)=0\nx = 15 [neglecting x = 3]\nSo time required by 1st pipe = 15 hours",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "There are two outlet pipes connected to a tank which can empty the tank in 2 hours and 3 hours respectively. There is an inlet pipe connected to the tank, which can fill it in 6 hours. Both the outlet pipes are opened when the tank is full. But by mistake, someone opened the inlet pipe when the tank was exactly half empty. Calculate the delay in time taken to empty the tank.",
    "choice_1": "",
    "choice_2": "",
    "choice_3": "",
    "choice_4": "",
    "answer_key": "",
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "There are four pipes joined in a tank where pipe C only outlet pipe. Pipe C\nand Pipe A together filled the tank in 24 hours. Pipe A and B together fill\nthe tank in 7.2 hours. Pipe B is double efficient than pipe D. Pipe A and D\ntogether filled the tank in [x +3] hours. Pipe A fill the tank alone in 12\nhours. Find how part pipe B and D fill the tank in x hours?",
    "choice_1": 11,
    "choice_2": 6,
    "choice_3": 7,
    "choice_4": 8,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Let the capacity of the tank = 1 unit\nPipe A fills the tank alone in 12 hours\nEfficiency of A = 1/12\nPipe C and A together fill the tank in 24 hours\nThat means:\nA's rate + C's rate = 1/24\nSubstitute A's rate:\n1/12 + C = 1/ 24\nC= 1/24-1/12 = [1 - 2] / 24 = -1/ 24\nPipe C is an outlet pipe (as stated), and it empties at the rate of 1/24\nA and B together fill the tank in 7.2 hours\n1/A + 1/B = 1/7.2\nOr, 1/12 + 1/B = 1/7.2\nOr, 1/B = 10/72 - 1/12 = [10- 6] / 72 = 1/18\nPipe B fills at 1/18 per hour.\nB is double efficient than D\nPipe D fills at 1/36 per hour.\nA and D together fill in x + 3 hours\n1/A + 1/D = 1/(x+3)\n= 1/12 + 1/36 = 1/(x+3)\nOr, 4/36 = 1 /(x+3)\nOr, x + 3 = 9 , x= 6\nWe know:\nB = 1/ 18 , D = 1/36\nTogether they fill at in rate of [ 1/18 + 1/ 36 = 3 /36 = 1/12]\nSo, in 6 hours, B and D fill:\n6 x[1/12] = 6/12=1/2\nPipe B and D together fill 1/2 of the tank in 6 hours.\nThe correct answer is option (2).",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two inlet pipes A and B working together for 4 hours fill 72 units of water\nin a tank having capacity 160 units. If A alone can fill the tank in 20 hours,\nthe time taken by B alone to fill the tank is",
    "choice_1": "25 hours",
    "choice_2": "15 hours",
    "choice_3": "21 hours",
    "choice_4": "16 hours",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Tank capacity = 160 units\nPipes A and B together fill 72 units in 4 hours\nPipe A alone fills the tank in 20 hours\nFormula used:\nRate of filling = Work done / Time\nRate of A + Rate of B = Combined rate\nTime taken = Tank capacity / Rate\nCalculation:\nRate of A = Tank capacity / Time taken by A\nRate of A = 160 / 20 = 8 units/hour\nRate of A + Rate of B = Combined rate\nCombined rate = Total water filled / Time\nCombined rate = 72 / 4 = 18 units/hour\nRate of B = Combined rate - Rate of A\nRate of B = 18 - 8 = 10 units/hour\nTime taken by B = Tank capacity / Rate of B\nTime taken by B = 160 / 10 = 16 hours",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A cistern has an inlet pipe and an outlet pipe. Inlet pipe can fill three-fourth\nof the cistern in 24 minutes while outlet pipe can empty the one-third filled\ncistern in 16 minutes. If both the pipes are opened together, then the\ncistern will be completely filled in-",
    "choice_1": 96,
    "choice_2": 92,
    "choice_3": 84,
    "choice_4": 75,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Inlet pipe can fill three-fourths of the cistern in 24 minutes.\nOutlet pipe can empty one-third of the cistern in 16 minutes.\nCalculations:\nRate of the inlet pipe = (3/4) cistern / 24 minutes = 3 / (4 x 24) = 1 / 32\ncistern per minute.\nRate of the outlet pipe = (1/3) cistern / 16 minutes = 1 / (3 x 16) = 1/48\ncistern per minute.\nWhen both pipes are opened together, the combined rate is:\nCombined rate = Rate of inlet pipe - Rate of outlet pipe = 1/32 - 1/48\nTo subtract, find the LCM of 32 and 48, which is 96:\n1/32 = 3/96, and 1/48 = 2/96, so combined rate = (3/96) - (2/96) = 1/96 cistern per minute.\nThus, the cistern will be filled in 96 minutes",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A cistern is connected to two inlet pipes, A and B, and one outlet pipe, C.\nPipe A can fill the cistern in 16 hours, and Pipe B can fill it in 12 hours. Pipe\nC can drain the entire cistern in 20 hours. If all three pipes are opened at\nthe same time, how long will it take to completely fill the cistern?",
    "choice_1": "9 3/5 hours",
    "choice_2": "10 10/23 hours",
    "choice_3": "8 12/25 hours",
    "choice_4": "9 9/11 hours",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Given:\n\nPipe A can fill the cistern in 16 hours\n\nPipe B can fill the cistern in 12 hours\n\nPipe C can drain the cistern in 20 hours\n\nCalculation :-\nLet total work be 240 units (LCM of 16, 12, and 20).\nCapacity of Pipe A = 240 / 16 = 15 units/hour\nCapacity of Pipe B = 240 / 12 = 20 units/hour\nCapacity of Pipe C = 240 / 20 = 12 units/hour (since it empties, it's -12)\nNet capacity when all three pipes are open = 15 + 20 - 12 = 23 units/hour\n10 hours\n23\nTime to fill the tank = 240 / 23 ~ 10\n10\n23\nFinal Answer: 10 hours",
    "Topic": "PIPES AND CISTERNS"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If a road of 210 km can be constructed by 540 workmen in 28 days, how many workmen are required to build a road of 150 km in 18 days?",
    "choice_1": 450,
    "choice_2": 600,
    "choice_3": 720,
    "choice_4": 300,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Soln: M1D1H1/W1 = M2D2H2/W2 \n        540 x 28 x h/210 =  M2 x 18 x h/150 \n                  M2 = 600",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If 7 spiders make 7 webs in 7 days, then 1 spider will make 1 web in how many days?",
    "choice_1": 1,
    "choice_2": 7,
    "choice_3": 14,
    "choice_4": 2,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Soln: M1D1H1/W1 = M2D2H2/W2 \n\t7 x 7 /7 =  1 x 1 x D2/1\n\t \t D2 = 7",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A contractor undertakes to do a job in 18 days. He employees certain number of men, but 12 of them being absent from the very first day, the rest can complete the work in 30 days. The number of men originally employed?",
    "choice_1": 20,
    "choice_2": 25,
    "choice_3": 30,
    "choice_4": 40,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Soln: M1D1H1/W1 = M2D2H2/W2 \n        (X-12) x 30 /1 =  X x 18/1\n                  X = 30",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A contractor employed 60 men to do a piece of work in 76 days. After 50 days, he employed 10 more men and the work was finished 2 day earlier. How many days he would have been behind, if he had not employed additional men?",
    "choice_1": "1 day",
    "choice_2": "2 days",
    "choice_3": "3 days",
    "choice_4": "4 days",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Soln: \tM1D1H1/W1 = M2D2H2/W2 \n\tTotal work = 60*50 + 70*24 \u000b\tNow days = D \u000b\tD*60 = 60*50 + 70*24 , We get D = 78, so 2 more days",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In a dairy farm, 20 horses eat 40 bags of husk in 40 days. In howmany days willl 10 horses eat 30 bags of husks?",
    "choice_1": 30,
    "choice_2": 60,
    "choice_3": 80,
    "choice_4": 100,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Soln: M1D1H1/W1 = M2D2H2/W2 \n\t20 x 40 / 40 =  10  x D2/30\n\t \t D2 = 60",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "2 men and 4 women can complete a job in 5 days. Also same job can be completed by 3 men and 8 women in 3 days. In how many days, twice the job can be completed by 3 men and 3 women?",
    "choice_1": 4,
    "choice_2": 8,
    "choice_3": 10,
    "choice_4": 8.5,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Soln: \t2M + 4W = 5D ⇨ 10M + 20W = 1D -------(1) \n\t3M + 8W = 3D ⇨ 9M + 24W = 1D ----------(2)\n\there, works are same \n\t∴ 10M + 20W = 9M + 24W\n\t1M= 4W\n\t12W can do work in 5D ------ from eq. (1), \n\t1W = 60D\n\t3 men and 3 women can do the job\n\t3M + 3W = 12W+3W = 15W, THEY CAN DO IN 60D/15 W = 4 D\n∴ 3 men and 3 women can do twice the job in 4D x 2 = 8 days",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A and B take 12 days to complete a given task. B and C together complete the same task in 10 days, while C and A take 20 days to finish the same task. If all of them undertake the task at Rs 700, find the share of C.",
    "choice_1": 250,
    "choice_2": 200,
    "choice_3": 350,
    "choice_4": 300,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Combined work of A and B in one day = 1/12\n\nCombined work of B and C in one day = 1/10\n\nCombined work of A and C in one day = 1/20\n\nAdding these,\n\n⇒ 1/A + 1/B + 1/B + 1/C + 1/A + 1/C = 1/12 + 1/10 + 1/20\n\n⇒ (5 + 6 + 3)/60 = 7/30\n\n⇒ 2(1/A + 1/B + 1/C) = 7/30\n\n⇒ (1/A + 1/B + 1/C) = 7/60\n\nIf we subtract A and B combined work we get,\n\n1/C = 7/60 - 1/12 = 2/60\n\nRatio of work done by C = 2/60 ÷ 7/60 = 2/7\n\nShare of C = 700 × 2/7 = Rs 200",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "4 men and 5 women can complete a work in 15 days, whereas 9 men and\n6 women can complete it in 10 days. To complete the same work in 7 days,\nhow many women should assist 4 men?",
    "choice_1": 14,
    "choice_2": 11,
    "choice_3": 15,
    "choice_4": 13,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "According to the question\nTotal work = Total work\n= (4m + 5w) × 15=(9m+6w)×10\n= (60m + 75w) = (90m + 60w)\n=(90m-60m) =(75w -60w)\n30m = 15w\n2m = 1w\nm: w = 1:2\nTotal work = (4m + 5w) x 15\n= (4 x 1 + 5 x 2) x 15\n= (4 + 10) × 15\n=(14×15)\n= 210\nLet x women assist 4 men to complete the work in 7 days, then\n= (4 x 1 + x x 2) x 7 = 210\n= (4 + 2x) = 210\n= (4 + 2x) = 30\n= 2x = (30-4)\n= 2x = 26\n= x = 13\n13 women assist 4 men Shortcut Trick\nAccording to the question\n(4m + 5w) x 15=(9m+6w)× 10\n60m + 75w =90m + 60w\n30m = 15w\nm : w = 1:2\nTotal work = (4m + 5w) x 15\n= (4 + 10) × 15\n= 210\nAccording to the question\n(4 + 2 x x) x 7 = 210\n28 + 14x = 210\n14x = 182\nx=13",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B and C are three book binders. A takes 10 minutes, B takes 12 minutes and C takes 15 minutes to bind a book. If they work each day for 12 hours, then on an average, a person can bind how many books per day?",
    "choice_1": "60 books",
    "choice_2": "90 books",
    "choice_3": "40 books",
    "choice_4": "100 books",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "A takes 10 min to bind 1 book \n\n∴ In 60 min A binds = 60/10 = 6 books\n\nB takes 12 min to bind 1 book\n\n∴ In 60 min B binds = 60/12 = 5 books\n\nC takes 15 min to bind 1 book \n\n∴ In 60 min C bind = 60/15 = 4 book\n\nNumber of books bound by them in 1 hour = 6 + 5 + 4 = 15\n\nTotal number of books bound by them in 12 hours = 15 × 12 = 180\n\n∴ Required average = 180/3 = 60 books",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man takes 12 days to complete a work by working for 8 hours a day while a woman completes the same work in 8 days by working 10 hours a day. In how many days will both of them complete the work by working together for 8 hours a day?",
    "choice_1": "52/11",
    "choice_2": "54/11",
    "choice_3": "58/11",
    "choice_4": "60/11",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "A man can complete a work in 12 days by working 8 hours a day\n\nA woman can complete the same work in 8 days by working 10 hours a day\n\nNumbers of hours taken by the man to complete the work = 12 × 8 = 96\n\nWork done in an hour by the man = 1/96\n\nNumber of hours taken by woman to complete the work = 8 × 10 = 80\n\nWork done in an hour by the woman = 1/80\n\nWork done by both of them in one hour = (1/96) + (1/80) = 11/480\n\nwork done by them in 8 hours = 8 × (11/480) = 11/60\n\nSo, Work will be completed in 60/11 days",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The amount of job that Amal, Sunil and Kamal can individually do in a day, are in harmonic progression. Kamal takes twice as much time as Amal to do the same amount of job. If Amal and Sunil work for ...",
    "choice_1": 27,
    "choice_2": 28,
    "choice_3": 29,
    "choice_4": 30,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Let us assume the efficiencies of Amal, Sunil, and\nKamal are a, s, and k, respectively.\n\nGiven that they are in H.P.\nAlso, given that Kamal takes twice as much time as\nAmal to do the same amount of job\n=> a = 2k\nGiven that when Amal and Sunil work for 4 days and\n9 days, respectively, Kamal needs to work for 16\ndays to finish the remaining job.\n\n=> If W is the total work => 4a + 9s + 16k = W.\nfrom (1)2/s =1/a+2/a =>a=3/2s and k = 3/4s\n=> 4(3s/2)+9s+16(3s/4) = W\n=> 6s+9s+12s = W\n=>27s = W\n=>s=W/27\nSunil will take 27 days to finish the work when working alone",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Three men and eight machines can finish a job in half the time taken by three machines and eight men to finish the same job. If two machines can finish the job in 13 days, then how many men can finish the job in 13 days?",
    "choice_1": 12,
    "choice_2": 13,
    "choice_3": 14,
    "choice_4": 15,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Consider the work done by a man in a day = a, and that by a machine = b \nSince three men and eight machines can finish a job in half the time taken by three machines and eight men to finish the same job, the efficiency will be doubled.\n\n=>3a+8b = 2(3b+8a)\n=>13a=2b\nHence work done by 13 men in a day=work done by 2 machines in a day.\n=> If two machines can finish the job in 13 days, then the same work will be done by 13 men in 13 days.\nHence the required number of men = 13",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Humans and robots can both perform a job but\nat different efficiencies. Fifteen humans and\nfive robots working together take thirty days to\nfinish the job, whereas five humans and fifteen\nrobots working together take sixty days to\nfinish it. How many days will fifteen humans\nworking together (without any robot) take to\nfinish it?",
    "choice_1": 45,
    "choice_2": 36,
    "choice_3": 32,
    "choice_4": 40,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Let the efficiency of humans be 'h' and the efficiency of robots be 'r'.\n In the first case, \n Total work = (15h + 5r) * 30......(i) \nIn the second case,\n Total work = (5h + 15r) * 60......(ii) \nOn equation (i) and (ii), we get\n(15h+15r)*30 = (5h+15r)*60\nor,15h+15r = 10h+30r\nor,5h=25r\nor,h=5r\nTotal work =(15h+5r)*30 = (15h+h)*30 = 480h\nTime taken by 15 humans = 480h/15h days = 32 days.",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If 2 men or 3 women or 4 boys can do a piece of work in 52 days, then\nthe same piece of work will be done by 1 man, 1 woman and 1 boy in:",
    "choice_1": "48 days",
    "choice_2": "36 days",
    "choice_3": "45 days",
    "choice_4": "32 days",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Work done by 2 men = 3 women = 4 boys\n1 man = 2 boys\n1 woman = 4/3 boys\nThus,\nBoys × days = 4 × 52 boys × days\nAgain,\n1 man + 1 women + 1 boys,\n=2+4/3+1\n=13/3 boys\nUsing work equivalent method,\nboys × day = BOYS × DAYS\n4×52=13/3 * x(let)\n\nx = 48 days",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "38. Two typist of varying skills can do a job in 6 minutes if they\nwork together. If the first typist typed alone for 4 minutes and\nthen the second typist typed alone for 6 minutes, they would be\nleft with 1/5 of the whole work. How many minutes would it take \nthe slower typist to complete the typing job working alone ?",
    "choice_1": "10 minutes",
    "choice_2": "15 minutes",
    "choice_3": "12 minutes",
    "choice_4": "20 minutes",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Working efficiency of both typist together,\n= 100/6 = 16.66% per minute\n\nNow, let work efficiency of first typist be x and then second typist will be (16.66 - x)\nFirst typist typed alone for 4 minutes and second typed alone for 6 minutes and they left with 1/5 (i.e 20%) of job, means they have completed 80% job\nNow,\nFirst Typist typed in 4 minute + Second typed in 6 minutes = 80%\n4 × x + 6 × (16.66 - x) = 80%\n4x + 100% - 6x = 80%\nx = 10%\nFirst Typist typed 10% per minutes. Then second typed (16.66 - 10) = 6.66% per minute\nThen, Second typist complete the whole job in 100/6.66 = 15.01 = 15 minutes.",
    "Topic": "WORK EQUIVALENCE(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Ram can do the work in 20 days. Ram and Shyam together can do the same work in 15 days. If they are paid Rs.400 for that work, what is the share of Shyam (in Rs.).",
    "choice_1": 100,
    "choice_2": 200,
    "choice_3": 150,
    "choice_4": 50,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Ram = 20 days\n\nRam + shyam = 15 days\n\nEfficiency (LCM of ram & shyam) = 60\n\nRam efficiency = 60 /20  3 unit/day\n\nRam + Shyam efficiency = 60 / 15  4 unit/day\n\nShyam alone = 4- 3  1 unit/day\n\nShyam share = 1/4 * 400  Rs. 100",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Rama can do a piece of work in 10 days and Rami alone can do it in 5 days. Rama and Rami undertook to do it for Rs.400. With the help of their neighbour Snooty, they finished it in 2 days. The share of Snooty out of the remuneration is",
    "choice_1": "Rs.120",
    "choice_2": "Rs.200",
    "choice_3": "Rs.160",
    "choice_4": "Rs.180",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "(Rama + Rami + Snooty)'s one day's work = 1/10 + 1/5 + 1/X.\n(Rama + Rami + Snooty)'s two day's work = 2 x (1/10 + 1/5 + 1/X).\n{because they need 2 days to do the job)\n=> 2 [ 1/10 + 1/5 + 1/X ] = 1 = On solving we get, X = 5 days.\nThis means that Snooty can do the whole work alone in 5 days.\n=> In one day, he does 1/5 of the work.\n=>In two days, he does (2 x 1/5) of the work.\n=> Snooty's share = 1/5 x 2 x 400 = Rs.160.",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A alone can do a piece of work in 6 days and B alone in 8 days. A and B undertook to do it for Rs. 3200. With the help of C, they completed the work in 3 days. How much is to be paid to C?",
    "choice_1": "Rs.300",
    "choice_2": "Rs.400",
    "choice_3": "Rs.500",
    "choice_4": "Rs.600",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Let the total work done be 24x (as 24 is the LCM of 6 & 8)\n\nPart of work done by A in a day = 24x/6 = 4x\n\nPart of work done by B in a day = 24x/8 = 3x\n\nPart of work done by A, B and C in a day = 24x/3 = 8x\n\nWork done by C in a day = 8x - 4x - 3x = x\n\nWork done by C in 3 days = 3x\n\nFor 24x work amount to be paid = Rs. 3200\n\nAmount paid to C = (3200/24x) x 3x\n\n= Amount paid to C = 400\n\n:. C is paid Rs. 400",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The labourers A, B, C were given a contract of Rs. 750 for doing a certain piece of work. All the three together can finish the work in 8 days. A and C together can do it in 12 days while A and B together can do it in 13(1/3)days. The money will be divided in the ratio.",
    "choice_1": "4:5:6",
    "choice_2": "4:7:5",
    "choice_3": "5:7:4",
    "choice_4": "5:6:8",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "A+B+C  = 8 --------------10\nA+C    = 12 ------------- 120 [LCM of 8,12,40/3]\nA+B    =  40/3 ------------9     \n13 1/3 = 40/3\n\nAs we know, money divided in their efficiency ratio.\nA + B + C = 15,\n A + C = 10 \n A + B = 9\nEfficiency of B = 15 - 10 = 5\nEfficiency of A = 9 - 5 = 4\nEfficiency of C = 10 - 4 = 6\nThe money divided among A, B, and C in the ratio = 4 : 5 : 6",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Sandy and Mandy do (8/13)th part of the work and the rest of the work was completed by Andy. If Sandy, Mandy and Andy take the same work for Rs 2600, then what is the share (in Rs) of Andy?",
    "choice_1": 1600,
    "choice_2": 1400,
    "choice_3": 800,
    "choice_4": 1000,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Formula used : W = E xT \n\nWhere, W = Work, E = Efficiency, and T = Time\n\nCalculation : \n\nLet the amount of total work be “a” \n\nWork done by Sandy and Mandy = 8a/13\n\nWork done by Andy = a - 8a/13 = 5a/13\n\nTotal amount of money taken by the 3 people = Rs. 2600\n\nAndy's share = 2600 x [(5a/13)/a]\n\n Andy's share = Rs. 1000",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "12 Men and 6 women can do a piece of work in 14 days, while 8 men and 9 women can do the work in 16 days. if a man gets Rs 54 per days, what should be the wage of a woman per day?",
    "choice_1": "Rs.45",
    "choice_2": "Rs.36",
    "choice_3": "Rs.76",
    "choice_4": "Rs.92",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Let a man's and a woman's one day work be denoted by M and W, respectively.\n\n12M + 6W=  1/14   and 8M + 9W = 1/16\n\nSolving the two equations, we get M = 1/224  and W = 1/336\n\nNow, M/W = 3/2\n\nWoman's Wage = 2/3 * man's wage \n \n                          =2/3 x  54 = Rs 36.",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If the wage of 45 women amount to Rs 15525 in 48 days, how many men must work for 16 days to receive Rs 5750, The daily wage of a man being double of that of a woman?",
    "choice_1": 45,
    "choice_2": 38,
    "choice_3": 25,
    "choice_4": 12,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "#ERROR!",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A and B complete a task in 12 days and 16 days respectively. They work together to finish the task and earn ₹5600. How should the wages be divided between A and B?",
    "choice_1": "3200,2400",
    "choice_2": "2400,3200",
    "choice_3": "3600,2000",
    "choice_4": "2600,3000",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Total work = LCM(12, 16) = 48 unit\nEfficiency of A = 48/12=4 units/day\nEfficiency of B = 48/16=3 units/day\nRatio of efficiencies = 4:3\nA's share = 4/7×5600=₹3200\nB's share = ₹2400",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B, and C are hired to complete a task for ₹9000. A can complete the task in 15 days, B in 20 days, and C in 30 days. How much will each person earn if they work together to complete the task?",
    "choice_1": "3200,2400,3400",
    "choice_2": "3400,3200,2400",
    "choice_3": "3600,2000,3600",
    "choice_4": "4000,3000,2000",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Total work = LCM(15, 20, 30) = 60 units\nefficiency  of A = 60/15=4  , efficiency of B = 60/20=3, efficiency of C = 60/30=2\nWages are divided in the ratio 4:3:2\nA's share = 4/9×9000=₹4000\nB's share =3/9 x 9000= 3000\nC's share = 2/9 x9000= 2000",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A and B are paid ₹4800 to complete a task. A works for 6 days and B works for 8 days to complete it. If A’s efficiency is twice that of B, what are their individual earnings?",
    "choice_1": "RS 2500, RS 2300",
    "choice_2": "RS 2880, RS 1920",
    "choice_3": "RS 2600, RS 2200",
    "choice_4": "RS  4300 ,RS 4500",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Let B’s efficiency = x. Then, A’s efficiency = 2x\nWork done by A = 6×2x=12x\nWork done by B = 8×x=8x\nRatio of work = 12x:8x=3:2 \nA’s share = 3/5×4800=₹2880\nB’s share = ₹1920",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B, and C earn ₹8400 for a task. A and B together can complete the task in 8 days, B and C together in 12 days, and A and C together in 10 days. How much will A earn?",
    "choice_1": "RS  4936.27",
    "choice_2": "RS 3926.26",
    "choice_3": "RS 3546.36",
    "choice_4": "RS 3856.76",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Total work = LCM(8, 12, 10) = 120 units\nEfficiency of A + B = 120/8=15\nEfifciency of  B + C = 120/12=10\nEfficiency of  A + C = 120/10=12.\nSo Efficiency of  A+B+C=37/2=18.5\nRatio = 8.5:6.5:3.5\nA’s share = 8.5/18.5×8400=₹3856.76",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Ram and Shyam undertake a piece of work for Rs 300. Ram can do it in 20 days and Shyam can do it in 60 days. With the help of Radha, they finish it in 10 days. How much should Radha be paid for her contribution?",
    "choice_1": "Rs.100",
    "choice_2": "Rs.200",
    "choice_3": "Rs.300",
    "choice_4": "Rs.400",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Ram alone takes 20 days and Shyam alone takes 60 days to finish the work.\nAll together can finish in 10 days.\nLet the total work done is LCM(10, 20, 60) = 60\nRam’s efficiency = 60/20 = 3\nShyam’s efficiency = 60/60 = 1\nCombined Efficiency = 60/10= 6\nRadha’s efficiency = 6 – 3 -1 = 2\n\nefficiency ratio = 3:1:2\n\ntherefore radha’s money = (2/6)*300=100 rs",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B and C took a job on contract for Rs. 6300. Only A and B worked for the first 6 days and only C worked for the next 4. If C alone can do the task in 10 days, how much is his share in the payment?",
    "choice_1": "Rs.2000",
    "choice_2": "Rs.3000",
    "choice_3": "Rs.3300",
    "choice_4": "Rs.2520",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "C can complete the entire job in 10 days.\n\nC's work rate is 1/10​ of the job per day.\n\nCalculate the work done by C:\n\nC worked for 4 days\n\nWork done by C = 4 days ×1/10​ of the job per day = 4/10=2/5​ of the job.\n\nCalculate C's share of the payment:\n\nTotal payment for the job is Rs. 6300.\n\nC's share = 2/5​ of Rs. 6300 = 2/5×6300.\n\nCalculate the amount:\n\nC′s share=2/5​×6300=2520",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B and C together earn Rs. 640 for 1 day’s work, A and B earn Rs. 1440 for 4 days’ work, B and C also earn Rs. 1440 for 3 days work. How much money (in rupees) would B earn for a day’s work?",
    "choice_1": 180,
    "choice_2": 200,
    "choice_3": 240,
    "choice_4": 144,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A+B+C=640\n\n4(A+B)=1440\n\n⟹A+B=1440/4​=360\n\n3(B+C)=1440\n\n⟹B+C=1440/3​=480\n\nA+B+C=640\nA+B=360\nB+C=480\n\n(A+B+C)−(B+C)=640−480 ⟹ A=160\n\nA+B=360⟹160+B=360 ⟹ B = Rs.200",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Mayank can do a piece of work in 3 days while Sanjay can do the same work in 4 days. The wage for the full work is Rs. 350. If they both work together to complete the work then find the earnings of Sanjay.",
    "choice_1": 100,
    "choice_2": 130,
    "choice_3": 145,
    "choice_4": 150,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Ratio of work done by Mayank and Sanjay = 3 : 4\n\nRatio of their earning = 4 : 3\n\nMayank earning = 4x/7x * 350  Rs. 200\n\nSanjay earning = 3x/7x * 350 Rs. 150",
    "Topic": "DIVISION OF WAGES(TIME AND WORK)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If a person walks at 14 km/hr instead of 10 km/hr, he would have walked 20 km more. The actual distance travelled by him is",
    "choice_1": "50 km",
    "choice_2": "60 km",
    "choice_3": "70 km",
    "choice_4": "80 km",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Speed = Distance/Time\nLet the time be x hours\n 14x - 10x = 20\n 4x = 20\nx = 5 hours\nHis actual speed is 10 km/h\nSo the actual distance is= 10 x 5 = 50 km.\n:. The actual distance is 50 km.",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Excluding stoppages, the speed of a bus is 54 kmph and including stoppages, it is 45 kmph. For how many minutes does the bus stop per hour?",
    "choice_1": 9,
    "choice_2": 10,
    "choice_3": 11,
    "choice_4": 12,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Due to stoppages, it covers 9 km less.\nTime taken to cover 9 km =(9/54) x 60 min = 10 min.",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The ratio between the speeds of two trains is 7 : 8. If the second train runs 400 km in 4 hours, then the speed of the first train is:",
    "choice_1": "85 km/hr",
    "choice_2": "86.5 km/hr",
    "choice_3": "87.5 km/hr",
    "choice_4": "89 km/hr",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Let the speed of two trains be 7x and 8x km/hr.\n\nDistance = speed * time\n\nSpeed of 2nd train = 400/4 = 100 km/hr\n\nThen, 8x = 100\n\n x = 100/8 = 12.5 \n\nSpeed of first train = (7 x 12.5) km/hr = 87.5 km/hr.",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man on tour travels first 160 km at 64 km/hr and the next 160 km at 80 km/hr. The average speed for the first 320 km of the tour is:",
    "choice_1": "69 km/hr",
    "choice_2": "70 km/hr",
    "choice_3": "71 km/hr",
    "choice_4": "72 km/hr",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "If the distance covered is the same then average speed = 2xy/(x + y)\n\nWhere, x = first speed\n            y = second speed\n\nAverage speed = 2 x 64 x 80/(64 + 80) km/hr\n\n10240/144 km/hr\n 71.11 km/hr.\n\n The average speed for 320 km is 71.11 km/hr",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In covering a distance of 30 km, Abhay takes 2 hours more than Sameer. If Abhay doubles his speed, then he would take 1 hour less than Sameer. Abhay's speed is:",
    "choice_1": "5 kmph",
    "choice_2": "6 kmph",
    "choice_3": "7 kmph",
    "choice_4": "8 kmph",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Let Abhay's speed be x km/hr.\n\nTime = distance / speed\n\nSpeed = d/t\n\nSpeed 🡺 1-> 30/1 = 30 🡺  doubles ->( 2) 🡺 30/2 🡪 15   \n\nDiffernce b/w 30 & 15 🡺 15\n\nTime difference = 3\n\nSpped = d / t   –> 15/3 = 5        \n\nOr \n\n30/x = t+2 -🡪 (1)\n30/2x = t-1 🡪(2)\n\n(1)-(2)\nThen,        30/x        -        30/2x        = 3 \n30/x [1-1/2] = 3\n30/x * ½ = 3\nX= 30",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A farmer travelled a distance of 61 km in 9 hours. He travelled partly on foot @ 4 km/hr and partly on bicycle @ 9 km/hr. The distance travelled on foot is:",
    "choice_1": "13 km",
    "choice_2": "14 km",
    "choice_3": "15 km",
    "choice_4": "16 km",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Let the distance travelled on foot be x km.\nThen, distance travelled on bicycle = (61 -x) km.\n\nTime = d/s\n\nSo,x/4 + (61 -x)/9 = 9        \n 9x + 4(61 -x) = 9 x 36\n5x + 244 = 324\n 5x = 80\n x = 16 km.",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "An aeroplane covers a certain distance at a speed of 240 kmph in 5 hours. To cover the same distance in 5/3 hours, it must travel at a speed of:",
    "choice_1": "300 kmph",
    "choice_2": "360 kmph",
    "choice_3": "600 kmph",
    "choice_4": "720 kmph",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Speed = d/t\n\nDistance = (240 x 5) = 1200 km.\n\nSpeed = Distance/Time\n\nSpeed = 1200/(5/3) km/hr.   \n\nRequired speed =1200x3/5km/hr= 720 km/hr.",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man complete a journey in 10 hours. He travels first half of the journey at the rate of 21 km/hr and second half at the rate of 24 km/hr. Find the total journey in km.",
    "choice_1": "220 km",
    "choice_2": "224 km",
    "choice_3": "228 km",
    "choice_4": "232 km",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "He travels the second half of the journey = 24 km/h\n\nSpeed = Distance/time\n\nLet the total distance be 2d km\n(d/21 +d/24) = 10\n 8d+7d/168  = 10\n15d/168 = 10\nd = 112 km\n\nNow, the total distance = 2d = (2 x 112) km = 224 km\n\n:. The required total journey is 224 km.\n\n\nOr \n\n(1/2)x /21       +        (1/2)x/24        = 10       \n\n x/21        +        x /24       = 20 \n\n15x = 168 x 20\n\n x =               ( 168 x 20)15              \n\nX   = 224 km.",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A car travelling with  5/7 of its actual speed covers 42 km in 1 hr 40 min 48 sec. Find the actual speed of the car.",
    "choice_1": "20 kmph",
    "choice_2": "25 kmph",
    "choice_3": "30 kmph",
    "choice_4": "35 kmph",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Time taken = 1 hr + 40/50 min + 48/3600 sec =   126/75        hrs.\n\nDistance travelled = 42 km \n\nSpeed = d/t \n\nSpeed  = 42/126/75 🡺 42 * 75/126\n\nSpeed of car = 5/7 * actual spped \n\nActual speed = 42 * 75/126 * 7/5\n\n7 * 5 \n\n35 km/hr\nLet the actual speed be x km/hr.\n\nThen,        (5/7)x    x        126/75        = 42\n\n x =                (42 x 7 x 75) / (5*126)                = 35 km/hr.",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A person crosses a 600 m long street in 5 minutes. What is his speed in km per hour?",
    "choice_1": "3.6 kmph",
    "choice_2": "7.2 kmph",
    "choice_3": "14.4 kmph",
    "choice_4": "24.8 kmph",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Length of the street = 600 m = 0.6 km\nTime = 5 minutes = 1/12 hours\n\nConcept Used:\n\n1 km = 1000 m\n1 hour = 60 minutes\nSpeed = Distance / Time\n\nCalculation:\n\nRequired speed = 0.6 / (1/12) = 7.2 km/hr\n\n Speed in km per hour is 7.2 km/hr.",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A train covers a distance of 360 km at a certain speed. If its speed had been 20 km/h more, it would have taken 1 hour less. What is the original speed of the train?",
    "choice_1": "40 km/h",
    "choice_2": "60 km/h",
    "choice_3": "75 km/h",
    "choice_4": "90 km/h",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Let the original speed be X km/h.\nThen time taken =  360/X hours.\nIf speed was X+20 , time = 360/(X+20) hours.\nGiven:\n360/x – 360/(x + 20) = 1\nSolve:\n(360(x + 20) - 360x)/(x(x + 20)) = 1\n(360-20)/(x(x + 20)) = 1\n7200 = x(x + 20)\nx2 + 20x - 7200 = 0\nSolving the quadratic:\nx = 75",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two cars start at the same time from two points 600 km apart and travel towards each other. One car travels 10 km/h faster than the other. If they meet after 5 hours, what is the speed of the faster car?",
    "choice_1": "50 km/h",
    "choice_2": "60 km/h",
    "choice_3": "65 km/h",
    "choice_4": "70 km/h",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Let the slower car's speed be  km/h.\nThen the faster car's speed is  km/h.\nSince they meet in 5 hours:\n5x + 5(x + 10) = 600\n5x + 5x + 50 = 600  \n10x = 550\nx = 55 \nx + 10 = 65\nThat means the answer is 65 km/h",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man travels from town A to B at 40 km/h and returns at 60 km/h. What is his average speed for the entire journey?",
    "choice_1": "48 km/h",
    "choice_2": "50 km/h",
    "choice_3": "52 km/h",
    "choice_4": "55 km/h",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Average speed for a round trip when speeds are different:\nAverage Speed = 2xy/(x + y) \n                           = (2*40*60*)/(40 + 60} \n                           = 4800/100\n                           = 48 km/h",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A cyclist travels 50 km at a certain speed. Due to a puncture, his speed reduces by 5 km/h for the next 50 km. If the entire journey takes 9 hours, what was his original speed?",
    "choice_1": "10 km/h",
    "choice_2": "14 km/h",
    "choice_3": "20 km/h",
    "choice_4": "25 km/h",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Let original speed = X km/h\nThen reduced speed = X-5 km/h\nTime = 50/X + 50/(X-5) = 9\n50(X-5) + 50X = 9(X(X-5))\n50X-250 + 50X = 9(X2 – 5X)\n100X-250 = 9X2 – 45X\n9x2 - 145x + 250 = 0\nX = 14km/hr",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man decided to cover a distance of 6 km in 84 minutes. He decided to cover two-thirds of the distance at 4 km/hr and the remaining at some different speed. Find the speed after the two-thirds distance has been covered.",
    "choice_1": "6 km/hr",
    "choice_2": "5 km/hr",
    "choice_3": "4 km/hr",
    "choice_4": "3 km/hr",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "4 km distance was covered at 4 km/hr.  Time taken to cover 4 km = 4 km / 4 km / hr = 1 hr = 60 minutes => Time left = 84 - 60 = 24 minutes Now, the man has to cover the remaining 2 km in 24 minutes or 24 / 60 = 0.4 hours => Speed required for remaining 2 km = 2 km / 0.4 hr = 5 km / hr",
    "Topic": "TIME SPEED DISTANCE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The distance between two cities A and B is 80 km. A motorcycle rider starts from A towards B at 7 am at a speed of 10 km/hr. Another motorcyclist starts from B towards A at 8 am at a speed of 25 km/hr. At what time will they cross each other?",
    "choice_1": "2:00 am",
    "choice_2": "3:00 am",
    "choice_3": "9:00 am",
    "choice_4": "10:00 am",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "In one hour, the earlier rider covers a distance of 10 km.\n\nThe distance between the two = 80 – 10 = 70 km.\n\nHence, the two riders approach each other with a relative speed of 10 + 25 = 35 kmph.\n\nThe time taken = 70/35 = 2 hrs. Therefore, they meet each other at (8 + 2) = 10 am.",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two trains start at the same time from two stations and proceed towards each other at the rate of 20 km/hr and 25 km/hr respectively. When they meet, it is found that one train has traveled 80 km more than the other. Find the distance between the two stations.",
    "choice_1": "700 KM",
    "choice_2": "400KM",
    "choice_3": "720 KM",
    "choice_4": "800 KM",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "In one hour, one train travels 5 km more than the other. The trains meet in 80/5 = 16 hours.\n\nTherefore, the distance = (20 + 25) x 16 = 720 km.",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two trains start at the same time from Aligarh and Delhi and proceed towards each other at the rate of 16 km/hr and 21 km/hr respectively. When they meet, it is found that one train has traveled 60 km more than the other. The distance between the two stations is",
    "choice_1": "333 KM",
    "choice_2": "444 KM",
    "choice_3": "222 KM",
    "choice_4": "343 KM",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Both the trains are coming closer to each other by (21 – 16), i.e., 5 km every hour.\n\nThey would meet after 60/5 = 12 hrs. Hence, the distance between the 2 stations = (21 + 16) x 12 = 37 x 12 = 444 km",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A starts from X at 9:00 am and reaches Y at 1:00 pm. B starts from Y at 9:00 am and reaches X at 3 pm. At what time do the two meet?",
    "choice_1": "11:30 am",
    "choice_2": "11:24 am",
    "choice_3": "11:00 am",
    "choice_4": "12:00 am",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Assuming the distance between X and Y to be d, since A and B take 4 hours and 6 hours respectively to cover the distance, their speeds are d/4 and d/6 .so, 4* 6 / 4+6 = 2.4 hrs ..afteer 9 am",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two boats, traveling at 5 and 10 km per hour, head directly towards each other. They begin at a distance of 20 km from each other. How far apart are they (in km) one minute before they collide?",
    "choice_1": "1/4",
    "choice_2": "1/8",
    "choice_3": "1/3",
    "choice_4": "1/2",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Relative speed of two boats =5+10=15 km/hr i.e. in 60 min they cover (together) = 15 km . 15/60 = 1/4\n\nIn 1 min they will cover (together)",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A train X departs from station A at 11.00 a.m. for station B, which is 180 km away. Another train Y departs from station B at 11.00 a.m. for station A. Train X travels at an average speed of 70 kms/hr and does not stop anywhere until it arrives at station B. Train Y travels at an average speed of 50 kms/hr, but has to stop for 15 minutes at station C, which is 60 kms away from station B enroute to station A. Ignoring the lengths of the trains, what is the distance, to the nearest km, from station A to the point where the trains cross each other?",
    "choice_1": "112 KM",
    "choice_2": "200 KM",
    "choice_3": "212 KM",
    "choice_4": "69 KM",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Time taken by train Y to reach station C which is 60 km away = \n60\n50\n=\n1\n1\n5\n hour = 1 hr 12 min\nTrain Y then stops in station C for 15 minutes.\nTime taken by train Y to leave station C = 1 hr 12 min + 15 minutes = 1 hr 27 min\n\nDistance travelled by train X in this 1 hr 27 minutes = \n70\n×\n1\n27\n60\n=\n70\n×\n87\n60\n = 101.5 km\n\nAfter 1 hr 27 minutes, distance between train X and Y = 180 – 60 – 101.5 = 18.5 km\nRelative speed = 70 + 50 = 120 km/hr\n\nTime taken by the trains to meet each other = \n18.5\n120\n=\n37\n240\n hr\n\nDistance travelled by train X in this time = \n70\n×\n37\n240\n = 10.8 km\n\nRequired distance from station A to the point where trains cross each other = 101.5 + 10.8 = 112.3 ≈ 112 km",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Navjivan Express from Ahmedabad to Chennai leaves Ahmedabad at 6:30 am and travels at 50 km per hour towards Baroda situated 100 km away. At 7 : 00 am Howrah-Ahmedabad Express leaves Baroda towards Ahmedabad and travels at 40 km per hour. At 7 : 30 Mr. Shah, the traffic controller at Baroda realises that both the trains are running on the same track. How much time does he have to avert a head-on collision between the two trains?",
    "choice_1": "15 MINS",
    "choice_2": "20 MINS",
    "choice_3": "30 MINS",
    "choice_4": "40 MINS",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The distance between Ahmedabad and Baroda given is 100 Km\n\nNavjivan express starts at 6:30 am at 50 Km/hr and Howrah expresses starts at 7:00 am at 40 Km/hr.\n\nTherefore, the distance covered by Navjivan express in 30 minutes (by 7 am) is 25 Km/hr.\n\nHence, at 7 am, the distance between the two trains is 75 Kms and they are travelling in opposite direction with a relative speed of 50+40=90 Km/hr.\n\nSo, the time taken them to meet is \n75\n90\n×\n60\n=\n50\nm\ni\nn\nu\nt\ne\ns\n.\n\nAlso, the problem was realized after thirty minutes. Therefore, the time left to avoid collision is 50-30 = 20 minutes",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A security guard starts chasing a robber. When the robber takes 12\nsteps, the guard takes 9 steps. Additionally, 4 steps of the guard\nare equal in distance to 5 steps of the robber. What is the ratio of\nthe speeds of the guard and the robber?",
    "choice_1": "15:16",
    "choice_2": "16:15",
    "choice_3": "11:12",
    "choice_4": "12:11",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Robber takes 12 steps while the guard takes 9 steps in the same time.\n\nThis means the step frequency ratio steps per unit time is:\n\nGuard Steps: Robber Steps = 9 : 12 = 3 : 4\n\n4 steps of the guard = 5 steps of the robber in distance.\n\nThus, the step length ratio is:\n\nGuard Step Length: Robber Step Length = 5:4\n\nSpeed is determined by step frequency x step length.\n\nLet:\n\nGuard's step frequency = 33 steps/sec.\nRobber's step frequency = 44 steps/sec.\n\nGuard's step length = 55 units.\n\nRobber's step length = 44 units.\n\nGuard's Speed = 3 x 5 = 15 units/sec.\n\nRobber's Speed = 4 x 4=16 units/sec.\n\nSpeed Ratio = Guard's Speed: Robber's Speed = 15 : 16\n\nThus, the ratio of the speeds of the guard and the robber is 15 : 16.",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The ratio between the speeds of two trains is 7: 8: If the second train runs 400 kms in 4 hours, then the speed of first train is:",
    "choice_1": 85,
    "choice_2": 87.5,
    "choice_3": 83,
    "choice_4": 92,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Given ratio = 7:8, Speed of the second train = 100 km/h Speed of the first train = (100 × 7) / 8 ⇒ Speed of the first train = 700 / 8 ⇒ Speed of the first train = 87.5 km/h The speed of the first train is 87.5 km/h.",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A rocket is launched at intervals of 11.5 seconds, moving in the same direction as a train traveling at an unknown speed. The speed of sound is 330 m/s. If a person seated inside the train hears the sound of the rocket after 11 seconds, determine the speed of the train.",
    "choice_1": 13,
    "choice_2": 12,
    "choice_3": 15,
    "choice_4": 19,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "330 + Vt = 30 × 11.5 ⇒ 330 + Vt = 345 ⇒ Vt = 345 - 330 ⇒ Vt = 15 m/s",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Moving at 50 kmph, a person reaches his office 10 min late. Next day, he increases his speed and moves at 60 kmph and reaches his office 5 min early. What is the distance from his home to his office?",
    "choice_1": "67 km",
    "choice_2": "75km",
    "choice_3": "23km",
    "choice_4": "102km",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "We can observe that difference in timings on both days is 15 min (and not 5 min, as one day he is late and on the other day he is early)\nLet the required distance = D km. As time taken at the speed of 50 kmph is more than time taken at 60 kmph, so equation can be formed as D/50-D/60=15/60.Solving this equation, we get the answer as 75 km.",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A person goes from A to B at the speed of 40 kmph and comes back at the speed of 60 kmph. What is his average speed for the whole journey?",
    "choice_1": 34,
    "choice_2": 48,
    "choice_3": 11,
    "choice_4": 23,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Since the distance traveled on both sides is the same, we can use the formula of harmonic mean of speeds.\nAverage Speed: 2xy/(x+y) where, x is the speed while going from A to B and y is the speed while coming back.\nSo using this formula, we get the answer as 48 kmph.",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A train 125 m long passes a man, running at 5 km/hr in the same direction in which the train is going, in 10 seconds. The speed of the train is",
    "choice_1": 30,
    "choice_2": 20,
    "choice_3": 50,
    "choice_4": 40,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Let the speed of the train be x km/hr. Then, relative speed = (x - 5) km/hr.\n\n x - 5 = 45          x = 50 km/hr.",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 27 seconds and 17 seconds respectively and they cross each other in 23 seconds. The ratio of their speeds is:",
    "choice_1": "3/2",
    "choice_2": "1/2",
    "choice_3": "5/19",
    "choice_4": "3/43",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Let the speeds of the two trains be x m/sec and y m/sec respectively.\n\nThen, length of the first train = 27x metres,\n\nand length of the second train = 17y metres.         27x + 17y/x+y = 23 ,..x/y = 3/2",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A train 360 m long is running at a speed of 45 km/hr. In what time will it pass a bridge 140 m long?",
    "choice_1": 20,
    "choice_2": 30,
    "choice_3": 40,
    "choice_4": 50,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "500*2/40 = 50 sec",
    "Topic": "RELATIVE SPEED"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A 270 metres long train running at the speed of 120 kmph crosses another train running in opposite direction at the speed of 80 kmph in 9 seconds. What is the length of the other train?",
    "choice_1": "230 m",
    "choice_2": "240 m",
    "choice_3": "260 m",
    "choice_4": "320 m",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Let length of the train be x m\nLength of first train = 270 m\nSpeed of the two trains is 120 km/hr and 80 km/h\nRelative speed, if opposite direction = 120 + 80 = 200 * 5/18  =500/9 m/sec\n\nAs we know,\nSpeed = distance/time\n500/9 = (270 +x)/9\n x = 500 – 270\nX = 230",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A flight from Srinagar to Trivandrum has an average speed of 400 km/hr without any stoppage. The average speed decreases to 320 km/hr when there are stoppages. Find the stoppage time per hour of the flight?",
    "choice_1": "6 min",
    "choice_2": "15 min",
    "choice_3": "18 min",
    "choice_4": "24 min",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Minutes of stops per hour = [(Faster speed - Slower speed)/Faster speed] x 60\nDifference in speed = 400−320=80 km/hr.\nStoppage time per hour = 80/400=1/5 hours. \nStoppage time per hour = 1/5×60=12 minutes.",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Without any stoppage, a person travels a certain distance at an average speed of 42 km/h, and with stoppages, he covers the same distance at an average speed of 28 km/h. How many minutes per hour does he stop",
    "choice_1": "14 min",
    "choice_2": "15  min",
    "choice_3": "28  min",
    "choice_4": "20  min",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Minutes of stops per hour = [(Faster speed - Slower speed)/Faster speed] x 60\nLet the total distance to be covered is 84 kms.Time taken to cover the distance without stoppage = 84/42 hrs = 2 hrs\u000bTime taken to cover the distance with stoppage = 84/28 = 3 hrs.Thus, he takes 60 minutes to cover the same distance with stoppage.Therefore, in 1 hour he stops for 20 minutes.",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 27 seconds and 17 seconds respectively and they cross each other in 23 seconds. The ratio of their speeds is",
    "choice_1": "1:3",
    "choice_2": "3:2",
    "choice_3": "3:4",
    "choice_4": "None of these",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Total time = Total Distance/Total speed\n\nLet the speed of the first train and the second train be \"a\" and \"b“\nLength of the first train = 27a\nLength of the second train = 17b\nT = d/s\n23 = 27a+17b/a+b\n23a + 23b = 27a + 17b\n6b = 4a\na/b = 6/4 = 3/2\na: b=3:2\n:. The ratio of their speeds is 3 : 2",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A train travelling at 30kmph takes 27/2 seconds in passing a certain point .Find the length of the train.",
    "choice_1": "112.5 m",
    "choice_2": "115.5 m",
    "choice_3": "122.5 m",
    "choice_4": "132.5 m",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "S=30km/hr  --=30 *5/18   m/s\nDistance = speed * time\nD= 30*5/18    *27/2\nD=112.5m",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A Train runs at speed of 42 m/s and takes 35 seconds to pass a tunnel. After travelling some distance. It takes 15 seconds to pass a pole. What is the length of the tunnel?",
    "choice_1": "162 m",
    "choice_2": "630 m",
    "choice_3": "840 m",
    "choice_4": "240 m",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "distance = length  of train + length  of tunnel \nd= 42*35=1470m\nd=15*42=630 m\n=1470-630 =840m",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A train 110 metres long is running with a speed of 60 kmph. In what time will it pass a man who is running at 6 kmph in the direction opposite to that in which the train is going?",
    "choice_1": "5 sec",
    "choice_2": "6 sec",
    "choice_3": "7 sec",
    "choice_4": "10 sec",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Relative speed = 60 + 6 = 66 km/hr                        \n\nDistance = speed * time \n\n110 = 66 * 5/18 * t\n\nT = 6 sec",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A train crosses a bridge of 400 m in 65 seconds. Speed of train is 36 km/hour. How long it will take to cross a platform of length 350 m?",
    "choice_1": "2 min",
    "choice_2": "1 min",
    "choice_3": "40 sec",
    "choice_4": "20 sec",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Speed in m/s=Speed in km/h×1000/3600 m/s\n​=36×5/18=10 m/s\n2: Determine the Length of the Train\nLength of the train = L meters\nLength of the bridge = 400 meters\nTime taken to cross the bridge = 65 seconds\nSpeed of the train =  36 * 5/18  10 m/s\n\nThe total distance covered when crossing the bridge is L+400 meters.\n\nSpeed in m/s=Speed in km/h×1000/3600 m/s\n​=36×5/18=10 m/\n\nDistance=Speed×Time\n\nL+400=10×65\nL+400=650\nL=650−400\nL=250 meters\n\nStep 3: Calculate Time to Cross the Platform\n\nTotal distance=Length of train+Length of platform\n                      =250+350=600 meters\n\nTime=Distance/Speed=600/10=60 seconds",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two  train  start at  the  same time   from A &B   and proceed towards  B  and A  at 36km/hr  and 42km/hr respectively . when they  meet, it is found   that one train   has  moved 48km more than the other . what is the distance  between  A  and  B ?",
    "choice_1": "624km",
    "choice_2": "600 km",
    "choice_3": "578km",
    "choice_4": "700km",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "T1  =T2 ---  >D/S=D/S\nX/36  =X+48/42\n7X=6X+288\nX=288=X+48 =336\n=288+336=624KM",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two trains running in opposite directions on parallel tracks, at speeds of 33 km/hr and 39 km / hr ,take 23 seconds to cross each other. If the length of one train is 250 m, then the length of the other train is:",
    "choice_1": "210 m",
    "choice_2": "225 m",
    "choice_3": "240 m",
    "choice_4": "190 m",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Let the length of the second train be x cm.\n\nLength of the first train = 250 m\n\nSpeed of the first train = 33 km/h\n\nSpeed of the second train = 39 km/h\n\nTime taken to cross each other = 23 sec\n\nSpeed = Distance/Time\n\n (33 + 39) x 5/18 = (250+x)/23\n\n72 * 5/18 *23 = 250+x\n\n460 -250 = x\n\n210m",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two stations A and B are 110 km apart on a straight line. One train starts from A at 7 a.m. and travels towards B at 20 kmph. Another train starts from B at 8 a.m. and travels towards A at a speed of 25 kmph. At what time will they meet?",
    "choice_1": "9.00 am",
    "choice_2": "10.00 am",
    "choice_3": "10.30 am",
    "choice_4": "11.00 am",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "TIME =X hours \nDistance  covered by A =20X\nDistance  covered by B (X-1)=25(X-1)\n20X+25(X-1) =110\n20X+25X-25=110\n45X=135\nX=3",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A train starts at 11:00 am from point A towards point B at 36 km/h while another train starts at 1:00 pm from point B  towards point A at 44 km/h. They cover a distance of 712 km till the meeting. At what time will they meet each other?",
    "choice_1": "7:30 pm",
    "choice_2": "8:00 pm",
    "choice_3": "8:30 pm",
    "choice_4": "9:00 pm",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Distance travelled by train which starts from point a from 11 to 1 pm =  36 * 2 = 72 km\nDistance left = 712 – 72 -- > 640 km\nRelative speed = 36 + 44-- > 80 km/hr\nTime = 640/80 -- > 8 hr \n\nT = 9:00 \n\nor\nLet both trains meet each other after t hours from 11 am.\nDistance = Speed x Time\n36 x t + 44 (t - 2) =712\n36t + 44t-88 = 712\n80t=712 +88 \nT = 10 hours\ni.e.= 9:00 pm",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A 720m long train takes 96 seconds more to cross a platform than it takes to cross a pole at the same speed. Given that the length of platform is twice the length of train. What is the speed of train in km/h?",
    "choice_1": 36,
    "choice_2": 54,
    "choice_3": 45.5,
    "choice_4": 64.4,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The length of the platform is twice the length of the train. \n\nLength of platform = 2×720=1440m\n\nTime to cross the pole: tp=720/v\n\nTime to cross the platform: tpt=720+1440/v=2160/v\n\nThe train takes 96s more to cross the platform than the pole: tpl=tp+96\n\n the speed, 2160/v=720/v+96\n\n2160 – 720 = 96v\n\nV = 1440/96 --- > 15 m/s\n\nConvert into km/hr  15 * 18/5  54 km/hr",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A train covered a distance at a uniform speed .if the train had been 6 km/hr faster it would have been 4 hour less than schedule time and if the train were slower by 6 km/hr it would have been 6 hours more. Find the distance.",
    "choice_1": "720 km",
    "choice_2": "700 km",
    "choice_3": "600 km",
    "choice_4": "690km",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "D = T *S1*S2/S1-S2\nCASE  1 :    S  ,  S+6   T=4\nD= 4 *S*(S+6)/S+6-S\nD=4*S*(S+6)/6\nCase  2:\nS  , S-6\nD= 6*S*(S-6)/S-S+6\nD=6*S*(S-6)/6\n4*S*(S+6)/6   = 6*S*(S-6)/6\n         2S+12  =3S-18\n  S=30KM/HR\nD=4*30*36/6 =24*30  =720KM",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If a train runs with the speed of 84 km/hr, it reaches its destination late by 25 minutes. However, if its speed is 98 km/hr, it is late by 10 minutes only. The right time for the train to cover its journey is -",
    "choice_1": "60 min",
    "choice_2": "80 min",
    "choice_3": "75 min",
    "choice_4": "92 min",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Let right time for the train to cover its journey (in minutes) be x min,\nDistance = Speed x Time\nDistance is same, then\n84 * (x+25)/60= 98 * (x+10)/60\n6 (x + 25) = 7 (x + 10)\n6x + 150 = 7x + 70\nx = 150 – 70  \nX = 80 min",
    "Topic": "Problems on Trains"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A boat can travel at a speed of 13 km/hr in still water. If the speed of the stream is 4 km/hr, find the time taken by the boat to go 68 km downstream",
    "choice_1": "2 hours",
    "choice_2": "3 hours",
    "choice_3": "4 hours",
    "choice_4": "5  hours",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Speed downstream = (13 + 4) km/hr = 17 km/hr.\nTime taken to travel 68 km downstream =68/17 hrs = 4 hrs.",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A boat running downstream covers a distance of 24 km in 3 hours, while covering the same distance upstream, it takes 6 hours. What is the speed of the current?",
    "choice_1": "5 km/hr",
    "choice_2": "4 km/hr",
    "choice_3": "3 km/hr",
    "choice_4": "2 km/hr",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "The downstream speed = 24/3 = 8 km/hr\u000bThe upstream speed = 24/6 = 4 km/hr\u000bThe speed of the current = (8-4)/2 = 4/2 = 2km/hr",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A    man   can  swim   3km/hr  in still   water  . if the  velocity   of  the   stream be  2km/hr, the time taken   by him  to swim    to a    place    10km   upstream   and     back is ?",
    "choice_1": "12 hours",
    "choice_2": "10 hours",
    "choice_3": "13 hours",
    "choice_4": "9 hours",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "T=D/S+D/S\nT =10/1  +10/5\nT=10+2  =12 HOURS",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Speed of the boat in still water is 15 km/hr and the speed of the current is 7 km/hr. Find the total time taken by a man rowing to a place at a distance of 88 km and back.",
    "choice_1": "20 hours",
    "choice_2": "10 hours",
    "choice_3": "15 hours",
    "choice_4": "5 hours",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "The downstream speed is 15 + 7 = 22 km/hr, and The upstream speed = 15 - 7 = 8 km/hr.                    The total time taken = (88/22) + (88/8) = 4+11 = 15hours",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "An escalator having 60 steps is moving up at the speed of 2 steps/second. Aakash has to go to the first floor and come back on this escalator. Calculate the time taken by Akash if his speed on stationary escalator is 3 steps/second.",
    "choice_1": 72,
    "choice_2": 47,
    "choice_3": 34,
    "choice_4": 67,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Explanation :Speed of Akas while going upstairs = 3 + 2 = 5 s/s.\nTime take to go up = 60/5 = 12 seconds.\nSpeed of Akas while going downstairs = 3 - 2 = 1 s/s.\nTime take to come down = 60/1 = 60 seconds.\n=Total time taken by Akash = 12 + 60 = 72 seconds.\nHence, 72.",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Bobby is going up the escalator. It takes Bobby 80 seconds to walk up the escalator, which is moving upwards and 120 seconds to walk up the escalator, which is moving downwards. Calculate the time (in secs) taken by Bobby to climb the escalator which is stationary",
    "choice_1": 76,
    "choice_2": 96,
    "choice_3": 57,
    "choice_4": 95,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Let Bobby's speed be \"a\" steps per second and \nThe escalator's speed be \"x“ steps per second. \nWhen the escalator is moving up, no. of steps\nN = 80a + 80x (Since Bobby is moving upwards, 80x will be added)\nWhen the escalator is moving down, no. of steps \nN = 120a - 120x (Since Bobby is moving upwards, 120x will be subtracted)\nBy equating the number of steps, 80a + 80x = 120a - 120x.\na = 5x\n= N = 80a + 80x = 80a + 16a = 96a..\n Time taken when the escalator is stationary = 96a/a = 96 seconds.\nHence, 96",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "P and Q walk up a moving escalator at constant speeds. For every 5 steps that P takes, Q takes 3 steps. How many steps would each have to climb when the escalator is switched off, given that P takes 50 and Q takes 40 steps to climb up the moving escalator, respectively?",
    "choice_1": 80,
    "choice_2": 90,
    "choice_3": 100,
    "choice_4": "none  of  these",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Both the person and the escalator are moving in the same direction.\n In this case, the relative speed would be Speed of (Man + Stairs).\u000bWe don't know the speed of the escalator, so assume that to be e. Let the speed of P be 5a steps/sec and Q's is 3a steps/sec.\nP is walking 50 steps and he does it in 50/5a = 10/secs., but in this 10/a secs, even the escalator must have moved with speed \"e\".\n The length moved by it would be 10e/a.\nSo, we can say the total length is 50 + 10e/a (steps moved by P and the escalator helps P in reaching the top). \nSimilarly, for Q we can write 40 + 40e/3a\nBoth are moving on the same escalator, \nhence the total number of steps should be same.50 + 10e/a = 40 + 40e/3a\nSo, e/a = 3\nSo total length is 50 + 10e/a = 80",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A speedboat runs 6 km upstream in a river and comes back to the starting point in 33 minutes. The stream of the river is running at 2 km/hr. What is the speed of speedboat in still water?",
    "choice_1": "25 km/hr",
    "choice_2": "26 km/hr",
    "choice_3": "22 km/hr",
    "choice_4": "21 km/hr",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Total time = d / (x - s) + d / (x + s)\nLet the speed of the speedboat in still water be x km/h.Then, speed downstream = (x + 2) km/h, speed upstream = (x - 2) km/h.\u000bSince it goes 6 km upstream and comes back in 33 minutes,we have 6/(x+2) + 6/(x-2) = 33/60 = 11/20-->11x² - 240x - 44 = 0\u000b11x² - 242x + 2x - 44 = 0-- >(x - 22)(11x + 2) = 0\u000bx = 22. Therefore, the required speed = 22 km/h.",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A boat covers a certain distance downstream in 1 hour, while it comes back in 1 (1/2)hours. If the speed of the stream be 3 kmph, what is the speed of the boat in still water?",
    "choice_1": "12 kmph",
    "choice_2": "13 kmph",
    "choice_3": "14 kmph",
    "choice_4": "15 kmph",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "S =3km/hr \nB=b  km/hr\nU=b-3      V=b+3\n Du=Dv\n(b-3)*3/2    =(b+3)*1\n3b-9=2b+6\nB=9+6=15km/hr",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A boat can covers a certain distance in upstream and same distance in downstream in total of 7 hours 48 minutes, If upstream speed of the boat is 62.5% of downstream speed of the boat and speed of the stream is 3 km/hr, what is the total distance covered by the boat?",
    "choice_1": 84,
    "choice_2": 86,
    "choice_3": 96,
    "choice_4": 98,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Let the downstream speed be 8x.\nSo, upstream speed is 8x x 5/ 8 = 5x\nSo, [8x - 5x]/2 = 3\nSo, x = 2\nSo, upstream speed is 10 and downstream speed is 16\nLet the Distance be D.\nSo, D/16 + D /10 = 7 (48/60) = 39/5Or, 13D/80 = 39/5Or, D = 48 km\nTotal distance is 48+48 = 96",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Shivam is climbing on a moving escalator that is going up and takes 30 steps to reach the top. Atharva on the other hand is coming down on the same escalator. For every5 steps that Atharva takes, Shivam takes only 3 steps. Both of them take the same amount of time to reach the other end. What is the difference in the number of stepsthat both of them had taken when they crossed each other?",
    "choice_1": 10,
    "choice_2": 12,
    "choice_3": 13,
    "choice_4": 15,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Since both of them take the same time for the same distance, their effective speed is the same.\n=> 5s -  x = 3s + x\n=>x = S\nSpeed of Shivam: Speed of escalator = 3s: s = 3: 1\nWhen Shivam takes 30 steps, the escalator takes 10 steps.\nTotal number of steps = 30 + 10 = 40 steps.\nBoth of them would have covered 20 steps when they crossed each other.\nShivam going up would have taken 15 steps, whereas the escalator would have taken 5 steps for him.\nAtharva coming down would have taken 25 steps, out of which the escalator would have nullified the movement of 5 steps for him.\nDifference in the number of steps = 25 - 15 = 10 steps.",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Anand takes 90 secs to move up an escalator which is moving downward and hetakes 30 secs to move down the same escalator. How much time (in seconds)will he take to go up or down, when the escalator is switched off?",
    "choice_1": 46,
    "choice_2": 47,
    "choice_3": 45,
    "choice_4": 48,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Take the length of the stairs LCM(90, 30) = 90\nTime taken when going upstream is 90 seconds, \nso we can say M - E = 90/90 = 1 , M + E = 90/30 = 3\nSo, speed of Man = 4/2 = 2Time taken is 90/2 = 45 sec\nAlternately,\nWhen moving upstream, speed is M + E\n When the escalator is stopped, is M \nAnd when moving upstream, speed is M–E \nSpeed is in AP, so time will be in HP, since they are inversely proportional.\nSo, the time taken would be – \n2*90*30/(90+30) = 60 *90/120 = 45 secs.",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In the downstream, two steamers A and B start simultaneously from the point P, but the steamer B reaches point Q, 2 hours before the steamer A reaches the same point. If the distance between point P and Q is 120 km and the speed of steamer B in upstream is 3 km per hour more than that of steamer B in upstream and the speed of stream is 2 km per hour, then find the sum of the speed of steamer A in still water and that of steamer B in still water?",
    "choice_1": "21 km per hour",
    "choice_2": "20 km per hour",
    "choice_3": "23 km per hour",
    "choice_4": "24 km per hour",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Let the speed of steamer A in still water = a km per hour and the speed of steamer B in still water = b\nkm per hour\nThe speed of stream = 2 km per hour\nThen, according to the question, (b – 2) – (a – 2) = b – a = 3\nIn downstream, the speed of steamer A = a + 2 = b – 3 + 2 = b – 1 km per hour\nThe speed of steamer B = b + 2 km per hour\nThen, according to the question,\n120 – 120 = 2\nb – 1 b + 2\nBy solving, b = 13 km per hour\nTherefore, the speed of steamer A in still water = 13 – 3 = 10 km per hour\nThe required sum = 10 + 13 = 23 km per hour",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The time taken by a boatman to travel (x + 40) km downstream and (x – 40) km upstream is 20 hours. The downstream speed is 50% more than the upstream speed. If a boatman can travel (x + 40) km in 12 hours in still water, then find the value of x.",
    "choice_1": 140,
    "choice_2": 160,
    "choice_3": 180,
    "choice_4": 200,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Let, the speed of boatman in still water and stream speed = ‘B’ km/hr and ‘s’ km/hr respectively\nAccording to the question,\n(B + s) = 1.5 (B – s)\n2.5s = 0.5B\nB = 5s\nAlso, x + 40 + x – 40 = 20\nB + s B – s\n(x + 40) (B – s) + (x – 40) (B + s) = 20 (B + s) (B – s)\nB = 5s\n(x + 40) (4s) + (x – 40) (6s) = 20 (6s) (4s)\nAlso, x + 40 = 12\nB\nx + 40 = 60s\n(x + 40) (x + 40) + (x – 40) (x + 40) = 8 (x + 40) (x + 40)\n15 10 60\n4(x + 40)2 + 6 (x – 40) (x + 40) = 8 (x + 40)2\n6 (x – 40) (x + 40) = 4 (x + 40)2\n3x – 120 = 2x + 80\n3x – 2x = 120 + 80\nx = 200",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Two boats A and B start from two points P and Q respectively in a river along the flow of river. Boat A has speed 10 kmph and goes downstream to reach Q while B has speed 12 kmph and goes upstream to reach P. If ratio of time A and B took is 5:6, find the ratio of time taken by A and B for the return trip.",
    "choice_1": "6:5",
    "choice_2": "7:4",
    "choice_3": "7:3",
    "choice_4": "8:5",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Let the stream speed be r kmph.\nSince the distance between P and Q is constant, we have the below equation according to the given\ninformation\n(12–r)/(10 + r) = 5/6\nr = 2\nIn return trip, speed of A = 10 – 2 = 8 kmph\nSpeed of B = 12 + 2 = 14 kmph\nRatio of time taken by A to B = 14 : 8 = 7 : 4\nHence, option 2 is correct.",
    "Topic": "Problems on Boats  and   streams  , Escalator"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In a 50 m race, A can give a start of 5 m to B and a start of 14 m to C. In the same race, how much start can B give to C ?",
    "choice_1": "18 m",
    "choice_2": "10 m",
    "choice_3": "27 m",
    "choice_4": "9 m",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "At the same time,\n A covers 50 m, B covers (50 – 5) = 45 m, and C covers (50 – 14) = 36 m.\n If the race is between B and C only, applying the unitary method, \nwhen B runs 45 m, C runs 36 m. \nHence, when B runs 50 m, C runs (36/45 × 50 = 40) \nThis means B gives C a 10 m start.",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A and B take part in a 100 m race. A gives B a start of 10 m and still beats B by 5 seconds. If A's speed is 2.5 m/s, find B's speed.",
    "choice_1": "2 m/s",
    "choice_2": "2.5 m/s",
    "choice_3": "1 m/s",
    "choice_4": "2.25 m/s",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Time taken by A to cover 100 m = 100/2.5 = 40 seconds \nA gives B a start of 10 m. \nHence, B covers only 90 m. \nA beats B by 5 seconds. Hence, time taken by B to cover 90 m = 40+5 = 45 seconds\n B covers 90 m in 45 seconds. \nB's speed = 90/45 = 2 m/s",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In a race of 200m, A can beat B by 31m and C by 18m. In a race of 350m, C will beat B by",
    "choice_1": "22.75 m",
    "choice_2": "25 m",
    "choice_3": "19.5 m",
    "choice_4": "7 4/7 m",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A : B = 200 : 169\nA : C = 200 : 182\nC/B = C/A * A/B\n       = 182/200 * 200/169\n       = 182 : 169\nWhen C covers 182 m, B covers 169 m-- >When C covers 350 m, B covers (169 / 182×350)m=325m C beats B by (350 - 325) m = 25 m",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A runs 1 2/3 times as fast as B. If A gives B a start of 80 m, how far must the winning post be so that A and B might reach it at the same time?",
    "choice_1": "200 m",
    "choice_2": "300 m",
    "choice_3": "270 m",
    "choice_4": "160 m",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Ratio of speeds of A and B =5/3:1=5:3\nThus, in a race of 5m, A gains 2m over B.2m are gained by A in a race of 5m.80m will be gained by A in a race of-- >(5/2×80)m=200m.The winning post is 200 m away from the starting point",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B, and C are three participants in a kilometer race. A can give B a start of 50 m  and C a start of 69 m. The start that B can allow C is –",
    "choice_1": "17m",
    "choice_2": "18m",
    "choice_3": "19m",
    "choice_4": "20m",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "A: B: C= 1000 : (1000 - 50) : (1000 - 69)= 1000: 950: 931.In a 950 m race, B can give C a start of(950 - 931) m= 19 m.In a 1000 m race, B can give C a start of= (19/950×1000)= 20 m",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In a 5000-metre race, if runner A runs at a speed of 12 metres per second and runner B runs at a speed of 15 metres per second, how many seconds will it take for runner B to finish the race if runner A finishes the race in 20 minutes?",
    "choice_1": "15 minutes",
    "choice_2": "16 minutes",
    "choice_3": "17 minutes",
    "choice_4": "18 minutes",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "let's convert the time it takes for runner A to finish the race from minutes to seconds.\nRunner A finishes the race in 20 minutes, which is equivalent to:\n20 minutes * 60 seconds/minute = 1200 seconds\nNow, we can calculate how far runner A would have run in 1200 seconds at a speed of 12 meters per second:\nDistance = Speed × Time\nDistance = 12 m/s × 1200 s = 14400 meters\nSo, runner A covers a distance of 14400 meters in 1200 seconds.\nNow, we need to find out how long it will take runner B, who runs at a speed of 15 meters per second, to cover the same distance (14400 meters). We can use the formula:\nTime = Distance / Speed\nTime = 14400 meters / 15 m/s = 960 seconds\nTherefore, it will take runner B 960 seconds to finish the race, which is 16 minutes.",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A and B take part in a 100 metres race. A runs at 5 km per hour. A gives B a start of 8 metres and still beats him by 8 seconds. The speed of B is?",
    "choice_1": "4.45 km/hr",
    "choice_2": "4.14 km/hr",
    "choice_3": "4.15 km/hr",
    "choice_4": "4.25 km/hr",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A's speed = 5 km/hr= (5×5/18)  m/sec\u000b= 25/18 m/sec.Time taken by A to cover 100 metres= (100×18/25)= 72 sec.Time taken by B to cover 92 metres= (72 + 8) sec= 80 sec=B's speed=92/80 m/sec= (92/80×18/5)km/hr= 414/100 km/hr= 4.14 km/hr",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In a 400 m race, A gives B a start of 5 seconds and beats him by 15 m. In another race of 400 m, A beats B by 7 1/7 seconds. Their respective speed are-",
    "choice_1": "6 m/sec, 7 m/sec",
    "choice_2": "5 m/sec, 7 m/sec",
    "choice_3": "8 m/sec, 7 m/sec",
    "choice_4": "9 m/sec, 7 m/sec",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Suppose A covers 400 m in t seconds\u000bThen, B covers 385 m in (t + 5) seconds\u000b∴ B covers 400 m in={(t+5)/385×400} sec=80(t+5)/77 sec\nAlso, B covers 400 m in \n(t+7 1/7) sec\n=(7t+50)/7 sec\n∴80(t+5)/77=7t+50/7\n⇒80(t+5)=11(7t+50)⇒(80t−77t)=(550−400)⇒3t=150⇒t=50\n∴ A's speed=400/50m/sec\n=8m/sec\n∴B's speed=385/55m/sec\n=7m/sec",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In a 1547 m race, Arjun reaches in 78 seconds, while Karan reaches the finish point in 91 seconds. By how much distance does Arjun beat Karan",
    "choice_1": "220 m",
    "choice_2": "221 m",
    "choice_3": "246 m",
    "choice_4": "231 m",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Karan,91 sec → 1547 m-->1 sec → 17 m-- >78 sec → 1326 m.Arjun, 78 sec → 1547 m.Karan is defeated by Arjun by= 1547 - 1326 = 221 m",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In a linear race of 500 m, A beats B by 50 m, and in a race of 600 m, B beats C by 60 m. By how many metres will A beat C in a race of 400 m?",
    "choice_1": 70,
    "choice_2": 68,
    "choice_3": 76,
    "choice_4": 72,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "A     :     B\n                     500    :    450\n                      10     :      9\n          AND     B      :      C\n                     600    :    540\n                       10    :      9\n                A    :     B     :     C\n               10    :     9     :     9\n                10  -    10    :     9   \n            ------------------------\n             100    :   90    :    81\n              *4                       *4\n            =400                   =324\n  DIFF = 400-324 = 76 metres",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In a mile race, Akshay can be given a start of 128 m by Bhairav. If Bhairav can give Chinmay a start of 4 m in a 100 m dash, then who out of Akshay and Chinmay will win a race of one and half miles, and what will be the final lead given by the winner to the loser? One mile is 1,600 m",
    "choice_1": "Chinmay, 1/16 mile",
    "choice_2": "Chinmay, 1/2 mile",
    "choice_3": "Akshay ,11/6mile",
    "choice_4": "Akshay ,1/16 mile",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "In a mile race, Akshay can be given a start of 128 m by Bhairav. This means that Bhairav can afford to start after Akshay has travelled 128 m and still complete one mile with him. In other words, Bhairav can travel one mile, i.e. 1,600 m in the same time as Akshay can travel (1600 – 128) = 1,472 m. Hence, the ratio of the speeds of Bhairav and Akshay = Ratio of the distances travelled by them in the same time = 1600/1472 = 25 : 23.\n\nBhairav can give Chinmay a start of 4 miles. This means that in the time Bhairav runs 100 m, Chinmay only runs 96 m. So the ratio of the speeds of Bhairav and Chinmay = 96 : 100 = 25 : 24.\n\nHence, we have B : A = 25 : 23 and B : C = 25 : 24. So A : B : C = 23 : 25 : 24. This means that in the time Chinmay covers 24 m, Akshay only covers 23 m. In other words, Chinmay is faster than Akshay. So if they race for 1.5 miles = 2,400 m, Chinmay will complete the race first and by this time Akshay would only complete 2,300 m. In other words, Chinmay would beat Akshay by 100 m = 1/16 mile.",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In a 1500 m race, if vehicle P gives vehicle Q a start of 200 m, then vehicle P wins the race by 8 sec. Alternatively, if vehicle P gives vehicle Q a start of 400 m, the race ends in a dead heat. How long does vehicle P take to run 1500 m?",
    "choice_1": "44 sec",
    "choice_2": "45 sec",
    "choice_3": "40 sec",
    "choice_4": "60 sec",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "1300/Q − 1500/P = 8 . . . . (i)\nand, 1100/Q = 1500/P . . . . (ii)\nP/Q = 15/11 = 15x/11x\nFrom equation (i)\n1300/11x − 1500/15x = 8\n19500 − 16500=8×11x×15x\n3000=8×11×15x\nx=25/11\nTime of P to travel 1500m=1500/15x =1500×11/15×25 =44sec",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In a 10 km race. A, B, and C, each running at uniform speed, get the gold, silver, and bronze medals, respectively. If A beats B by 1 km and B beats C by 1 km, then by how many metres does A beat C?",
    "choice_1": 2000,
    "choice_2": 1900,
    "choice_3": 1800,
    "choice_4": 1600,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A beats B by 1 km, means A travels 10 km in the same time that B travels 9 km. The ratio of speeds of A and B is 10 : 9. Similarly, the ratio of speeds of B and C is 10 : 9.\nA : B = 10 : 9\nB : C = 10 : 9\n⇒ The ratio of speeds of A : B : C = 100 : 90 : 81\nIn the same time that A travels 100 m, C travels 81 metres ⇒ In the same time that A travels 10000 m, C would travel 8100 m or A would beat C by 1900 m.",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A train approaches a tunnel AB. Inside the tunnel is a cat located at a point that is 3/8 th of the distance AB measured from the entrance A. When the train whistles the cat runs. If the cat moves to the entrance of the tunnel, A, the train catches the cat exactly at the entrance. If the cat moves to the exit, B, the train catches the cat at exactly the exit. Ratio of the speed of train to speed of cat?",
    "choice_1": "3:1",
    "choice_2": "4:1",
    "choice_3": "5:1",
    "choice_4": "6:1",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Explanation:\nLet the length of the tunnel be x and distance of the train to entrance A be y. Let the speeds of train and cat be t and c respectively. \nHence, when the cat runs 3x/8, the train covers y.\n => (3x/8)/c\n => (3x/8)/c = y/t−−− (1) \nWhen the cat runs 5x/8 to the other end, the train covers x+y \n=>(5x/8)/c = (x+y)/t−−−(2) \nTaking ratio of (1) to (2) 3/5 = y/(x+y)\n=> 3x = 2y −−−(3) \nSubstituting (3) in (2y/8)/c = y/t \n  => t = 4c Hence the ratio t:c is 4:1....",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A and B run a 1 km race. If A gives B a start of 50m, A wins by 14 seconds, and if A gives B a start of 22 seconds, B wins by 20 m. Find the time taken by A to run 1 km.",
    "choice_1": "100 seconds",
    "choice_2": "98 seconds",
    "choice_3": "95 seconds",
    "choice_4": "90 seconds",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Let the speeds of A and B be a m/s and b m/s respectively. \nCase (I): A gives B a start of 50 m.\n A wins by 14 seconds. \nA runs 1000 m, while B runs only 950 m \nA reached 14 seconds before B. \nDistance travelled by B in 14 seconds = 14b \nHence, while A ran 1000m, \nB had completed only 950-14b m \na/b = 1000/(950-14b) \nCase (II): A gives B a start of 22 seconds. \nB wins by 20 meters.\n A started 22 seconds after B started. \nA was 20 meters behind(980 m) when B completed 1000 m.\n Distance covered by B in the first 22 seconds = 22b \nIf B had also started at the same time, B would have run (1000-22b) m\n a/b = 980/(1000-2b) \n1000/(950-14b) = 980/(1000-22b)\n Solving, b = 25/3 \na/(25/3) = 1000/[950-14*(25/3)] \na = 10 m/s \nTo run 1 km, \nA takes 100 seconds.",
    "Topic": "Problems on  Races"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If a product is bought for Rs. 500 and sold for rs. 600, what is the profit percentage?",
    "choice_1": "20%",
    "choice_2": "25%",
    "choice_3": "10%",
    "choice_4": "15%",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Profit = SP – CP\nProfit % = (Profit / CP) * 100\nProfit = (600 - 500) = 100;\n Profit % = (100/500) * 100 = 20%",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If the cost price of 12 apples is equal to the selling price of 10 apples, what is the profit percentage?",
    "choice_1": "16%",
    "choice_2": "20%",
    "choice_3": "25%",
    "choice_4": "30%",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "SP of 1 apple = Rs. 1\n\nSP of 10 apples  Rs. 10 = CP of 12 apples\n\nSp of 12 apples = Rs. 12 \n\nProfit % = [(12-10)/10] * 100 = 20%",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A shopkeeper has a loss of 10% on selling an article for Rs. 450,then find the selling price in order to get 15% profit.",
    "choice_1": "Rs. 550",
    "choice_2": "Rs. 500",
    "choice_3": "Rs 575",
    "choice_4": "Rs. 600",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Loss % = [(C.P - S.P)/C.P] x 100\n10 = [(C.P - 450)/C.P] x100\n 100 C.P - 45000 = 10 C.P\n 100 C.P - 10 C.P = 45000\n 90 C.P = 45000\n C.P = 4500/9\n C.P = Rs. 500\nS.P = [(100+ P%)/100] x C.P\n S.P = [(100 + 15)/100] x 500\n S.P = Rs. 575\n:. The selling price is Rs. 575.",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If an article is sold for Rs. 750 and a profit of 25% is earned, for how much should he sell it to gain 30%?",
    "choice_1": "Rs. 600",
    "choice_2": "Rs. 720",
    "choice_3": "Rs. 700",
    "choice_4": "Rs. 780",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "CP = (Initial SP) x 100/(100+P%)\nCP = 750 × 100/(100 +25)\nCP = Rs. 600\nAs he wants to sell the article at gain of 30%\nRequired SP = CP x (100 + P%)/100\nRequired SP = 600 x (100 + 30)/100 = 780\n He should sell the sweater at Rs. 780 to gain 30%",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Hari suffered a loss of 8% by selling an article. If he had sold it for Rs. 300 more, he would have made a profit of 4%. Find his CP (in Rs.)",
    "choice_1": 2250,
    "choice_2": 2400,
    "choice_3": 2575,
    "choice_4": 2500,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Let the Cost price be 100%\nLoss = (100-8)= 92%\n\nAgain, when there is a profit of 4%\n\nProfit = (100 + 4)= 104%\nDifference of an article = (104 - 92)= 12%\n 12% = 300\n100%=(300×100)/12\n         = Rs. 2500. \nThe required CP is Rs. 2500",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The cost prices of articles A and B are Rs. 1200 and Rs. 1600 respectively. The selling price of article A is Rs. 1380 and the total profit on selling both the articles is 25%. What is the profit percentage on the selling of article B?",
    "choice_1": 27.5,
    "choice_2": 32.5,
    "choice_3": 29.5,
    "choice_4": 35.5,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The cost price of articles A and B = 1200 + 1600 = Rs. 2800\nThe selling price of articles A and B = cost price x (100 + profit)% = 2800 x125%\nThe selling price of articles A and B = Rs. 3500\nThe selling price of articles A + the selling price of articles B = 3500\n1380 + the selling price of articles B = 3500\nThe selling price of articles B = Rs. 2120\n Profit % on article B = [(2120- 1600)/1600] x 100 = 520/16 = 32.5%\n The profit percentage on the selling of article B is 32.5%.",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man sells two articles for ₹990 each. On one, he gains 10% and on the other, he loses 10%. What is his overall gain or loss percentage?",
    "choice_1": "1% loss",
    "choice_2": "1% gain",
    "choice_3": "No profit, no loss",
    "choice_4": "2% loss",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "If gain% and loss% is same and SP of both articles is same then there occurs loss.\n\nLoss % = a^2 / 100\n            = 10^2 / 100 = 1%",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man sold an article at a loss of 10%. Had he sold it for ₹40 more, he would have gained 10%. What is the cost price of the article?",
    "choice_1": 180,
    "choice_2": 200,
    "choice_3": 220,
    "choice_4": 240,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Let the cost price be ₹x.\nLoss case: ( 10% loss )\u000bSelling Price = x – 10% of x= 0.9x\nProfit case: ( 10% profit )\u000bSelling Price = x + 10% of x= 1.1x\n\nGiven difference:1.1x – 0.9x = ₹40-- >0.2x = ₹40 --- > x = ₹200",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The difference between the selling price of a table when sold at profits of 6% and 8% is Rs.106. find the cost price of the table.",
    "choice_1": "5,618",
    "choice_2": "5,784",
    "choice_3": "6,100",
    "choice_4": 5300,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Let  CP be x\nSP = 100 +P%/100  *CP \nSP = 106x/100\nSP = 100+8%/100  *x\nSP =108x/100\n108x/100 -106x/100  =106\n2x=10600\nX=5300",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Mathi purchased a walkman from her friend. She then sold it for Rs.90.Had it been sold for Rs.105. The gain would have been 1/4 of the former loss. What is the cost price of the walkman?",
    "choice_1": 82,
    "choice_2": 102,
    "choice_3": 114,
    "choice_4": 126,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "P =1/4 L\nSP-CP =1/4(CP-SP)\n105-CP =1/4(CP-90)\n420-4CP=CP-90\n510 =5CP\nCP=102",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A women sold 15 bed sheets for Rs.15,000. Hence gaining 5 bedsheet‘s cost prices. The cost per sheet is",
    "choice_1": 960,
    "choice_2": 1000,
    "choice_3": 750,
    "choice_4": 800,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "15bedsheets  SP =15000\nP=SP-CP\n5CP =15000-15CP\n20CP=15000\nCP=750",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man sold a horse at a loss of 7 %. Had he been able to sell it at again of 9 %, it would have fetched Rs. 64 more than it did. What was the cost price ?",
    "choice_1": 600,
    "choice_2": 700,
    "choice_3": 400,
    "choice_4": 500,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "let  cp =x  \nsp =93x/100\nsp=109x/100\n109x/100 -93x/100  =64\n16x=6400\nX=400",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The salesman has the liberty to sell a hair dryer in his store at a price between Rs.300 and Rs.700.The profit earned by selling the hair dryer for Rs.650 is twice the loss incurred when it is sold for Rs.350.What is the cost price of hair dryer?",
    "choice_1": 450,
    "choice_2": 350,
    "choice_3": 550,
    "choice_4": 150,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "P = 2L\nSP-CP =2(CP-SP)\n650-CP =2(CP-350)\n650-CP =2CP -700\n1350 =3CP\nCP =450",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "My friend collects antique stamps. She purchased two, but found that she needed to raise money urgently. So she sold them for Rs. 8000 each. On one she made 20% and on the other she lost 20%. How much did she gain or lose in the entire transaction?",
    "choice_1": "lost Rs 500.67",
    "choice_2": "lost Rs 666.67",
    "choice_3": "gain Rs 666.67",
    "choice_4": "gain Rs 500.67",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "SP =8000+8000 =16000\nP%=20%  SP=8000\nCP =100/120  *8000\nCP =6666.667\nL%=20%   SP=8000\nCP = 100/80  *8000\nCP =10000\nCP =10000+6666.67\n     =16666.67\nL=CP-SP =16666.67-16000=666.67",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A showroom offers 10% discount on a microwave, whose marked price is Rs8000 and also gives a blender worth Rs1200 as a complimentary gift with it. Even then the showroom earns a profit of 20%.The cost price per microwave is.",
    "choice_1": 7200,
    "choice_2": 6000,
    "choice_3": 5000,
    "choice_4": 5500,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "8000 ---- > 10%  = 800\nSp = 7200 --- > Rs.1200  complimentary gift \nSP =7200-1200\nSP =6000\nSP =6000   P% =20%\nCP = 100/120  * 6000\nCP = 5000",
    "Topic": "Profit and Loss"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A shopkeeper buys an article for ₹720 and wants to make a profit of 25% after giving a discount of 10%. What should be the marked price?",
    "choice_1": "₹950",
    "choice_2": "₹1000",
    "choice_3": "₹1050",
    "choice_4": "₹1100",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Let MP = x\u000bSelling Price = x – 10% of x = 0.9x\u000bTo make 25% profit:\u000bSelling Price = 720 + 25% of 720 = 720 × 1.25 = ₹900\nSo,\u000b0.9x = 900 ⇒ x = 900 / 0.9 = ₹1000",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A product has a marked price of ₹800. Two successive discounts of 10% and 5% are given. What is the final selling price?",
    "choice_1": "₹684",
    "choice_2": "₹700",
    "choice_3": "₹720",
    "choice_4": "₹740",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "First discount = 10% of ₹800 = ₹80 ⇒ New Price = ₹800 - ₹80 = ₹720\u000bSecond discount = 5% of ₹720 = ₹36 ⇒ Final Price = ₹720 - ₹36 = ₹684",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A toy is marked at ₹500. A discount of 10% is given, but the shopkeeper still makes a profit of 20%. Find the cost price.",
    "choice_1": "₹375",
    "choice_2": "₹400",
    "choice_3": "₹450",
    "choice_4": "₹425",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Selling Price = Marked Price - Discount = ₹500 - 10% of 500 = ₹500 - ₹50 = ₹450\u000bLet the Cost Price be CP.\u000bProfit% = (SP - CP)/CP × 100 = 20%\nSo,\u000b(450 - CP)/CP × 100 = 20\u000b=> (450 - CP) = 0.2CP\u000b=> 450 = 1.2CP\u000b=> CP = 450 / 1.2 = ₹375",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A shopkeeper bought a shirt for ₹600 and sold it for ₹540. What is the loss percentage?",
    "choice_1": "5%",
    "choice_2": "10%",
    "choice_3": "8%",
    "choice_4": "12%",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Loss = Cost Price - Selling Price = ₹600 - ₹540 = ₹60\nLoss% = (Loss / Cost Price) × 100\u000b= (60 / 600) × 100 = 10%",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man buys a pen for ₹40 and sells it for ₹50. What is his profit percentage?",
    "choice_1": "20%",
    "choice_2": "25%",
    "choice_3": "30%",
    "choice_4": "35%",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Profit = Selling Price - Cost Price\u000b= ₹50 - ₹40 = ₹10\nProfit% = (Profit / Cost Price) × 100\u000b= (10 / 40) × 100 = 25%",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man sold an article at a loss of 10%. Had he sold it for ₹40 more, he would have gained 10%. What is the cost price of the article?",
    "choice_1": "₹180",
    "choice_2": "₹200",
    "choice_3": "₹220",
    "choice_4": "₹240",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Solution:\nLet the cost price be ₹x.\nLoss case: ( 10% loss )\u000bSelling Price = x – 10% of x= 0.9x\nProfit case: ( 10% profit )\u000bSelling Price = x + 10% of x= 1.1x\n\nGiven difference:\u000b1.1x – 0.9x = ₹40\u000b⇒ 0.2x = ₹40\u000b⇒ x = ₹200",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man sells two articles for ₹990 each. On one, he gains 10% and on the other, he loses 10%. What is his overall gain or loss percentage?",
    "choice_1": "1% loss",
    "choice_2": "1% gain",
    "choice_3": "No profit, no loss",
    "choice_4": "2% loss",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "NOTE: If gain% and loss% is same and SP of both articles is same then there occurs loss.\n\nLoss % = a^2 / 100\n            = 10^2 / 100 = 1% loss",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A shopkeeper allows two successive discounts of 20% and 10% on the marked price of ₹5,000. Find the selling price.",
    "choice_1": "₹3,400",
    "choice_2": "₹3,500",
    "choice_3": "₹3,600",
    "choice_4": "₹3,700",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Solution:\n20% decrease and 10% decrease\nSuccessive change in percentages= A+B+AB/100 = -20 – 10 + (20)(10)/100 = -30 + 2 = - 28\n5000 – 28% of 5000 = 3600.\n\nAnswer: c) ₹3600",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A trader offers a 25% discount on an article but still makes a 25% profit. If the marked price is ₹800, find the cost price.",
    "choice_1": "₹450",
    "choice_2": "₹480",
    "choice_3": "₹500",
    "choice_4": "₹520",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Selling Price = 75% of ₹800 = ₹600\u000bProfit = 25% ⇒ SP = 1.25 × CP\u000bSo, 600 = CP + 25% of CP ⇒ CP = ₹480",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A shopkeeper claims to sell sugar at cost price but uses a false weight of 950 grams instead of 1 kg. What is his profit percentage?",
    "choice_1": "4.76%",
    "choice_2": "5.26%",
    "choice_3": "5.56%",
    "choice_4": "6.25%",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "He gives 950g but charges for 1000g.\u000bSo, Profit = 50g\u000bProfit% = (50 / 950) × 100 = 5.26%",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The ratio of cost price to selling price of an article is 4:7, and the ratio of the marked price to selling price of the article is 36:35. If the markup price of the article is Rs 160, then find the profit (in Rs).",
    "choice_1": 180,
    "choice_2": 120,
    "choice_3": 140,
    "choice_4": 150,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Cp:Sp = 4:7;\nMP:SP = 36:35\nBalance CP and SP according to MP and Sp\nCP:SP = 20:35\n(Marked Price:\nAlso known as the list price, retail price, or sticker price. \nMarkup Price:\nThe difference between the cost price of a product and its selling price. \nIt's the amount added to the cost to cover expenses and generate profit.)\n36x - 20x= 160; x = 10.\nthen cp = 200, Sp = 350, profit = differen of SP and Cp = 150",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A shopkeeper made a loss of 15% on selling an article. Had he sold the article for Rs. 3000 more, he would have made a profit of 5%.  If he marked the article at 20% above the cost price, then find the discount given on the article (in Rs.)?",
    "choice_1": 5050,
    "choice_2": 5250,
    "choice_3": 5450,
    "choice_4": 4850,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "-15% to +5% = total 20%\n20% =3000, then 100% = 15000 = CP\nIf the article marked 20% above, 120% of 15000 = 18000\nSp of 15% loss = 12750.\nThe the discout given by the shop keeper is 18000 - 12750 = 5250",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Rohan, Mohan and Sohan decided to sell their TV, fridge and phone, respectively. The cost price of the TV was Rs. 12,775 and Rohan sold it for a profit of 12%. The cost price of the fridge was Rs. 51,100 and Mohan earned a profit of 14% by selling it. If the cost price of the phone is equal to the selling price of the TV and Sohan suffered a loss equal to half the amount of profit gained by Mohan, then what is the selling price of the phone?",
    "choice_1": "Rs. 11,337",
    "choice_2": "Rs. 10,213",
    "choice_3": "Rs. 10,731",
    "choice_4": "Rs. 9,877",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "CP (TV)= Rs 12775;\nSP = 112% OF 12775 = RS. 14308\nCP (FRIDGE)= Rs 51100;\nSP = 114% OF 51100 = RS. 58254\nCP(PHONE) = SP OF TV = 14308\nSohan suffered a loss equal to half the amount of profit gained by Mohan\nMOHAN’S PROFIT = 58254 – 51100 = 7154\nSohan suffered a loss equal to half the amount of profit gained by Mohan = 7154/2 = 3577\nSP OF PHONE = 14308 – 3577 = 10731",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Rahul bought a watch which has Rs. 1,875 as a marked price at a 24% discount. Rahul sold the watch to Rohit earning a 28% profit. Rohit then decided to sell the watch and set the marked price at 25% higher than the cost price at which he bought the watch. Mohit bought the watch from Rohit at a 15% discount on the marked price. Mohit marked up the price to 50% higher than the cost price at which he bought the watch and sold it to Rahul at some discount. If Rahul had to pay Rs. 28.5 extra than the initial price he paid, then at what percent discount did Mohit sell the watch?",
    "choice_1": "40%",
    "choice_2": "45%",
    "choice_3": "50%",
    "choice_4": "65%",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Rahul cp = 76% of 1875 = 1425\nRahul sp = 128% of 1425 = 1824\nRohit cp = 1824\nRohit mrp = 125% of 1824 = 2280\nMohit cp = 85% of 2280 = 1938\nMohit mrp = 150% of 1938 = 2907\nRahul paid = 1425 + 28.5 = 1453.5\nDiscount given by mohit = 2907 of x % = 1453.5\n                Disc = 50%",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A shopkeeper marked up of article A at 60% above its cost price and sold it at the discount of 25%. Profit made by shopkeeper on article A is Rs.475. If the cost price of article B is 40% more than that of article A and profit on both articles is same, then find the selling price of article B?",
    "choice_1": "Rs. 3800",
    "choice_2": "Rs. 3990",
    "choice_3": "Rs. 3860",
    "choice_4": "Rs. 3960",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "CP of A = 100;\nA at 60% above its cost price (CP = 160) and sold it at the discount of 25%.\n75%of 160 = 120 = SP. Here 20% = 475, then 100% = Rs. 2375 (Original CP).\nArticle B is 40% more than A = Rs. 3325.. profit are same therefore Rs. 475 profit on both cases, therefore 3325 + 475 = 3800",
    "Topic": "PROFIT AND LOSS, DISCOUNT"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A and B started a business by investing ₹5000 and ₹3000 respectively. After 3 months, A increased his investment by ₹500. After 6 more months, B increased his investment by ₹y. If the ratio of the profits of A to B at the end of the year is 43:40, then find the value of 5y.",
    "choice_1": "30k",
    "choice_2": "40k",
    "choice_3": "33k",
    "choice_4": "44k",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Calculations: A's investment: ₹5000 for 3 months = 5000 × 3 = 15000 ₹5500 for 9 months = 5500 × 9 = 49500 Total = 64500 B's investment: ₹3000 for 9 months = 3000 × 9 = 27000 ₹(3000 + y) for 3 months = (3000 + y) × 3 = 9000 + 3y Total = 27000 + 9000 + 3y = 36000 + 3y Profit ratio: 64500 : (36000 + 3y) = 43 : 40 ⇒ 21500 : (12000 + y) = 43 : 40 ⇒ 21500 / (12000 + y) = 43 / 40 ⇒ 40 × 21500 = 43 × (12000 + y) ⇒ 860000 = 516000 + 43y ⇒ 344000 = 43y ⇒ y = 8000 ⇒ 5y = 5 × 8000 = 40000 ∴ The value of 5y is ₹40,000",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B, and C started a business by investing Rs. 4000, Rs. 6000, and Rs. 5000 respectively. Their investment periods are n months, (n+2) months, and 10 months respectively. If the profit share of A is Rs. 1600 and the total profit is Rs. 6480, find the investment period of B.",
    "choice_1": "12 months",
    "choice_2": "14 months",
    "choice_3": "2 months",
    "choice_4": "11 months",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Investments: A: ₹4000 for n months B: ₹6000 for n + 2 months C: ₹5000 for 10 months A's profit = ₹1600 Total profit = ₹6480 So, B and C together share ₹6480 – ₹1600 = ₹4880 Profits are divided in the ratio of: Investment × Time Let’s write the profit ratios: A's share ∝ 4000 × n = 4000n B's share ∝ 6000 × (n + 2) C's share ∝ 5000 × 10 = 50000 So, total profit ratio: A : B : C = 4000n : 6000(n + 2) : 50000 Let’s assume this ratio is proportional to their actual profit shares: A’s share = ₹1600 Total = ₹6480 So, let's convert the ratios to actual values: Let’s write the ratios in terms of A’s share = ₹1600 Let: 4000n = A's share → corresponds to ₹1600 Then 1 unit = ₹1600 / 4000n = ₹2/5n Now find the other shares in terms of ₹: B’s share = 6000(n+2) × (2 / 5n) C’s share = 50000 × 2 / 5n And total of B and C = ₹4880 So: 6000(n+2) × (2/5n) + 50000 × (2/5n) = 4880 Take LHS: (2/5n) [6000 (n+2) + 50000] = 4880 First compute inside the bracket: 6000 (n+2) = 6000n + 12000 ⇒ 6000n + 12000 + 50000 = 6000n + 62000 Now: (2/5n) 6000n + 62000 = 4880 Multiply both sides by 5n: 2 (6000n + 62000) = 4880 × 5n ⇒ 12000n + 124000 = 24400n 124000 = 24400n − 12000n = 12400n ⇒ n = 124000 / 12400 = 10 B invested for n + 2 = 10 + 2 = 12 months Thus, the correct answer is 12 months.",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A invests Rs. 50,000. B joins after 3 months with Rs. 40,000 and C joins after 6 months with Rs. 60,000. Find the ratio of their profits at the end of the year",
    "choice_1": "5:3:2",
    "choice_2": "2:2:4",
    "choice_3": "2:2:2",
    "choice_4": "5:2:2",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Answer:\nA = 50 × 12 = 600\nB = 40 × 9 = 360\nC = 60 × 6 = 360\nRatio = 600:360:360 = 5:3:3",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A and B start a business. After 4 months, C joins with an amount equal to A's investment. At the end of the year, C gets Rs. 3,000 as profit. What was the total profit?",
    "choice_1": "9k",
    "choice_2": "6k",
    "choice_3": "11k",
    "choice_4": "12k",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Let A invest Rs. x, B also x, C = x (after 4 months).\nC’s capital × time = x × 8 = 8x\nA = x × 12 = 12x\nB = x × 12 = 12x\nTotal = 12x + 12x + 8x = 32x\nC’s share = 8x/32x = 1/4\nIf 1/4 = 3000 → Total profit = Rs. 12,000",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B, and C invest in the ratio 3:4:5. After 4 months, A withdraws half his capital, B doubles his, and C keeps it unchanged. Find the new ratio of profits after a year.",
    "choice_1": "1:23:15",
    "choice_2": "6:31:51",
    "choice_3": "6:20:11",
    "choice_4": "6:20:15",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "A: 3 for 4 months, then 1.5 for 8 months = 3×4 + 1.5×8 = 12 + 12 = 24\nB: 4 for 4 months, 8 for 8 months = 16 + 64 = 80\nC: 5 for 12 months = 60\nRatio = 24:80:60 → Simplified: 3:10:7.5 = 6:20:15",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B, and C invest in a business. A invests Rs. 10,000, B invests Rs. 15,000 after 3 months, and C invests Rs. 20,000 after 6 months. If the business runs for 1 year, what is the profit ratio?",
    "choice_1": "8:09:08",
    "choice_2": "1:03:01",
    "choice_3": "2:01:02",
    "choice_4": "7:02:02",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "A = 10×12 = 120\nB = 15×9 = 135\nC = 20×6 = 120\nRatio = 120:135:120 = 8:9:8",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A started a business with Rs. 12,000. After 4 months, B joins with Rs. 16,000. Find their profit-sharing ratio at the end of the year.",
    "choice_1": "10:3",
    "choice_2": "1:5",
    "choice_3": "3:2",
    "choice_4": "9:8",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Answer:\nA = 12,000 × 12 = 1,44,000\nB = 16,000 × 8 = 1,28,000\nRatio = 144000:128000 = 9:8",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A started a business with Rs. 20,000. After 6 months, B joined with Rs. 40,000. At the end of the year, what is the ratio of A and B’s profit?",
    "choice_1": "3:2",
    "choice_2": "2:1",
    "choice_3": "1:1",
    "choice_4": "1:5",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Answer:\nA = 20,000 × 12 = 2,40,000\nB = 40,000 × 6 = 2,40,000\nRatio = 1:1",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A and B entered into a partnership by investing Rs. x and Rs. (x + 5000) respectively. At the end of the year, the ratio of profit share of A to B is 7: 9. Find the value of 7x?",
    "choice_1": "none of the above",
    "choice_2": 140000,
    "choice_3": 10000,
    "choice_4": 122500,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Cross multiplying: 9x = 7(x + 5000) 9x = 7x + 35000 9x - 7x = 35000 2x = 35000 x = 35000 / 2 = 17500 Now, find the value of 7x: 7x = 7 × 17500 = 122500 ∴ The value of 7x is Rs. 122500.",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In a partnership business A contributes Rs. 1,200 for 5 months and B Rs. 750 for 4 months. If there is a profit of Rs. 450, then ratio of the profit of A and B is",
    "choice_1": "4:1",
    "choice_2": "1:1",
    "choice_3": "2:1",
    "choice_4": "2:3",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "A's share = ₹1,200 × 5 = ₹6,000 B's share = ₹750 × 4 = ₹3,000 Ratio of profits = A's share : B's share ⇒ Ratio = ₹6,000 : ₹3,000 ⇒ Ratio = 6 : 3 = 2 : 1 ∴ The correct answer is option 3.",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A sum of 12540 is divided among A, B and C in such a way that the ratio between the share of A and that of B and C together is 3 : 7 and that of B and that of A and C together is in the ratio 2 : 9. What is the share of C?",
    "choice_1": 6498,
    "choice_2": 7000,
    "choice_3": 4533,
    "choice_4": 3402,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Share of C = 12540 - (3762 + 2280) = 6498",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Peter started a retail business by investing Rs. 25000. After eight months Sam joined him with a capital of Rs. 30,000. After 2 years they earned a profit of Rs. 18000. What was the share of Peter in the profit?",
    "choice_1": "29k",
    "choice_2": "13k",
    "choice_3": "22k",
    "choice_4": "10k",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "The time period of Peter = 24 months The time period of Sam = 16 months Now, 25000 × 24 : 30000 × 16 = 5 : 4 ∴ Peter’s share = (5/9) × 18000 = Rs. 10,000",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Three friends A, B, C invested in a business in the ratio of 3 ∶ 2 ∶ 6. After 6 months C withdraw half his capital. If the total profit earned for the year is Rs.53010 (in Rs.).Then Profit made by A is",
    "choice_1": 16740,
    "choice_2": 12030,
    "choice_3": 23112,
    "choice_4": 23132,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "12x3 : 12x2 : 6(6+3) 6/19 x 53010=16740",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Three partners X, Y and Z started their business by investing ₹40,000, ₹38,000 and ₹30,000, respectively. After 6 months, X and Z made additional investments of ₹20,000 and ₹15,000 respectively, whereas Y withdrew ₹8,000. Find the share of Y (in ₹) in the total profit of ₹38,880 made at the end of the year.",
    "choice_1": 11200,
    "choice_2": 10000,
    "choice_3": 12110,
    "choice_4": 10880,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "The share of Y (in ₹) in the total profit of ₹38,880 made at the end of the year is 10880.",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A and B entered into a partnership with certain investments. At the end of 8 months, A withdrew and collected back his money. A and B received profit in the ratio 5 ∶ 9 at the end of the year. If B had invested Rs. 36,000, then how much (in Rs.) had A invested?",
    "choice_1": "30k",
    "choice_2": "20k",
    "choice_3": "33k",
    "choice_4": "22k",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Total profit = Investment × time",
    "Topic": "partnerships"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The average temperature of Delhi in the first four days of June 2017 was 52 degrees. The average for the second, third, fourth, and fifth days was 55 degrees. If the temperatures of the first and fifth days were in the ratio 5:7, then what was the temperature of Delhi on 5th June 2017?",
    "choice_1": "36 degrees",
    "choice_2": "30 degrees",
    "choice_3": "48 degrees",
    "choice_4": "42 degrees",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Sum of temperature on 1st, 2nd, 3rd, and 4th days = (52 x 4) = 208-\n--- (I)\n\nSum of temperature on 2nd, 3rd, 4th, and 5th days = (55 x 4) = 220-\n-- (II)\n\nSubtracting equation (I) from (II)\n\nTemperature on 5th June 2017 - temperature on 1st June 2017 = 12\ndegrees.\n\nLet the temperature on 1st and 5th June 2017 be 5x and 7x degrees\nrespectively.\n\nThen, 7x - 5x = 12\n2x = 12\nX=6\n\nSince temperature on the 5th June 2017 in Delhi = 7x = 7 x 6 = 42\ndegrees.",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The average weekly salary per head of all employees\n(supervisors and labourers) is Rs. 100. The average weekly\nsalary per head of all the supervisors is Rs. 600 while the\naverage weekly salary per head of all the labourers is Rs. 75.\nFind the number of supervisors in the factory if there are 840\nlabourers in it.",
    "choice_1": 46,
    "choice_2": 42,
    "choice_3": 44,
    "choice_4": 48,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "using Allegation method\n\nAverage salary of Labourers(Rs.75)\nAverage salary  of Supervisors(Rs.600)\nMean(Rs.100)\n\nQuantity of Cheaper/Quantity of Dearer = CP of Dearer - Mean Price/Mean Price - CP of Cheaper\n= 600 - 100 / 100 - 75 = 500 / 25 \nThe required ratio is 500:25 or 20:1\nNo of Labourers/No of Supervisors = 20/1\n840/No of supervisors = 20/1\nHence no of supervisors = 42",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The average score (runs/match) of Dravid before the start of\nWorld Cup was 35. In the world cup of 6 matches, his total\nscore was 355 runs. Find the total number of matches played\nby him till date, if his new average after the series is 37.5.",
    "choice_1": 55,
    "choice_2": 56,
    "choice_3": 52,
    "choice_4": 58,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Let the total number of matches Dravid has played, till the start of\nWorld Cup be X\n\nSo, the total runs scored by Dravid till the beginning of the World Cup are\n35 x X\n\nAfter the World Cup, the new average will be\n35*X+355/X+6\nAccording to the question,\n35*X+355/X+6 = 37.5\n=>37.5*X+225 = 35xX+355\n=2.5*x=130\nX=52\nHence, the total number of matches played by Dravid till date =\n52 + 6 = 58",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In a school, there are five friends- A, B, C, D and E. The weight of A is equal to the average weight of B, C and D and the weight of B is equal to the average weight of A, C and D. The average weight of A and C is equal to the average weight of C and D. E is 30 kg heavier than C and the average weight of B and D is 60 kg. What is the average weight (in kgs) of A, B, C,\nD and E?",
    "choice_1": 52.5,
    "choice_2": 56,
    "choice_3": 58.4,
    "choice_4": 66,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Let the weights of four friends A, B, C, D, and E be a, b, c, d, and e kgs\nrespectively\n\nFrom the question,\n3a = b + c + d\n3b = a + c + d\nSubtracting equations (i) and (ii)\n3a - 3b = b - a -- (ii)\nb = a ---- (iii)\nAdding equations (i) and (ii)\n3a + 3b = a + b + 2c + 2d\na + b = c + d ---- (iv)\nThe average weight of A and C is equal to the average weight of C and D\nIt means, a + c = c + d\na = d\nPut a = d in equation (iv)\nWe get b = c\nIt means, b = a = c = d\nThe average weight of B and D is 60 kg\nb + d = 60 x 2 = 120 kgs\nSo, b = d = 60 kgs = a = c\nE is 30 kg heavier than C\ne = (60 + 30) kgs\nBy solving, e = 90 kg\nThe sum of the weights of A, B, C, D, and E = 60 + 60 + 60 + 60 + 90 =\n330 kgs\nThe average = 330/5 = 66 kgs",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "There are five consecutive even numbers. Each number is multiplied by 2 and then 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5 is added to first, second, third, fourth and fifth number respectively. The new average of the five numbers is 125% more than the original average. What is the difference between the highest and lowest original number?",
    "choice_1": 12,
    "choice_2": 6,
    "choice_3": 10,
    "choice_4": 8,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Let the original average of the five numbers = x\nEach number is multiplied by 2, so average = 2x\nAnd then 1 + 2 + 3 + 4 + 5 = 15 is added to the total sum\nSo, the new average = 2x + 15/5 = 2x + 3\n2x + 3/x = 225/100 = 9/4\nx = 12\nSo, the original numbers are 8, 10, 12, 14, 16\nRequired difference = 16 - 8 = 8\nHence, option D is correct.",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The average weight of five friends P, Q, R, S, and T is (x + 6)kg while the average weight of R and T is (x - 6) kg. If the weight of another person U is also added, then average weight of all of them is reduced by 5 kg. Find the value of 'x' if average weight of P, Q, S and U is 94.5 kg.",
    "choice_1": 74,
    "choice_2": 80,
    "choice_3": 84,
    "choice_4": 90,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Total weight of friends P, Q, R, S and T = (x + 6) x 5 = 5 (x + 6) kg\n\nSo, total weight of P, Q and S = 5 (x + 6) - 2 (x - 6) = (3x + 42) = 3 (x +\n14)\n\nWeight of U =(x+6-5)x6-5 (x +6) = 6(x +1) - 5 (x + 6) = (x -24)\nkg\n\nAccording to the question,\n\n[3(x+14)+(x-24)]=94.5×4\n\n4x + 18 = 378\n\n4x = 360; x = 90\n\nHence, option D is correct.",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A, B, C, D and E are five persons. The weight of A, B and C is 90%, 112% and 94% respectively of the average weight of all five. The ratio of weight of D and E is 6 : 11. The difference between the weight of D and E is 75kg. What is the average weight of al the five persons?",
    "choice_1": "84 kg",
    "choice_2": "90 kg",
    "choice_3": "76 kg",
    "choice_4": "None of these",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Let the average weight of all five = 100k\n\nSo, weight of A = 90k, B = 112k and C = 94k\n\nLet the weight of D = d and that of E = e\n90k + 112k + 94k + d + e\n= 100k\nd + e = 204k\nd: e = 6:11 - d = 6/17x 204 = 72k -e = 132k\nDifference = 132k - 72k = 60k\n60k = 75\nSo, k = 75/60= 1.25\n\nAverage weight of all the five persons = 100 x 1.25 = 125kgNew average =\n\n595-175\n12\n\nTotal marks obtained by 17 girls = 35 x 17 = 595\n\nLet the marks obtained by 17 girls be(in ascending order):\n\n(a-8d) , (a-7d) , (a-6d) , (a-5d) , (a-4d) , (a-3d) , (a-2d) , (a-d),\n(a) (a +d), (a+2d), (a+3d), (a+4d), (a+5d), (a+6d), (a +7d), (a\n+ 8d)\n\nA = 35\n\nSum of 2nd, 6th, 9th, 12th and 16th term = 5a =175\n\nNew average = 595-175/12 = 420/12 = 35\n\nHence, option B is correct.\n\nLet the average weight of all five = 100k\nSo, weight of A = 90k, B = 112k and C = 94k\nLet the weight of D = d and that of E = e\n90k + 112k + 94k + d + e/5 = 100k\nd + e = 204k\nd:e = 6:11\nd =6/17*204 = 72k \ne=132k\nDifference = 132k - 72k = 60k\n60k = 75\nSo, k = - = 1.25\nAverage weight of all the five persons = 100 x 1.25 = 125kg",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Average marks of group of students is 48. Out of these, 3 students with marks 43, 68 and 51 are removed and a new student with a score of 84 is added to the list. If the number of students in the group was 8, then find the percentage increase in the average marks with respect to the initial\naverage?",
    "choice_1": "6.25%",
    "choice_2": "5.75%",
    "choice_3": "8.25%",
    "choice_4": "6.75%",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Let the sum of the marks of the unchanged 5 students from the initial tally\nbe equal to 'x', such that,\nx+43+68+51/8 = 48 (Given)\nThen,\nx = 384-(43 + 68 + 51) = 384 - 162 = 222\nBy adding of the new student's marks,\nSum of marks of 6 students becomes = x + 84 = 222 + 84 = 306\nNew Average = 306/6= 51\nPercentage increase in average = 51-48/48× 100\n300/48 = 100/16 = 6.25%",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "N' is the number employees in a Bengaluru based IT\ncompany. The average age of employees working in the company is 35 years. What will be the average age of these employees in next two years when 10 employees will retire. Given that, retirement age is 60 years and N = 40.",
    "choice_1": "87/13",
    "choice_2": "83/7",
    "choice_3": "86/13",
    "choice_4": "None of these",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Total employees in the company = 40\n\nAverage age of employees = 35\n\nTotal age of employees = (40 × 35) =1400\n\nIn next two years,\n\nTotal remaining employees = 40 - 10 = 30\n\nRetirement age = 60 years\n\nTotal age of 30 employees after 2 years = 1400 + (40 ×2) - (60×10)\n\n= 1400 + 80 - 600 = 880\nAverage age after two years = 880/30 = 88/3years\nHence, option E is correct.",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In Champions league, Rohit scored an average of 120 runs per match in the first 3 match and an average of 140 runs per match in the last four match. What is Rohit's average runs for the first match and the last two match if his average runs per match for all the five match is 122 and total number of\nmatches are 5?",
    "choice_1": 100,
    "choice_2": 200,
    "choice_3": 150,
    "choice_4": 50,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Rohit's average score in the first 3 exams = 120\n\nLet the scores in the 5 exams be denoted by M1, M2, M3, M4, and M5\n\nM1 + M2 + M3 = 120 x 3 = 360 ....... (i)\n\nAverage of last 4 matches = 140\n\nM2+M3+M4+M5/4\n\n= 140\n\nM2 + M3 + M4 + M5 = 560 .....(ii)\n\nThe average of all the exams\n\nM1+ M2+ M3 + M4+ M5/5 = 122\n\nM1+ M2 + M3 + M4 + M5 = 122 x 5 = 610\n\nFrom solving above equation, we get M1 + M4 + M5 = 300\n\nRequired average runs = 300/3 = 100",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The students of a class are divided into 3 groups depending on their performance in a test - the top, middle and bottom. The top group consists of 45% of the students, the middle group consists of 30% of the students and the rest are in the bottom group. The average marks of the bottom group are 20, those of the middle are 25 while the average marks for the entire class are 26. Find the average marks of the top group.",
    "choice_1": 7,
    "choice_2": 12,
    "choice_3": 22,
    "choice_4": 30,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Number of student,\nTop = 45,Average = p\nMiddle = 30,Average = 25\nBottom = 25,Average = 20\nTotal no of students = 100\nTotal average = 26\n\nLet the total number of students in the class = 100. The data given in\nThe question is shown in the table.\n\nLet the average of top group be P\n\n(45 × P) + (30 × 25) + (20×25)=(100×26)\n\n=> P=30",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The average height of girls in a class is 5 ft and that of boys is 5.7 ft. If the average height of the students in class is 5.5 ft what could be the possible strength of boys and girls respectively in the class:",
    "choice_1": "30,20",
    "choice_2": "20,30",
    "choice_3": "50,20",
    "choice_4": "60,50",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Let the number of boys be B and\n\nThe number of girls in the class\n\nso total strength of class = B + G\n\nIf the average height of boys in the class is 5.7 ft, then the total height of the boys\nIn class will be 5.7B\n\nsimilarly, if the average height of girls in class is 5 ft, then the total height of girls in class will be 5G\n\nALSO, given the average height of all students in the class is 5.5ft, then\n\n7.5B + 5G/B + G = 5.5\n5.7B + 5G= 5.5B + 5.5G\n0.2B = 0.5G or 2B = 5G ... a)\n\nNow we have to choose B and G such that .... a) gets equal\nThe value of option 3rd is B = 50 and G = 20 satisfy",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A man purchases milk for three consecutive years. In the first year, he purchases milk at the rate of ₹ 7.50 per litre, in the\nsecond year, at the rate of ₹ 8.00 per litre and in the third year, at ₹ 8.50 per litre. If he purchases milk worth ₹ 4,080 each\nyear, the average price of milk per litre for the three years is",
    "choice_1": "₹ 7.68",
    "choice_2": "₹ 7.98",
    "choice_3": "₹ 7.54",
    "choice_4": "₹ 7.83",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Price of milk in the first year = ₹ 7.50 per litre.\nQuantity of milk in first year = 4080/7.50 = 544 litres\n\nPrice of milk in the second year = ₹ 8.00 per litre.\nQuantity of milk in second year = 4080/8.00 = 510 litres\n\nPrice of milk in the third year = ₹ 8.50 per litre.\nQuantity of milk in third year = 4080/8.50 = 480 litres\n\n:. Required average = 3 x 4080/544 + 510 + 480 = 12240/1534 = ₹ 7.98\n\nHence, option B is correct.",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The average of the three numbers x, y and z is 45. x is greater than the average of y and z by 9. The average of y and z is greater than y by 2. Then the difference of x and z is",
    "choice_1": 3,
    "choice_2": 5,
    "choice_3": 7,
    "choice_4": 11,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Average of x, y and z = 45\n\n:. x + y + Z = 45 x 3 = 135 ... (i)\n\nAccording to the question,\n\nx = y+ z/2 + 9\n2x-y - z = 18 ... (ii)\n\nAgain, according to the question,\n\ny + Z/2 = y + 2\n= z-y = 4 ... (iii)\n\nBy equations (i) and (ii),\n\n3x = 153 => x = 51\n\nBy equation (i) and (iii),\n\nx + 2z= 139\n\n= 51 + 2z = 139\n\n2z = 139-51 = 88 => z = 44\n\nNow, difference of x and z = x-z => 51-44 = 7\n\nHence, option C is correct.",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The average expenditure of a worker for 6 months was Rs. 95\nand he fell into debt. In the next 4 months by reducing his\nmonthly expenses to Rs. 70 he not only cleared off his debt\nbut also saved Rs. 50. His monthly income is",
    "choice_1": "Rs. 85",
    "choice_2": "Rs. 95",
    "choice_3": "Rs. 88",
    "choice_4": "Rs. 90",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "We know,\n\nAverage of quantities = sum of all quantities / no. of quantities\n\nThe average expenditure of a worker for 6 months was Rs. 95.\n\nSo, the total expenditure of the worker for 6 months = Rs. 95 x 6 = Rs.\n570\n\nIn the next 4 months by reducing his monthly expenses to Rs. 70 he not\nonly cleared off his debt but also saved Rs. 50. So, total expenditure in\nthese 4 months = Rs. 70x4 = Rs. 280\n\nWe know,\nTotal income - total expenditure = total savings\n\n= Total income = total expenditure + total savings\n\n= Total income = (570 + 280) + 50 = 900\n\nSo, the total income in 10 months = Rs. 900\n\n:. His monthly income = Rs. (900 / 10) = Rs. 90",
    "Topic": "AVERAGES ,WEIGHTED AVERAGE"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the LCM of 5/2, 8/9, 11/14.",
    "choice_1": 280,
    "choice_2": 360,
    "choice_3": 440,
    "choice_4": 540,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "LCM of 5/2, 8/9 and 11/14 would be given by: (LCM\n of numerators)/(HCF of denominators)\n = 440/1 = 440",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the HCF and LCM of the polynomials (x^2 – 5x+ 6) and (x^2 – 7x + 10).",
    "choice_1": "(x - 2), (x – 2) (x – 3) (x – 5)^2",
    "choice_2": "(x – 3), (x – 2) (x – 3) (x – 5)",
    "choice_3": "(x – 2), (x – 2)(x – 3)",
    "choice_4": "(x - 2), (x – 2) (x – 3) (x – 5)",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "(x^2 – 5x + 6) = (x – 2)(x – 3)\n & (x^2 – 7x + 10) = (x – 5)(x – 2)\n Required HCF = (x – 2); required LCM = (x – 2)\n (x – 3)(x – 5).",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The sides of a pentagonal field (not regular) are 1737\n metres, 2160 metres, 2358 metres, 1422 metres and\n 2214 metres respectively. Find the greatest length of\n the tape by which the five sides may be measured completely.",
    "choice_1": 9,
    "choice_2": 8,
    "choice_3": 6,
    "choice_4": 7,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The sides of the pentagon being 1422, 1737, 2160,\n 2214 and 2358, the least difference between any two\n numbers is 54. Hence, the correct answer will be a\n factor of 54.\n Further, since there are some odd numbers in the\n list, the answer should be an odd factor of 54.\n Hence, check with 27, 9 and 3 in that order. You\n will get 9 as the HCF.",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "There are 576 boys and 448 girls in a school that are to be divided into equal sections of either boys or girls alone. Find the minimum total number of sections thus formed.",
    "choice_1": 13,
    "choice_2": 16,
    "choice_3": 22,
    "choice_4": 28,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The HCF of 576 and 448 is 64. Hence, each section\n should have 64 children. The number of sections\n would be given by: 576/64 + 448/64= 9 + 7 = 16.",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The G.C.D of 1.08, 0.36, 0.9 is",
    "choice_1": 0.36,
    "choice_2": 0.18,
    "choice_3": 0.09,
    "choice_4": 0.03,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "HCF of 108, 36, 90 is 18. then G.C.D is 0.18",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the pairs of natural numbers whose greatest common divisor is 5 and the least common multiple is 105.",
    "choice_1": "5 and 105 or 15 and 35",
    "choice_2": "6 and 105 or 16 and 35",
    "choice_3": "5 and 15 or 15 and 135",
    "choice_4": "5 and 20 or 15 and 35",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "the LCM of 5 and 105 is\n 105 and their HCF is 5. Also for the pair of values,\n 15 and 35 the HCF is 5 and the LCM is 105.",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Amitabh has a certain number of toffees, such that if he distributes them amongst ten children he has nine left, if he distributes amongst 9 children he would have 8 left, if he distributes amongst 8 children he would have 7 left … and so on until if he distributes amongst 5 children he should have 4 left. What is the second lowest number of toffees he could have with him?",
    "choice_1": 5039,
    "choice_2": 7559,
    "choice_3": 8249,
    "choice_4": 2519,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The least number would be (LCM of 10, 9, 8, 7, 6\n and 5 – 1) = 2519. The second least number = 2520 ¥\n 2 –1 = 5039.",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What will be the sum of all natural numbers between 101 and 1000 which on division by 2, 4, 6, 8, 10 leave remainders 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, respectively?",
    "choice_1": 4358,
    "choice_2": 4312,
    "choice_3": 5478,
    "choice_4": 5682,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Difference between the divisor and the remainder is\n 1 in each division. [2 −1 = 4 − 3 = 6 − 5 = 8 − 7\n = 10 − 9 = 1]\n So the general form of the number will be LCM of\n [2, 4, 6, 8, 10] – 1 = 120k − 1 where ‘k’ is a natural\n number.\n There are 8 such numbers between 101 to 1000: 119,\n 239, 359, 479, 599, 719, 839, 959.\n So the required sum = 119 + 239 + 359 + 479 + 599\n + 719 + 839 + 959 = 4312.",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If LCM of 'a' and 'b' is 'a' and LCM of 'b’ and 'c' is b, then what is the LCM of 'c' and a?",
    "choice_1": "a",
    "choice_2": "b",
    "choice_3": "c",
    "choice_4": "abc",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "LCM of a and b is 'a' means , a will be the bigger number (ex. LCM of 2 ans 4 is 4.) Then LCM of b and c is b means 'bi is a bibber numbe. If LCM of c and a should be 'a' because, a >b, b>c, then the LCM of third pair of numbers c and a will be 'a'.",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the least number that when divided by 16, 18 and 20 leaves a remainder 4 in each case, but is completely divisible by 7.",
    "choice_1": 364,
    "choice_2": 2884,
    "choice_3": 2254,
    "choice_4": 2964,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The LCM of 16, 18 and 20 is 720. The numbers\n which would give a remainder of 4, when divided\n by 16, 18 and 20 would be given by the series:\n 724, 1444, 2164, 2884 and so on. Checking each of these\n numbers for divisibility by 7, it can be seen that 2884 is\n the least number in the series that is divisible by 7",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Three wheels can complete 40, 24 and 16 revolutions per minute respectively. There is a red spot on each wheel that touches the ground at time 0. After how much time, all these spots will simultaneously touch the ground again?",
    "choice_1": "9(3/2)",
    "choice_2": "11(1/2)",
    "choice_3": "7(1/2)",
    "choice_4": "9(1/2)",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "For one revolution, the first, second and third wheels take 60/40, 60/24, 60/16 seconds i.e., 3/2, 5/2, 15/4 seconds respectively. \n Time taken for all red spots to touch the ground again simultaneously = 3/2, 5/2, 15/4 = (LCM of 3,5,15)/(HCF of 2,2,4) = 15/2 sec = 7(1/2) sec.",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If x is a number of five-digits which when divided by\n 8, 12, 15 and 20 leaves respectively 5, 9, 12 and 17\n as remainders, then find x such that it is the lowest\n such number.",
    "choice_1": 10017,
    "choice_2": 10097,
    "choice_3": 10057,
    "choice_4": 10077,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Since the LCM of 20,15,12 and 8 is 120 we need\n the smallest 120n - 3 number in 5 digits. 120 × 84\n = 10080. Thus, the required number is 10080 - 3 =\n 10077",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find gcd (2^100) – 1, (2^120) – 1).",
    "choice_1": "(2^10)– 1",
    "choice_2": "(2^20)– 1",
    "choice_3": "(2^60)– 1",
    "choice_4": "(2^40)– 1",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The GCD of A^x – 1 & A^y − 1 is given by A^(GCD of x,y)\n − 1. Hence, the required answer would be 2^20 − 1",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the gcd (111…11 hundred ones ; 11…11 sixty\n ones).",
    "choice_1": "111…forty ones",
    "choice_2": "111…twenty five ones",
    "choice_3": "111…sixty ones",
    "choice_4": "111…twenty ones",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "The required GCD would be 1111…111 twenty ones.",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the GCD of the numbers 2n + 13 and n + 7.",
    "choice_1": 1,
    "choice_2": 2,
    "choice_3": 3,
    "choice_4": 4,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "You can experimentally verify that for all values\n of n, the required GCD would be 1 as the numbers\n would be co-prime to each other.",
    "Topic": "NUMBER SYSTEM 1\n Lcm,HCF Divisibility rule"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The sum of two integers is 10 and the sum of their reciprocals is 5/12. Then the ratio of the larger number and the smaller number is",
    "choice_1": "3 : 2",
    "choice_2": "1 : 3",
    "choice_3": "2 : 1",
    "choice_4": "2 : 3",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "x+y = 10\n 1/x + 1/y = 5/12\n (x + y)/xy = 5/12, \n 10 /xy = 5/12\n Make numerator 10 on RHS and xy becomes 24. Then possible values ox x and y to get value 10 is 6 and 4 only.\n Then the ratio is 6 : 4 = 3 : 2",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Let K be a positive integer such that k + 4 is divisible by 7. Then the smallest positive integer n, greater than 2, such that k + 2n is divisible by 7 equals.",
    "choice_1": 9,
    "choice_2": 7,
    "choice_3": 5,
    "choice_4": 3,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Let k = 7n+3, then k + 2n becomes 7n+3+2n. Among the options, if n=3, \n 7n+3+2n = 30, it is not divisible by 7. \n if n=5, \n 7n+3+2n = 48, it is not divisible by 7.\n if n=7, \n 7n+3+2n = 30, it is not divisible by 7\n if n=9, \n 7n+3+2n = 30, it is divisible by 7",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the remainder when (146)^56 is divided by 7.",
    "choice_1": 1,
    "choice_2": 2,
    "choice_3": 3,
    "choice_4": 7,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "146 can be expressed as [(7×21) – 1] so\n Remainder of the above question is (- 1)^56 = 1",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the remainder when (269)^57587 is divided by 6.",
    "choice_1": 1,
    "choice_2": 2,
    "choice_3": 3,
    "choice_4": 5,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Solution: 269 can be expressed as [( 6x 45) – 1] so\n Remainder of the above question is (- 1)^57587 = – 1 = -1 + 6 = 5",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the remainder when 73 x 75 x 78 x 194 x 57 is divided by 25.",
    "choice_1": 0,
    "choice_2": 1,
    "choice_3": 2,
    "choice_4": 3,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "If denominator is perfectly divisible by any one number of given numerator expression values then remainder of the whole expression is Zero.",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the remainder when 1! + 2! + 3! + . . . . .. . .. 99! + 100! is divided by the product of first 7 natural numbers.",
    "choice_1": 751,
    "choice_2": 543,
    "choice_3": 873,
    "choice_4": 963,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "From 7! the remainder will be zero. Why ? because 7! is nothing but product of first 7 natural numbers and all factorial after that will have 7! as one of the factor. so we are concerned only factorials till 7!, i.e, 1! + 2! + 3! + 4! + 5! + 6!\n 1! + 2! + 3! + 4! + 5! + 6! = 873 and as 7! > 873 our remainder will be 873",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the remainder when 64^999 is divided by 7?",
    "choice_1": 1,
    "choice_2": 5,
    "choice_3": 3,
    "choice_4": 11,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Remainder [64^999 / 7 ] = Remainder[ 64 * 64 * …. 64 (999 times) / 7 ]\n Remainder[64/7] = 1, hence Remainder [64^999 / 7 ] = Remainder [ 1^999 / 7 ] = 1",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A number when divided by 18 leaves a remainder 7. The same number when divided by 12 leaves a remainder n. How many values can n take?",
    "choice_1": 1,
    "choice_2": 3,
    "choice_3": 2,
    "choice_4": 7,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Number can be 7, 25, 43, 61, 79.\nRemainders when divided by 12 are 7 and 1.\nn can take exactly 2 values",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "It is desired to extract the maximum power of 3 from 24!, where n! = n.(n – 1) . (n – 2) … 3.2.1. What will be the exponent of 3?",
    "choice_1": 8,
    "choice_2": 9,
    "choice_3": 10,
    "choice_4": 11,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "From 0 to 24, there are 8 numbers which are divisible by 3. and  the numbers 9 (3 * 3) and 18 (3*3*2) have two two 3s. Therefore, 8 +2 = 10.",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The unit digit in the expression 36^234 x 33^512 x 39^180 – 54^29 x 25^123 x 31^512 will be",
    "choice_1": 3,
    "choice_2": 6,
    "choice_3": 8,
    "choice_4": 9,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "It can be seen that the first expression is larger than the second one. Hence, the required answer would be given by the (units digit of the first expression – units digit of the second expression) = 6 – 0 = 6.",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the remainder when 444^444^444 is divided by 7?",
    "choice_1": 0,
    "choice_2": 3,
    "choice_3": 1,
    "choice_4": 7,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Remainder[444/7] = 3\n Remainder[ 444^444 ^ 444 / 7 ] = Remainder [ 3^444 ^ 444 / 7 ]\n = Remainder [ ( 3^2 )^222 ^ 444 / 7 ] = Remainder [ 2222 ^ 444 / 7 ] ( As Remainder [ 3^2 / 7 ] = 2 )\n = Remainder [ ( 2^3 ) 74 ^ 444 / 7] = Remainder [ 1^ 74 ^ 444 / 7 ] = 1 ( As Remainder [ 2^3 / 7 ] = 1 )",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the remainder when 97 97 ^ 97 is divided by 11?",
    "choice_1": 6,
    "choice_2": 4,
    "choice_3": 7,
    "choice_4": 2,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Remainder [97/11] = 9\n So, Remainder [97^97^97/11] = Remainder [9^97^97/11]\n From Euler’s theorem, Remainder [9^10/11] = 1\n 97 and 10 are again co primes. So φ(10) = 10 (1-1/2) (1-1/5) = 4\n Remainder [97^4/11] = 1\n 97 = 4n + 1, So Remainder [97^97/11] = Remainder [97/10] = 7\n Means 97^97 can be written as 10n + 7\n Now our original question,\n Remainder [9^97^97/11] = Remainder [9^10n+7/11] = Remainder [9^7/11] = 4.",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The sum of the digits of a number N is 23. The remainder when N is divided by 11 is 7. What is the remainder when N is divided by 33?",
    "choice_1": 7,
    "choice_2": 17,
    "choice_3": 21,
    "choice_4": 29,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Sum of digits = 23\n Remainder when N is divided by 9\n N/9 = 5 {Remainder on division by 9 for any number is equal to the remainder of dividing the sum of the digits of the number by 9}\n => Remainder of N/3 = 2 {A number of the form 9k + 5 divided by 3 leaves a remainder 2}\n N = 11k + 7\n N = 3m + 2\n 11k + 7 => Possible numbers are 7, 18, 29, 40, 51\n 3m + 2 => Possible numbers are 2, 5, 8, 11, 14, 17, 20, 23, 26, 29\n \n The number that is of the form 11k + 7 and 3m + 2 should be of the form 33b + 29. How did we arrive at this result?\n \n The first natural number that satisfies both properties is 29.\n Now, starting with 29, every 11th number is of the form 11k + 7, and every 3rd number is of the form 3m + 2.\n So, starting from 29, every 33rd number should be on both lists (33 is the LCM of 11 and 3).\n Or, any number of the form 33b + 29 will be both of the form 11K + 7 and 3m + 2, where b, k, m are natural numbers.\n The remainder when the said number is divided by 33 is 29.",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "N = 1! – 2! + 3! – 4! +…..+ 47! – 48! + 49! – 50! + 51!, Then what is the unit digit of N^N?",
    "choice_1": 3,
    "choice_2": 1,
    "choice_3": 7,
    "choice_4": 0,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "From 5! onwards, each of the numbers would have a units digit of 0.Hence, the units digit of the given number would depend on the units digit of 1! − 2! + 3! − 4!, which would be 1 (1 − 2 + 6 − 4). Since N is a number that has a unit’s digit of 1, when it is raised to any power, the units digit would not change. Hence, the correct answer would be 1",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "For what maximum value of 'n' will the\n expression 10200!/(504^n), n be an integer?",
    "choice_1": 1526,
    "choice_2": 1538,
    "choice_3": 1698,
    "choice_4": 1786,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "We thus have to look for the number of 7s, the number of 2^3s and the number of 3^2s that are contained in 10200!. The lowest of these will be the constraint value for n. To find the number of 2^3s we need to find the number\n of 2s as, \n [10200/2] + [10200/4] + [10200/8] + [10200/16] + [10200/32] + [10200/64] + [10200/128] + [10200/256] + [10200/512] + [10200/1024] + [10200/2048] + [10200/4096] + [10200/8192] = 5100 + 2550 + 1275 + 637 + 318 + 159 + 79 + 39 +\n 19 + 9 + 4 + 2 + 1 = \n Number of twos = 10192.\n Number of 3s = [10200/3] + [10200/9] + [10200/27] + [10200/81] + [10200/243] + [10200/729] + [10200/2187] + [10200/2187] = 3400 + 1133 + 377 + 125 + 41 + 13 + 4 + 1 = 5094.\n No. of 3^2s = 2547\n Similarly we find the number of 7s as = [10200/247] + [10200/49] + [10200/343] + [10200/2401 = 1698.\n Thus, we have, 1698 sevens, 2547 nines and 3397 eights\n contained in 10200!.\n The required value of n will be given by the lowest of\n these three [The student is expected to explore why this\n happens]\n Hence, answer = 1698.",
    "Topic": "NUMBERS 1 (POWER CYCLES AND REMAINDER CYCLE)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\nMy favorite history professor, (as well as) some of his administrative staff, (were) asked to resign (because) fewer students were taking\nhistory courses (than) ever before. No error",
    "choice_1": "because",
    "choice_2": "No error",
    "choice_3": "than",
    "choice_4": "were",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "In this sentence, the verb does not agree with the subject. The subject \"professor\" is singular (“as well as some of the administrative staff” is a modifying phrase and doesn’t count), so the correct verb form should be “was,” not “were.”",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions )"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\nStephanie claims that she (wants) (to attend) college after graduation, but her poor attitude about (studying) during senior year (do not) (indicate) that she enjoys being a student. (No error)",
    "choice_1": "do not indicate",
    "choice_2": "studying",
    "choice_3": "to attend",
    "choice_4": "wants",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Her poor attitude about studying\" is the subject of this clause, so the verb must agree with the singular subject \"attitude.\" Therefore, the correct verb should be \"does\"—her attitude \"does not indicate.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\nJames is a proactive police officer, (so although) the local rebellious teenagers (are annoyed) by his (strict nature), the overall safety of the town (have improved ) drastically since he was hired. (No error)",
    "choice_1": "have improved",
    "choice_2": "so although",
    "choice_3": "are annoyed",
    "choice_4": "No error",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "This is an issue of subject-verb agreement within this independent clause: \"the overall safety of the town have improved drastically since he was hired.\" Simplified, the subject is \"safety,\" which is a singular noun, so the verb must also be singular, making \"have improved\" incorrect and \"has improved\" the corrected verb.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\nA pair of (supportive) shoes (are) important if (you) (are experiencing) lower back pain. (No error)",
    "choice_1": "you",
    "choice_2": "supportive",
    "choice_3": "are",
    "choice_4": "No error",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "The verb \"are\" agrees with a plural subject, but the subject of this sentence is the singular \"pair.\" Changing \"are\" to \"is\" corrects the sentence's error. The corrected sentence reads, \"A pair of supportive shoes is important if you are experiencing lower back pain.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Select the bracket word or phrase that needs to be changed to make the sentence correct. Some sentences contain no error at all.\n\nThe paralegal believed (that) there (were) an overload (of cases in the office), (which) was creating stress. (No error)",
    "choice_1": "that",
    "choice_2": "were",
    "choice_3": "of cases in the office",
    "choice_4": "which",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The verb \"were,\" which is used with plural nouns, corresponds to \"overload,\" which is a singular noun. Therefore, the verb should be \"was,\" to match the singular noun, instead of \"were.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\nThe three friends, Max included, (was supposed to meet) for dinner later that night.",
    "choice_1": "was supposed to meet",
    "choice_2": "was supposed to have met",
    "choice_3": "were suppose to be meeting",
    "choice_4": "were supposed to meet",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "The subject of this sentence is friends which is plural. The phrase Max included is set off by commas and, like any “sandwich” phrase, can be crossed out to help isolate the subject and the main verb:\n\nThe three friends was…\n\nThe plural subject friends does not agree with the singular verb was. We need the plural verb were. A) was supposed to meet\nSubject / verb agreement? NO – three friends (plural) : was (singular)\n\nB) was supposed to have met\nSubject / verb agreement? NO – three friends (plural) : was (singular)\n\nC) were suppose to be meeting\nSubject / verb agreement? YES – three friends (plural) : were (plural)\nAdditional errors? Diction: “suppose to be” should read “supposed to be”\n\nD) were supposed to meet\nSubject / verb agreement? YES – three friends (plural) : were (plural)\nAdditional errors? No",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\nThe number of students chosen for the prestigious medical internship (have more than doubled) in the past fifteen years.",
    "choice_1": "have more than doubled",
    "choice_2": "have been more than doubling",
    "choice_3": "has more than doubled",
    "choice_4": "has been more than doubling",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "The phrase The number of is a singular subject that does not agree with the plural verb have…doubled. We need the singular verb has…doubled. A) have more than doubled\nSubject / verb agreement? NO – The number of students (singular) : have…doubled (plural)\n\nB) have been more than doubling\nSubject / verb agreement? NO – The number of students (singular) : have…doubling (plural)\n\nC) has more than doubled\nSubject / verb agreement? YES – The number of students (singular) : has…doubled (singular)\nAdditional errors? NO\n\nD) has been more than doubling\nSubject / verb agreement? YES – The number of students (singular) : has been…doubling (singular)\nAdditional errors? Verb tense: The verb form “has been…doubling” is inappropriate for an action that has already been completed.\n\nE) has doubled even more\nSubject / verb agreement? YES – The number of students (singular) : has doubled (singular)\nAdditional errors? Idioms: “has doubled even more” is the wrong idiom to express the notion of something “more than doubling.”\n\n(C) is correct.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\n Following intense debate, (the faculty has approved the measure to increase )class size by 15% over the next four years.",
    "choice_1": "the faculty has approved the measure to increase",
    "choice_2": "the faculty has approved the measure and increased",
    "choice_3": "the faculty have approved the measure to increase",
    "choice_4": "the faculty have given their approval to the measure to increase",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The collective noun faculty refers to the members of the faculty as a collective body; the members of the faculty acted as one in making the decision to approve the measure. We  therefore need the singular verb has approved. A) the faculty has approved the measure to increase\nSubject/verb agreement: YES – faculty (singular) : has approved (singular)\nAdditional errors? NO\n\nB) the faculty has approved the measure and increased\nSubject/verb agreement: YES – faculty (singular) : has approved (singular)\nAdditional errors? Verb tense: the faculty has made the decision “to increase“class size\n\nC) the faculty have approved the measure to increase\nSubject/verb agreement: NO – faculty (singular) : have approved (plural)\n\nD) the faculty have given their approval to the measure to increase\nSubject/verb agreement: NO – faculty (singular) : have approved (plural)\n\nE) the faculty, having approved the measure to increase\nSubject/verb agreement: NO – faculty (singular) : have approved (plural)\n\n(A) is correct.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\n Some (members of the tribe has been protesting) the recent passage of hunting laws applying to indigenous populations.",
    "choice_1": "members of the tribe has been protesting",
    "choice_2": "members of the tribe have been protesting",
    "choice_3": "tribe members has been protesting",
    "choice_4": "tribe members will have been protesting",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The plural subject Some members does not agree with the singular verb has been protesting. To help isolate the subject and verb, cross out any prepositional phrases, which do not impact agreement in the main clause:\n\nSome members has been protesting the recent passage of hunting laws applying to indigenous populations.\n\nNote that here, the subject is Some members, which is the same as saying Some of the members. This construction requires the plural verb have been protesting. A) members of the tribe has been protesting\nSubject / verb agreement? NO – Some members (plural) : has been protesting (singular)\n\nB) members of the tribe have been protesting\nSubject / verb agreement? YES – Some members (plural) : have been protesting (plural)\nAdditional errors? NO\n\nC) tribe members has been protesting\nSubject / verb agreement? NO – Some tribe members (plural)/ has been protesting (singular)\n\nD) tribe members will have been protesting\nSubject / verb agreement? YES – Some tribe members (plural) : will have been protesting (plural)\nAdditional errors? Verb tense: “will have been protesting” implies that the action takes place in the future, but the protest is happening now.\n\nE) members of the tribe, having protested\nSubject / verb agreement? NO – Agreement does not apply here because the main clause has no verb.\n\n(B) is correct.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\nAfter she attended the career fair, (many more resources were at Philippa’s disposal), including job boards, new contacts, and numerous books and pamphlets to help her improve her resume and cover letter.",
    "choice_1": "Philippa had many more resources at her disposal",
    "choice_2": "Philippa, at her disposal, had many more resources",
    "choice_3": "at Philippa’s disposal were many more resources",
    "choice_4": "many more resources were at Philippa’s disposal",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The introductory phrase includes the pronoun she, so we know that this modifier must refer to Philippa. However, the phrase many more resources is next to the modifying phrase. The word Philippa must immediately follow the comma. A) many more resources were at Philippa’s disposal\nModifier used correctly? NO – After she attended the career fair is followed by many more resources\n\nB) at Philippa’s disposal were many more resources\nModifier used correctly? NO – After she attended the career fair is followed by at Philippa’s disposal\n\nC) there were many more resources at Philippa’s disposal\nModifier used correctly? NO – After she attended the career fair is followed by there were\n\nD) Philippa, at her disposal, had many more resources\nModifier used correctly? YES – After she attended the career fair is followed by Philippa\nAdditional errors? Awkward construction: The correct expression is “had x at her disposal.”\n\nE) Philippa had many more resources at her disposal\nModifier used correctly? YES – After she attended the career fair is followed by Philippa.\nAdditional errors? NO\n\n(E) is correct.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the Subject-Verb Agreement with answer that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\n\nThe convention of meteorologists, despite being well funded, were unsuccessful and have failed to achieve any of their annual goals.",
    "choice_1": "The convention of meteorologists, despite being well funded, were unsuccessful and has failed to achieve any of their annual goals.",
    "choice_2": "The convention of meteorologists, despite being well funded, was unsuccessful and has failed to achieve any of its annual goals.",
    "choice_3": "The convention of meteorologists, despite being well funded, was unsuccessful and have failed to achieve any of its annual goals.",
    "choice_4": "The convention of meteorologists, despite being well funded, were unsuccessful and have failed to achieve any of its annual goals.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "With a complex sentence such as this, it’s important to keep track of your subjects and verbs. Although “meteorologists” is plural, the subject of the sentence is the singular “convention,” and therefore the correct verb forms are “was” and “has failed,” not “were” and “have failed.” Similarly, the singular pronoun “its” is correct and the plural pronoun “their” is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket portion  of Subject-Verb Agreement with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\n\n( Making up stories are one of the chief ways ) a child learns to develop critical thinking skills.",
    "choice_1": "Making up stories is one of the chief ways",
    "choice_2": "Making up stories are one of the chief way's",
    "choice_3": "Making up stories are one chief way",
    "choice_4": "Making up, stories are one of the chief ways",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The subject of the sentence is actually the gerund phrase \"Making up stories,\" which is a singular construction, despite the use of \"stories.\" The verb, therefore, must match the singular subject, but is written in a plural form. \"Making up stories is one of the chief ways\" is the answer choice that best corrects this issue.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket portion  of Subject-Verb Agreement with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English. \n\n( Paul and Tom, who is some of the fastest runners I have ever seen, ) left yesterday.",
    "choice_1": "Paul and Tom, who is some of the fastest runners I have ever seen",
    "choice_2": "Paul and Tom who is some of the fastest runners I have ever seen",
    "choice_3": "Paul and Tom, who are some of the fastest runners I have ever seen,",
    "choice_4": "Paul and Tom, who are some of the fastest runners I have seen,",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "In standard English, there are different forms for verbs. You must always ensure, in any sentence, that the form of the verb being used corresponds to the noun whose action is being described. In the sentence above, there is an error due to the fact that the subject is plural and the verb is singular. The best way to correct the underlined portion is: \"Paul and Tom, who are some of the fastest runners I have ever seen,\"\n\nNote that the interrupting phrase \"who are some of the fastest runners I have ever seen\" is correctly enclosed with commas.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket portion  of Subject-Verb Agreement with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English. \n\n(The jury are ready to render the verdict:) it's all going to be over soon.",
    "choice_1": "The jury are ready to render the verdict;",
    "choice_2": "The jury are ready to render the verdict,",
    "choice_3": "The juries is ready to render the verdict:",
    "choice_4": "The jury is ready to render the verdict:",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "In standard English, there are different forms for verbs. You must always ensure, in any sentence, that the form of the verb being used corresponds to the noun whose action is being described. In the sentence above, there is an error due to the fact that the subject is singular and the verb is plural. It is important to remember that some nouns describe groups of people as a unit, like a \"jury,\" and those nouns are considered singular. The best way to correct the underlined portion is: \"The jury is ready to render the verdict:",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket portion of Subject-Verb Agreement with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English. \nEveryone in the villages (know that) the boy was in trouble from the moment he came home.",
    "choice_1": "know which",
    "choice_2": "knows that",
    "choice_3": "knows which",
    "choice_4": "know that",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The subject of the sentence \"Everyone\" is a singular noun, but the verb \"know\" is plural. A subject and verb have to match in tense, so the verb needs to be in the singular form. The correct answer is \"knows that.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Subject-Verb Agreement based and Modifiers based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\n\n(What is unique about these category is their relation to these things that are taken on) to add to a being’s natural capacities.",
    "choice_1": "What is unique about those category is it's relation to those things which are taken on",
    "choice_2": "What is unique about this category is its relation to those things that are taken on",
    "choice_3": "What is unique about this category is its relation to them things which are taken on",
    "choice_4": "What is unique about these category is their relation to these things that are taken on",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Pronouns should agree with their noun antecedents in number and case (\"this\" with the singular \"category;\" \"those\" with the plural and inanimate \"things;\" \"that\" with the nominative \"things\"). \"It's,\" being a contraction of \"it is,\" is not a pronoun!",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\n\nAfter reviewing all of the relevant legal information, (the court decided that the original agreement had been strictly between she and the family trust, legally a technicality that significantly reduced the amount she expected to receive.)",
    "choice_1": "the decision of the court significantly reduced the amount that she expected to receive, being based as it was on the legal technicality that the original agreement had been strictly between her and the family trust",
    "choice_2": "the court decided that the orginal agreement had been strictly between she and the family trust, a legal technicality that significantly reduced the amount she expected to receive",
    "choice_3": "the court decided that the orginal agreement had been strictly between her and the family trust, a legal technicality that significantly reduced the amount she expected to receive",
    "choice_4": "she expected to receive a significantly reduced amount because the court decided, based on a legal technicality, that the original agreement had been strictly between her and the family trust.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "The clause at the beginning of the sentence modifies \"the court,\" so that must be the subject of the sentence. Otherwise, the clause would be considered a dangling modifier. Additionally, the pronoun \"she\" is incorrectly used. Since the pronoun is functioning as the object of the preposition \"between,\" it must be an objective-case pronoun. In order to be correct, it must be changed to \"her,\" as in \"the agreement is between her and the family trust.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\n\nLike supermarkets across the country, (the grocery chain was seeking to offer their clientele more local and organic products to meet new consumer demands.)",
    "choice_1": "the grocery chain was seeking to offer their clientele more local or organic products to meet new consumer demands.",
    "choice_2": "the grocery chain was seeking to offer their clients more local and organic products to meet new consumer demands.",
    "choice_3": "the grocery chain was seeking to offer their clientele more local and organic products, to meet new consumer demands.",
    "choice_4": "the grocery chain was seeking to offer its clientele more local and organic products to meet new consumer demands.",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "In the underlined portion of the sentence, \"the grocery chain\" is singular, but the chain's \"clientele\" is referred to with a plural pronoun, \"their.\" The pronoun must be changed to the possesive singular pronoun, \"its.\" As the only answer choice that makes this correction, \"the grocery chain was seeking to offer its clientele more local and organic products to meet new consumer demands\" is the correct answer choice.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\nIt is explicitly stated in the employee handbook (that all workers must supply his or her own steel-toed shoes.)",
    "choice_1": "that each worker must supply they're own steel-toed shoes.",
    "choice_2": "that all workers must supply their own steel-toed shoes.",
    "choice_3": "that all workers must supply one's own steel-toed shoes.",
    "choice_4": "that each worker must supply their own steel-toed shoes.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Because \"all workers\" is plural, the pronoun that refers to it as its antecedent must also be plural. Thus, the correct version of the sentence is: \"It is explicitly stated in the employee handbook that all workers must provide their own steel-toed shoes.\"\n\nIf the workers are made individual (\"each worker\") then the correct pronoun form would be \"his or her,\" because the individual pronoun is required but the gender of the worker is not specified.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\n\nNeither the supervisor nor the employees (expressed his objections to the schedule at the time it was posted.)",
    "choice_1": "expressed their objections to the schedule at the time it was posted.",
    "choice_2": "expressed one's objections to the schedule at the time it was posted.",
    "choice_3": "expressed whatever objections he had at the time it was posted.",
    "choice_4": "expressed his or her objections to the schedule at the time it was posted.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "This sentence uses a correlative conjunction (\"Neither . . . nor\") to connect two antecedents; therefore, the pronoun must agree with the second antecedent, in this case \"the employees,\" which is plural. Thus, the correct pronoun is \"their.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\n\nThe new guidelines clearly stated that if a supervisor or an employee ( had a workplace issue, they were supposed to take) the problem to the Human Resources department.",
    "choice_1": "had a workplace issue, he or she was supposed to take",
    "choice_2": "had a workplace issue, they were supposed to take",
    "choice_3": "had a workplace issue, they are supposed to take",
    "choice_4": "had a workplace issue, they were supposing to take",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The use of the plural pronoun \"they\" is wrong in this sentence, as a pronoun must always be in agreement with its antecedent, which in this sentence is each of the singular nouns \"a supervisor\" and \"an employee.\" The pronoun should be changed to an appropriate singular form. As the only option that makes this change, \"had a workplace issue, he or she was supposed to take\" is the correct answer choice.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\n\nThe new strategy was (a remarkable departure from those laid) by the general’s predecessor.",
    "choice_1": "a remarkable departure from the ones laid",
    "choice_2": "a remarkable departure for those laid",
    "choice_3": "a remarkably departure from those laid",
    "choice_4": "a remarkable departure from the one laid",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "In this sentence, the use of the demonstrative pronoun \"those,\" which indicates a plural antecedent, is not in agreement with the singular subject of \"strategy.\" The pronoun should be changed to a singular form to be in agreement with the subject. There is only one answer choice that makes this change, \"a remarkable departure from the one laid,\" which is the correct answer.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the Parallelism error in the below question.\n\nHe desired to make a lot of money and that he might earn a good reputation.",
    "choice_1": "He desired to make a lot of money and to earn a good reputation.",
    "choice_2": "He desired making a lot of money and that he might earn a good reputation.",
    "choice_3": "He desired to make a lot of money and earning a good reputation.",
    "choice_4": "He desired that he might make a lot of money and to earn a good reputation.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The sentence \"He desired to make a lot of money and that he might earn a good reputation\" has a parallelism problem.  \"To make a lot of money\" is an infinitive phrase, while \"that he might earn a good reputation\" is a clause.  Option (a): \"He desired to make a lot of money and to earn a good reputation.\"  This is correct.  Both \"to make\" and \"to earn\" are infinitive phrases, creating parallel structure.\n\nOption (b): \"He desired making a lot of money and that he might earn a good reputation.\" This is incorrect.  \"Making\" is a gerund (a verb form ending in -ing that functions as a noun), while \"that he might earn\" is a clause.  These are different grammatical structures and shouldn't be used in parallel.\n\nOption (c): \"He desired to make a lot of money and earning a good reputation.\" This is incorrect.  It mixes an infinitive phrase (\"to make\") with a gerund phrase (\"earning\").\n\nOption (d): \"He desired that he might make a lot of money and to earn a good reputation.\" This is incorrect. It mixes a \"that\" clause with an infinitive phrase.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Select the bracket word or phrase that needs to be changed to make the sentence correct. Some sentences contain no error at all.\n\n(Small in size), the mongoose may not seem like (an imposing creature), but when threatened (they) can (fight off and even slay) a large predator such as the king cobra. (No error)",
    "choice_1": "fight off and even slay",
    "choice_2": "an imposing creature",
    "choice_3": "No error",
    "choice_4": "they",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "They,\" a plural pronoun, is used in the sentence to refer to \"the mongoose,\" a singular subject. So, \"they\" should be changed to \"it.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket portion of Pronoun Antecedent Agreement Errors with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English.\n\n(Although the basketball team used their star players), the match was lost.",
    "choice_1": "Although the basketball team used its star players",
    "choice_2": "Although the basketball team used their star players",
    "choice_3": "Although the star players were used by the basketball team",
    "choice_4": "The basketball team used their star players",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Choose a pronoun that properly agrees with the subject. In this case, \"basketball team\" is singular, although it represents a group of people, and should be accompanied with \"its,\" instead of \"their.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Identify the Pronoun Antecedent Agreement Errors with the answer choice that best improves the bracket portion of the sentence. \n\n\nWhile it can seem like a daunting task to train for a marathon, anyone who has completed the challenge knows that ( preparing a plan that they stick to ) is the key to success.",
    "choice_1": "preparing a plan that they stick to",
    "choice_2": "preparing, and having that be a plan that they stick to",
    "choice_3": "preparing a plan and sticking to it",
    "choice_4": "preparing a plan that he sticks to",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "In this sentence, the subject is \"anyone,\" a singular pronoun. Therefore, all pronouns relating back to \"anyone\" should be singular. In the underlined portion of the sentence, \"preparing a plan that they stick to,\" \"they\" is plural, not singular. Now that we have identified the problem, we have to figure out how to correct it.\n\nGiven that \"anyone\" is gender neutral, the best way to improve this sentence is avoid the use of a gendered pronoun (meaning \"he\" or \"she\") and simply avoid using a pronoun at all. The correct answer, \"preparing a plan and sticking to it,\" accomplishes this objective and is therefore the best way to improve the sentence.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket portion of Pronoun Antecedent Agreement Errors with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English. \n\nThe community is currently accepting nominations for the award, which will be given to ( the person who has most significantly transformed the world through their charitable actions or scientific discoveries ).",
    "choice_1": "the person who most significantly transformed the world through their charitable actions or scientific discoveries.",
    "choice_2": "the person who has most significantly transformed the world through their charitable actions or scientific discoveries.",
    "choice_3": "the person that has most significantly transformed the world through his or her charitable actions or scientific discoveries.",
    "choice_4": "the person who has most significantly transformed the world through his or her charitable actions or scientific discoveries.",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "The original text \"the person who has most significantly transformed the world through their charitable actions or scientific discoveries\" and the answer choice \"the person who most significantly transformed the world through their charitable actions or scientific discoveries\" contain pronoun agreement errors because they incorrectly use the plural pronoun \"their\" to refer to the singular noun \"person.\"\n\nThe answer choices \"the person that has most significantly transformed the world through his or her charitable actions or scientific discoveries\" and \"the person that significantly transformed the world through his or her charitable actions or scientific discoveries\" are incorrect because they use \"that\" to refer to a person, when \"who\" or \"whom\" should be used when referring to a person. (Remember to use \"that\" only when referring to non-human living things or objects.)\n\nThe answer choice \"the person who has most significantly transformed the world through his or her charitable actions or scientific discoveries\" is correct because it is the only answer choice that correctly uses \"who\" and the singular pronoun \"his or her\" to match the singular noun \"person.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket portion of Pronoun Antecedent Agreement Errors with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English. .\n\nThe reason that so many ancient empires no longer exist (is that they became too large for its government to collect tax revenues from citizens).",
    "choice_1": "is that they became too large for their governments to collect tax revenues from citizens",
    "choice_2": "is that it became too large for its government to collect tax revenues from citizens",
    "choice_3": "is that they became too large for its government to collect tax revenues from citizens",
    "choice_4": "are that it became too large for its government to collect tax revenues from citizens",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The original text contains a pronoun reference error. The antecedent of \"its\" is \"empires,\" which is plural. We should therefore use the plural possessive pronoun \"their\" instead of the singular possessive pronoun \"its.\" Only the answer choice \"is that they became too large for their governments to collect tax revenues from citizens\" correctly uses the plural posessive pronoun.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket portion of Pronoun Antecedent Agreement Errors with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English. . \n\nIn addition to helping the environment, renewable resources—such as solar power and hydroelectricity—may also provide an economic benefit, (as it may reduce our dependence on foreign oil).",
    "choice_1": "as they depend on the reduction of foreign oil.",
    "choice_2": "as they may reduce our dependence on foreign oil.",
    "choice_3": "as it reduces our dependence on foreign oil.",
    "choice_4": "as it may reduce our dependence on foreign oil.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The pronoun \"it\" should be plural because its antecedent is the plural subject \"resources.\" Only two choices correcty change \"it\" to \"they,\" but one of them, \"as they depend on the reduction of foreign oil,\" confuses cause and effect. The resources are not dependent on the reduction of foreign oil. The correct answer is \"as they may reduce our dependence on foreign oil.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket portion of Pronoun Antecedent Agreement Errors with the answer choice that results in a sentence that is clear, precise, and meets the requirements of standard written English. \n\n( Most men who go to sporting events find it an enjoyable diversion ).",
    "choice_1": "Most men who go to sporting events find it to be an enjoyable diversion.",
    "choice_2": "Many men who go to sporting events find it an enjoyable diversion.",
    "choice_3": "Most men who go to sporting events find them an enjoyable diversion.",
    "choice_4": "Most of the men who go to sporting events find it an enjoyable diversion.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "The sentence as written contains one small error. \"It,\" a singular pronoun, is used to refer to the plural \"sporting events.\" In order to fix this issue, the pronoun needs to be made plural, which is done in \"Most men who go to sporting events find them an enjoyable diversion.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Parallelism based and Pronoun-Antecedent Agreement based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Identify the correct sentence:",
    "choice_1": "She had gone to the store before I arrived.",
    "choice_2": "She had went to the store before I arrived.",
    "choice_3": "She gone to the store before I arrived.",
    "choice_4": "She goes to the store before I arrived.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Had gone' is the correct past perfect tense; 'had went' is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence correctly follows verb tense sequence?",
    "choice_1": "He said that he will finish the work by tomorrow.",
    "choice_2": "He said that he would finish the work by tomorrow.",
    "choice_3": "He said that he will have finished the work by tomorrow.",
    "choice_4": "He said that he finished the work by tomorrow.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Would finish' is correct for reported speech; 'will finish' is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Choose the sentence with correct comparison:",
    "choice_1": "This laptop is better than any other laptops.",
    "choice_2": "This laptop is better than any other laptop.",
    "choice_3": "This laptop is better than all laptops.",
    "choice_4": "This laptop is better than any laptops.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Better than any other laptop' correctly maintains comparison logic.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following sentences is grammatically correct?",
    "choice_1": "I prefer coffee than tea.",
    "choice_2": "I prefer coffee against tea.",
    "choice_3": "I prefer coffee over tea.",
    "choice_4": "I prefer coffee with tea.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Prefer over' is correct; 'prefer than' is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence maintains logical time sequence?",
    "choice_1": "After he will finish his work, he will go home.",
    "choice_2": "After he finishes his work, he will go home.",
    "choice_3": "After he finishing his work, he will go home.",
    "choice_4": "After he had finished his work, he will go home.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The correct sequence is 'After he finishes'; 'will finish' is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Identify the sentence with proper parallel comparison:",
    "choice_1": "The salary of a teacher is lower than that of a doctor.",
    "choice_2": "The salary of a teacher is lower than a doctor.",
    "choice_3": "The salary of a teacher is lower compared to a doctor.",
    "choice_4": "The salary of a teacher is low than a doctor.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "For proper comparison, 'lower than that of' is correct.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Choose the sentence with the correct verb sequence:",
    "choice_1": "If I was you, I would take the job.",
    "choice_2": "If I were you, I would take the job.",
    "choice_3": "If I am you, I would take the job.",
    "choice_4": "If I be you, I would take the job.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "If I were' is correct in subjunctive mood; 'was' is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence follows a valid comparison structure?",
    "choice_1": "She is taller compared to her sister.",
    "choice_2": "She is more taller than her sister.",
    "choice_3": "She is taller than her sister.",
    "choice_4": "She is tallest than her sister.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Taller than' is the correct comparison; 'compared to' is incorrect here.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Identify the grammatically correct sentence:",
    "choice_1": "Neither of the boys were interested in sports.",
    "choice_2": "Neither of the boys was interested in sports.",
    "choice_3": "Neither of the boys were interested to sports.",
    "choice_4": "Neither of the boys was interested for sports.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Neither' is singular, so 'was' is correct; 'were' is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence correctly maintains tense consistency?",
    "choice_1": "By the time we reached, he leaves already.",
    "choice_2": "By the time we reached, he already left.",
    "choice_3": "By the time we reached, he has already left.",
    "choice_4": "By the time we reached, he had already left.",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Had already left' follows the correct past perfect sequence.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Identify the correct sentence based on verb time sequence: She claimed that she ___ the documents before the meeting started.",
    "choice_1": "has reviewed",
    "choice_2": "had reviewed",
    "choice_3": "would have reviewed",
    "choice_4": "reviewed",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The reporting verb “claimed” is in the past tense.\n\nThe action of reviewing happened before the meeting.\n\n→ Use past perfect (\"had reviewed\") for the earlier of two past actions.\n\n“Has reviewed” is present perfect and incorrect for past narration.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Identify the correct sentence based on Comparison:  Unlike the novels of her contemporaries, Jane Austen's works focus on social class and irony rather than ___ centered on heroism and adventure.",
    "choice_1": "her contemporaries’ were",
    "choice_2": "her contemporaries’ novels",
    "choice_3": "those of her contemporaries",
    "choice_4": "they",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "The comparison must be between “Jane Austen’s works” and other novels.\n\n“Those” refers to “novels”, maintaining parallelism.\n\n“They” and “them” are vague and ungrammatical here.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Identify the correct sentence based on verb time sequence:  If he ___ the blueprint before presenting, the errors could have been avoided.",
    "choice_1": "has checked",
    "choice_2": "would check",
    "choice_3": "had checked",
    "choice_4": "was checking",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "This is a third conditional sentence (imaginary past).\n\nStructure: If + past perfect, could have + past participle",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Identify the correct sentence based Sequence and Modal Tense Conflict : The manager warned that unless the report ___ by noon, the client meeting would be postponed.",
    "choice_1": "is submitted",
    "choice_2": "was submitted",
    "choice_3": "would be submitted",
    "choice_4": "has been submitted",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Conditional clause in past-future setup:\n→ “warned” (past), so use past simple in the condition: “was submitted.”\n\n\"Is submitted\" (present) and \"has been submitted\" (present perfect) are tense mismatches.\n\n\"Would be submitted\" is incorrect because “unless” requires a real condition, not a hypothetical.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Identify the correct sentence based Comparison and  Verb tense :  The new prototype is faster and more energy-efficient than any of the models that ___ last year.",
    "choice_1": "is tested",
    "choice_2": "was tested",
    "choice_3": "had been test",
    "choice_4": "were tested",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "“Models that ___ last year” → refers to a completed action in the past\n\nSo use simple past passive: “were tested”\n\n“Was tested” is wrong due to plural subject “models”",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Verb Time Sequences based and Comparisons based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Identify the correct sentence:",
    "choice_1": "She is waiting since two hours.",
    "choice_2": "She has been waiting for two hours.",
    "choice_3": "She is waiting from two hours.",
    "choice_4": "She is waiting at two hours.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Has been waiting for' is the correct phrase; 'since' is incorrect here.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence uses the correct preposition?",
    "choice_1": "I am interested for learning new languages.",
    "choice_2": "I am interested in learning new languages.",
    "choice_3": "I am interested about learning new languages.",
    "choice_4": "I am interested by learning new languages.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Interested in' is the correct preposition; 'for' is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Choose the sentence with the correct determiner:",
    "choice_1": "He has a few books on his shelf.",
    "choice_2": "He has little books in his shelf.",
    "choice_3": "He has the few books in his shelf.",
    "choice_4": "He has some few books in his shelf.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "A few books' is correct because 'few' means almost none.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following sentences is grammatically correct?",
    "choice_1": "I prefer this rather than that.",
    "choice_2": "I prefer this to that.",
    "choice_3": "I prefer this than that.",
    "choice_4": "I prefer this over that.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Prefer to' is the correct phrase; 'rather than' is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence correctly uses a preposition?",
    "choice_1": "She is married to a doctor.",
    "choice_2": "She is married with a doctor.",
    "choice_3": "She is married on a doctor.",
    "choice_4": "She is married by a doctor.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Married to' is the correct phrase; 'married with' is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Identify the sentence with the correct determiner usage:",
    "choice_1": "I bought much apples from the market.",
    "choice_2": "I bought many apples from the market.",
    "choice_3": "I bought any apples from the market.",
    "choice_4": "I bought more apples from the market.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Many apples' is correct because 'many' is used for countable nouns.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Choose the sentence with proper preposition usage:",
    "choice_1": "He is good in mathematics.",
    "choice_2": "He is good on mathematics.",
    "choice_3": "He is good at mathematics.",
    "choice_4": "He is good by mathematics.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Good at' is the correct phrase; 'good in' is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence uses the correct determiner?",
    "choice_1": "Can you lend me few money?",
    "choice_2": "Can you lend me a little money?",
    "choice_3": "Can you lend me some few money?",
    "choice_4": "Can you lend me many money?",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A little money' is correct for uncountable nouns.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Identify the grammatically correct sentence:",
    "choice_1": "She is fond with chocolates.",
    "choice_2": "She is fond by chocolates.",
    "choice_3": "She is fond in chocolates.",
    "choice_4": "She is fond of chocolates.",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Fond of' is the correct phrase; 'fond with' is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence correctly maintains proper preposition usage?",
    "choice_1": "He was accused for stealing.",
    "choice_2": "He was accused of stealing.",
    "choice_3": "He was accused with stealing.",
    "choice_4": "He was accused on stealing.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Accused of' is the correct phrase; 'accused for' is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "sentence has been provided below with one blank which needs to be filled with appropriate determiners. Choose the answer from the options provided.\n\nThere are ___ people who believe in ghosts, but ___ of them are willing to admit it.",
    "choice_1": "few,most",
    "choice_2": "many,few",
    "choice_3": "some,none",
    "choice_4": "all,few",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The correct answer is “many, few.” “Many” is used to indicate a large number of people who believe in ghosts, while “few” is used to indicate a small number of people who are willing to admit it. Therefore, option (b) is the correct answer.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which needs to be filled with appropriate determiners. Choose the answer from the options provided.\n\n The company has ____________ employees who can speak Mandarin.",
    "choice_1": "few",
    "choice_2": "a few",
    "choice_3": "little",
    "choice_4": "a little",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The quantifier “a few” is used to express a small number, but it implies that it is enough or sufficient for the purpose. In this sentence, it implies that there are some employees who can speak Mandarin, and it is enough for the company’s needs. The quantifier “few” without “a” has a negative connotation and means “not many” or “scarcely any”. The quantifiers “little” and “a little” are used for non-countable nouns, such as “time”, “money”, or “experience”, and express a small amount or quantity.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following sentences have INCORRECT usage\nof preposition?\n1. The manager was sitting at the desk.\n2. My work is superior to yours.\n3. I prefer coffee than tea.\n4. She was accused for stealing gold.\n5. This is an exception to the rule.\n6. They are leaving to England soon.",
    "choice_1": "1,2,3",
    "choice_2": "3,4,5",
    "choice_3": "3,4,6",
    "choice_4": "2,3,4",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Statements 3, 4 and 6 are incorrect. Correct statements are: 3: I prefer coffee to tea. 4: She was accused of stealing gold. 6: They are leaving for England soon. Answer is option C",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "fill the blank with Prepositions: He doesn't like working __________ civil servants.",
    "choice_1": "for",
    "choice_2": "to",
    "choice_3": "at",
    "choice_4": "with",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "The correct answer is \"with\". This is because the sentence is asking about someone's preference for working with civil servants. The word \"with\" indicates that the person does not enjoy collaborating or cooperating with civil servants in their work.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Replace the bracket with sentence improvement based on Prepositions:  She is improving her pronunciation of English with a view to (become) a newsreader.",
    "choice_1": "no improvement",
    "choice_2": "be becoming",
    "choice_3": "have become",
    "choice_4": "becoming",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Replace ‘become’ with ‘becoming’.\nIf after preposition any verb\ncomes it is used in gerund form.",
    "Topic": "SENTENCE CORRECTION (Prepositions based and Determiners based questions)"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "She is very ___ and always helps others without expecting anything in return.",
    "choice_1": "cruel",
    "choice_2": "selfish",
    "choice_3": "generous",
    "choice_4": "rude",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Generous means kind and giving, fitting the sentence.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The teacher asked the students to ___ their homework before the deadline.",
    "choice_1": "ignore",
    "choice_2": "submit",
    "choice_3": "destroy",
    "choice_4": "copy",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Submit means hand in or turn in.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The children were ___ after playing in the park for hours.",
    "choice_1": "fresh",
    "choice_2": "energetic",
    "choice_3": "exhausted",
    "choice_4": "excited",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Hours of play makes someone exhausted.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Ravi decided to ___ a new language to improve his skills.",
    "choice_1": "forget",
    "choice_2": "invent",
    "choice_3": "learn",
    "choice_4": "delete",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Learn fits the context of improving skills.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The cake smells so ___ that I can’t wait to eat it.",
    "choice_1": "awful",
    "choice_2": "delicious",
    "choice_3": "burnt",
    "choice_4": "bitter",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Delicious refers to tasty, which fits a cake.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The manager ___ his team to finish the project ahead of time.",
    "choice_1": "discouraged",
    "choice_2": "ignored",
    "choice_3": "motivated",
    "choice_4": "punished",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Motivated means encouraged, fits with finishing a project.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Many people think the novel is ___ because it tells a powerful story.",
    "choice_1": "boring",
    "choice_2": "inspiring",
    "choice_3": "dull",
    "choice_4": "confusing",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A powerful story is often inspiring.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Due to heavy rains, the match was ___ for the day.",
    "choice_1": "continued",
    "choice_2": "postponed",
    "choice_3": "advanced",
    "choice_4": "ignored",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Rain typically causes postponement.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The artist's ___ style makes her paintings unique and recognizable.",
    "choice_1": "common",
    "choice_2": "ordinary",
    "choice_3": "distinctive",
    "choice_4": "dull",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Distinctive means unique.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The scientist's new theory was ___ by many experts in the field.",
    "choice_1": "rejected",
    "choice_2": "ignored",
    "choice_3": "criticized",
    "choice_4": "accepted",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "A new theory can be accepted if experts agree with it.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Although the movie received ___ reviews, it performed poorly at the box office.",
    "choice_1": "negative",
    "choice_2": "mixed",
    "choice_3": "average",
    "choice_4": "glowing",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Glowing means very positive; despite that, it failed.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The detective solved the case with his remarkable ___ skills.",
    "choice_1": "observational",
    "choice_2": "physical",
    "choice_3": "cooking",
    "choice_4": "musical",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Detectives rely on observational skills.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "After years of conflict, the two countries finally signed a ___ to end hostilities.",
    "choice_1": "battle",
    "choice_2": "treaty",
    "choice_3": "protest",
    "choice_4": "speech",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Treaty is a formal agreement to stop conflict.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Her arguments were so ___ that everyone was convinced of her point of view.",
    "choice_1": "illogical",
    "choice_2": "confusing",
    "choice_3": "persuasive",
    "choice_4": "weak",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Persuasive means convincing.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The professor’s lecture was full of ___, making it difficult for students to follow.",
    "choice_1": "clarity",
    "choice_2": "brilliance",
    "choice_3": "simplicity",
    "choice_4": "jargon",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Jargon means technical language that is hard to understand.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The baby began to ___ as soon as she saw her mother.",
    "choice_1": "laugh",
    "choice_2": "cry",
    "choice_3": "sleep",
    "choice_4": "shout",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Babies usually smile or laugh seeing their mother happily.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Ramesh was late to work because he missed the ___.",
    "choice_1": "lunch",
    "choice_2": "bus",
    "choice_3": "meeting",
    "choice_4": "call",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Missing the bus is a common reason for being late.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The flowers in the garden look very ___.",
    "choice_1": "dull",
    "choice_2": "fresh",
    "choice_3": "dead",
    "choice_4": "dry",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Healthy garden flowers are usually fresh.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "He was very ___ after winning the match.",
    "choice_1": "sad",
    "choice_2": "bored",
    "choice_3": "angry",
    "choice_4": "happy",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Winning a match makes people happy.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The teacher gave the students a ___ to read during the holidays.",
    "choice_1": "punishment",
    "choice_2": "novel",
    "choice_3": "test",
    "choice_4": "bill",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A novel is something to read for enjoyment.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The athlete’s ___ training helped him win the championship.",
    "choice_1": "lazy",
    "choice_2": "irregular",
    "choice_3": "rigorous",
    "choice_4": "short",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Rigorous means intense and fits championship preparation.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "They decided to ___ the old building instead of demolishing it.",
    "choice_1": "paint",
    "choice_2": "ignore",
    "choice_3": "restore",
    "choice_4": "abandon",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Restore means repair or renovate.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The scientist was awarded for his ___ contributions to medicine.",
    "choice_1": "ordinary",
    "choice_2": "minor",
    "choice_3": "insignificant",
    "choice_4": "remarkable",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Remarkable means exceptional and fits with winning an award.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The child showed great ___ while dealing with the difficult puzzle.",
    "choice_1": "patience",
    "choice_2": "anger",
    "choice_3": "disgust",
    "choice_4": "sadness",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Patience is needed to solve difficult puzzles.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Despite his ___ efforts, he could not solve the mystery.",
    "choice_1": "relaxed",
    "choice_2": "casual",
    "choice_3": "lazy",
    "choice_4": "tireless",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Tireless means persistent, fits with trying hard but failing.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The committee reached a ___ after hours of intense discussion.",
    "choice_1": "conflict",
    "choice_2": "quarrel",
    "choice_3": "deadlock",
    "choice_4": "consensus",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Consensus means general agreement.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The medicine had a ___ effect on the patient’s recovery.",
    "choice_1": "harmful",
    "choice_2": "negligible",
    "choice_3": "transformative",
    "choice_4": "negative",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Transformative means causing major positive change.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Her writing style is known for its ___ and clarity.",
    "choice_1": "confusion",
    "choice_2": "simplicity",
    "choice_3": "complexity",
    "choice_4": "ambiguity",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Simplicity and clarity go together.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "The environmental policy was implemented to ___ the negative effects of pollution.",
    "choice_1": "increase",
    "choice_2": "worsen",
    "choice_3": "mitigate",
    "choice_4": "expand",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Mitigate means reduce or lessen.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "He gave a ___ apology, but no one believed his sincerity.",
    "choice_1": "heartfelt",
    "choice_2": "genuine",
    "choice_3": "superficial",
    "choice_4": "sincere",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Superficial means shallow, which is why people did not believe him.",
    "Topic": "Sentence completion-2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph:  A) In simpler terms, it is the Indian version of the Razzies.  B) The 3rd Golden Kela Awards will be hosted by Cyrus Broacha this year.  C) It was created in order to ridicule the bad performances and as a revenge for wasting our precious time and money on such idiotic films.  D) The Golden Kela is held each year where awards are given for the year's worst in Bollywood. E) It was created by Random magazine, India's longest running humor magazine in the year 2009.",
    "choice_1": "DAECB",
    "choice_2": "BACDE",
    "choice_3": "ACEDB",
    "choice_4": "CEADB",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Para Jumble"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph:  A) Despite the strong performance of the economy in 2010-11, the outlook for 2011-12 is clouded by stubborn and persistently high inflation, and rising external risks. B) The three key macroeconomic concerns before the Union Budget 2011-12 were high inflation, high current account deficit (CAD), and fiscal consolidation. C) Additionally, there was an expectation that the government would restart the reform process. D) While the Budget sets a lower nominal gross domestic product (GDP) growth target of 14%, we believe that the real GDP growth target of 9% factored in the Budget is on the optimistic side.  E) The Budget has made an attempt to address all these issues, albeit through small steps.",
    "choice_1": "BCEAD",
    "choice_2": "CBAED",
    "choice_3": "DACEB",
    "choice_4": "ADCEB",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Para Jumble"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph: A) These were mainly bulwarks against winter, the hoarded dregs of more plentiful seasons. B) The first were the earliest mince pies, which saw cooked, shredded meat, dried fruits, alcohol with its preservative qualities and perhaps a few spices or herbs, all encased in large pies. C) Subsequently, people baked this into a kind of pie, adding bread-crumbs for bulk, eggs to bind it, and upping the dried fruits and called it 'plum pudding'. D) The pudding seems to have had two principal forerunners. E) The second main pudding was a pottage or soup called frumenty, a fast dish involving cracked wheat, currants and almonds which was ladled out at the start of a meal.",
    "choice_1": "ECDAB",
    "choice_2": "BAECD",
    "choice_3": "DACEB",
    "choice_4": "DBAEC",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Para Jumble"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph:  A) In a bid to placate the associate members, the ICC has decided to increase the number of participating teams to 16 in the Twenty20 World Cup, as the game's governing body feels these countries will have a greater chance of competing on an equal footing in cricket's shortest format. B) It is convenient just now to forget that in the last edition of the tournament, considerable criticism was heaped on the governing body for the inordinate length of the tournament, thanks in large part to the presence of the associates. C) To be fair to the ICC, criticism of the move to restrict the number of teams in the next edition of the Cup is a case of damned if you do, damned if you don't. D) The ICC's decision to restrict the number of teams in the 2015 World Cup has evoked mixed responses, with opinion divided among players of the full member teams. E) Not surprisingly, the associate members aren't too thrilled about the idea of being kept out of cricket's showpiece event.",
    "choice_1": "ECDAB",
    "choice_2": "BAECD",
    "choice_3": "DACEB",
    "choice_4": "DEACB",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Para Jumble"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph: A) Environment Education unit of Centre for Science & Environment has always been working towards providing easy to understand reading material. B) Their new publication on this subject is an attempt to lend teachers a helping hand. C) It unfolds in two sections: Climate change: how to make sense of it all. D) And natural resources how to share & care. E) However, they are introduced to students not as a paragraph to memorize but as an activity to do.",
    "choice_1": "ACEBD",
    "choice_2": "DBCAE",
    "choice_3": "ABCDE",
    "choice_4": "BECAD",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Para Jumble"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph: A) A famous Japanese rock garden is at Ryoan-Ji in Northwest Kyoto, Japan. B) The rocks of various sizes are arranged on small white pebbles in five groups, each comprising five, two, three, two, & three rocks. C) The garden is 30 meters long from East to West & 10 meters from north to south. D) The garden contains 15 rocks arranged on the surface of white pebbles in such a manner that visitors can see only 14 of them at once from whichever angle the garden is viewed. E) There are no trees, just 15 irregularly shaped rocks of varying sizes, some arranged by gravel/sand that is raked everyday.",
    "choice_1": "ACEBD",
    "choice_2": "CAEDB",
    "choice_3": "SEABC",
    "choice_4": "BADEC",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Para Jumble"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph: A) The post-election crisis in Kenya remains unresolved. B) The damage being done to the country's economy is severe: tourism, horticulture, and other industries that depend on trade beyond the Kenyan border are reeling. C) Many countries responded, providing essential humanitarian assistance and logistical support. For this, I and many other Kenyans are very grateful. D) Thousands of livelihoods, along with investments throughout the region, are threatened and collapsing. E) As the situation in Kenya escalated with murders, rapes, burning of property, looting, and the displacement of thousands of people throughout the country - the international community was urged to help.",
    "choice_1": "AEDBC",
    "choice_2": "ABCED",
    "choice_3": "ACDEB",
    "choice_4": "ABDEC",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Para Jumble"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph: A) The US market will continue to be the dominant one in the foreseeable future. The rupee could become even stronger. B) A greater recourse to hedging as well as striving for multi-currency revenue streams automatically suggests itself. C) Already one company, TCS, by resorting to these methods extensively has turned in an above - average performance during the first quarter. D)Most IT companies have been grappling with more mundane problems such as a high level of attrition amidst rising wage costs and inability to secure the right type and number of American visas. E) The BPO industry and many medium-sized software exporters are reportedly operating on thin margins.",
    "choice_1": "BCADE",
    "choice_2": "ABCDE",
    "choice_3": "DCBAE",
    "choice_4": "EDABC",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Para Jumble"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph: A) Last March, I was invited to present a paper on the topic of whether the mistakes of the 20th century would be repeated in the 21st century as well. B) The economic crisis hadn't become grave then. C) But today the world is in the midst of the biggest economic crisis since 1929. D) The key difference between then and now is that the old power structures have finally disappeared. E) Now even the US is pleading for financial help from China.",
    "choice_1": "BCADE",
    "choice_2": "ABCDE",
    "choice_3": "CDEAB",
    "choice_4": "DEABC",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Para Jumble"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph: A) Thus, despite India's huge population, we have not done well in Olympic Games. B) During the British period also, cricket remained popular in India. C) Cricket has been an extremely popular game in India for quite some time now. D) It is time our government and corporate fraternity pay due attention to other games/sports and we redeem our national pride in Olympic Games. E) However, due to this reason, other games/sports did not receive the required attention they deserve.",
    "choice_1": "EACDB",
    "choice_2": "BDACE",
    "choice_3": "CBEAD",
    "choice_4": "DCEAB",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Para Jumble"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph:                                                      A. The Cold War was underpinned by an understanding which allowed the US to maintain hegemony over the capitalist world and which gave the Soviet Union a regional sphere of influence in Eastern Europe.\n\nB. The bloody upheavals and wars occurred not in Europe, America or Russia, but in Asia, Africa and the Middle East, and were either directly or indirectly a response to the experience of Western colonialism.\n\nC. Despite the aggressive rhetoric of this era, the Cold War was a period of relative peace between hostile geopolitical blocs.\n\nD. In retrospect, what was remarkable about the Cold War was the ability of most of the major players to manage their conflict.",
    "choice_1": "ADCB",
    "choice_2": "DBCAE",
    "choice_3": "CBDA",
    "choice_4": "BADC",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "ParaJumbles"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph:                                                                           A. The Mandate of Heaven indicated divine approval of a king’s right to rule.\n\nB. In other words, the Mandate of Heaven gave divine ruling authority to kings that lived a moral life, administered justice, and protected the welfare of his people.\n\nC. Whereas Medieval Europeans legitimized their ruling authority by the divine right of kings, Confucian societies used a similar concept called the Mandate of Heaven.\n\nD. However, it differed from the divine right of kings in that Heaven’s endorsement depends upon the virtuous conduct of the ruler.",
    "choice_1": "ABCD",
    "choice_2": "ABDC",
    "choice_3": "CDAB",
    "choice_4": "CADB",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "ParaJumbles"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph: A. Hate speech is characterized by a deliberate targeting of communities rather than beliefs.\n\nB. What the management must seek to do is to not let political discussions and debates to descend into vituperative attacks and hate speech.\n\nC. But such an association will be spurious, as questioning orthodoxy and conservatism is not tantamount to hate speech.\n\nD. The student body's activism has been criticized by detractors and it has been sought to be associated with hate speech.",
    "choice_1": "BACD",
    "choice_2": "ACDB",
    "choice_3": "DBCA",
    "choice_4": "DCAB",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "ParaJumbles"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph:  A. The crash in the Alps has launched a search for a solution to the problem of accessing the cockpit from outside if the plane has been commandeered from within.\n\nB. Flight safety has so far focused on threats from the passenger side, and the 9/11 terror episode led to fortification of the cockpit.\n\nC. But if they are in a position to act, pilots can override this mechanism.\n\nD. In exceptional circumstances, such as an emergency affecting the pilot and the cockpit area, the crew can use a code that opens the cockpit door briefly, or it even opens automatically if the pilots are immobilized due to depressurization.",
    "choice_1": "ABCD",
    "choice_2": "BDCA",
    "choice_3": "BADC",
    "choice_4": "ADCB",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "ParaJumbles"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Arrange the following sentences to form a coherent paragraph: A. According to scientists from NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory, the current melting of ice in Greenland is already causing the tilt to change at a rate of approximately 2.6 cm each year.\n\nB. While a natural event such as this could bring about major changes to the climate, some scientists are warning that there is a possibility for reverse feedback.\n\nC. The Earth's orbital tilt is said to vary between 22 and 25 degrees roughly every 41,000 years.\n\nD. In other words, instead of an orbital tilt causing climate change, current changes in climate could end up causing changes in the Earth's axial tilt.",
    "choice_1": "ABCD",
    "choice_2": "CDBA",
    "choice_3": "CBDA",
    "choice_4": "ABDC",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "ParaJumbles"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.    \n\n       If a person suddenly encounters any terrible danger, the change of nature one undergoes is equally great. Sometimes fear numbs our senses. Like animals, one stands still, powerless to move a step in fright or to lift a hand in defense of our lives, and sometimes one is seized with panic, and again, act more like the inferior animals than rational beings. On the other hand, frequently in cases of sudden extreme peril, which cannot be escaped by flight, and must be instantly faced, even the most timid men at once as if by miracle, become possessed of the necessary courage, sharp quick apprehension and swift decision. This is a miracle very common in nature. Man and the inferior animals alike, when confronted with almost certain death ‘ gather resolution from despair’ but there can really be no trace of so debilitating a feeling in the person fighting, or prepared to fight for dear life. At such times the mind is clearer than it has ever been; the nerves are steel, there is nothing felt but a wonderful strength and daring. Looking back at certain perilous moments in my own life, I remember them with a kind of joy, not that there was any joyful excitement then, but because they broadened my horizon, lifted me for a time above myself. \nQUESTION : The title that best suits the passage would be?",
    "choice_1": "The Will to Fight",
    "choice_2": "The Miracle of Confronting Danger",
    "choice_3": "The Change of Nature",
    "choice_4": "Courage and Panic",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "This best captures the essence of the passage. In case one is faced with sudden danger, even the man who is shy gets the courage to face the situation as it has further been discussed in the lines “Frequently in cases.......in nature.”",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.    \n\n       If a person suddenly encounters any terrible danger, the change of nature one undergoes is equally great. Sometimes fear numbs our senses. Like animals, one stands still, powerless to move a step in fright or to lift a hand in defense of our lives, and sometimes one is seized with panic, and again, act more like the inferior animals than rational beings. On the other hand, frequently in cases of sudden extreme peril, which cannot be escaped by flight, and must be instantly faced, even the most timid men at once as if by miracle, become possessed of the necessary courage, sharp quick apprehension and swift decision. This is a miracle very common in nature. Man and the inferior animals alike, when confronted with almost certain death ‘ gather resolution from despair’ but there can really be no trace of so debilitating a feeling in the person fighting, or prepared to fight for dear life. At such times the mind is clearer than it has ever been; the nerves are steel, there is nothing felt but a wonderful strength and daring. Looking back at certain perilous moments in my own life, I remember them with a kind of joy, not that there was any joyful excitement then, but because they broadened my horizon, lifted me for a time above myself. \nQUESTION :  A man may react to sudden danger in three different ways. What are they?",
    "choice_1": "He may flee in panic, or fight back or stand still.",
    "choice_2": "He may be paralysed with fear, seized with panic or act like an inferior animal.",
    "choice_3": "He may be paralysed with fear, or seized with panic, or as if by miracle, become possessed of the necessary courage, and face the danger.",
    "choice_4": "He may be paralysed with fear, run away or fight.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "The paragraph clearly identifies 3 ways:\nSometimes fear numbs our senses. Like animals, one stands still, powerless to move a step in fright or to lift a hand in defense of our lives,\nand sometimes one is seized with panic, and again, act more like the inferior animals than rational beings.\nOn the other hand, frequently in cases of sudden extreme peril, which cannot be escaped by flight, and must be instantly faced, even the most timid men at once as if by miracle, become possessed of the necessary courage, sharp quick apprehension and swift decision.",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.    \n\n       If a person suddenly encounters any terrible danger, the change of nature one undergoes is equally great. Sometimes fear numbs our senses. Like animals, one stands still, powerless to move a step in fright or to lift a hand in defense of our lives, and sometimes one is seized with panic, and again, act more like the inferior animals than rational beings. On the other hand, frequently in cases of sudden extreme peril, which cannot be escaped by flight, and must be instantly faced, even the most timid men at once as if by miracle, become possessed of the necessary courage, sharp quick apprehension and swift decision. This is a miracle very common in nature. Man and the inferior animals alike, when confronted with almost certain death ‘ gather resolution from despair’ but there can really be no trace of so debilitating a feeling in the person fighting, or prepared to fight for dear life. At such times the mind is clearer than it has ever been; the nerves are steel, there is nothing felt but a wonderful strength and daring. Looking back at certain perilous moments in my own life, I remember them with a kind of joy, not that there was any joyful excitement then, but because they broadened my horizon, lifted me for a time above myself. \nQUESTION : What is the meaning of the word debilitating?",
    "choice_1": "enfeeble",
    "choice_2": "strengthen",
    "choice_3": "debase",
    "choice_4": "thriving",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The word “enfeeble” means to make weak or feeble.",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.    \n\n       If a person suddenly encounters any terrible danger, the change of nature one undergoes is equally great. Sometimes fear numbs our senses. Like animals, one stands still, powerless to move a step in fright or to lift a hand in defense of our lives, and sometimes one is seized with panic, and again, act more like the inferior animals than rational beings. On the other hand, frequently in cases of sudden extreme peril, which cannot be escaped by flight, and must be instantly faced, even the most timid men at once as if by miracle, become possessed of the necessary courage, sharp quick apprehension and swift decision. This is a miracle very common in nature. Man and the inferior animals alike, when confronted with almost certain death ‘ gather resolution from despair’ but there can really be no trace of so debilitating a feeling in the person fighting, or prepared to fight for dear life. At such times the mind is clearer than it has ever been; the nerves are steel, there is nothing felt but a wonderful strength and daring. Looking back at certain perilous moments in my own life, I remember them with a kind of joy, not that there was any joyful excitement then, but because they broadened my horizon, lifted me for a time above myself. \nQUESTION :  The author feels happy in the recollection of dangers faced and overcome because?",
    "choice_1": "They brought him a new experience.",
    "choice_2": "They added a new perspective and lifted him above himself for a time.",
    "choice_3": "These experiences boosted his confidence.",
    "choice_4": "He felt elated as he was alive.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "It is mentioned in the last few lines.",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.    \n\n       If a person suddenly encounters any terrible danger, the change of nature one undergoes is equally great. Sometimes fear numbs our senses. Like animals, one stands still, powerless to move a step in fright or to lift a hand in defense of our lives, and sometimes one is seized with panic, and again, act more like the inferior animals than rational beings. On the other hand, frequently in cases of sudden extreme peril, which cannot be escaped by flight, and must be instantly faced, even the most timid men at once as if by miracle, become possessed of the necessary courage, sharp quick apprehension and swift decision. This is a miracle very common in nature. Man and the inferior animals alike, when confronted with almost certain death ‘ gather resolution from despair’ but there can really be no trace of so debilitating a feeling in the person fighting, or prepared to fight for dear life. At such times the mind is clearer than it has ever been; the nerves are steel, there is nothing felt but a wonderful strength and daring. Looking back at certain perilous moments in my own life, I remember them with a kind of joy, not that there was any joyful excitement then, but because they broadened my horizon, lifted me for a time above myself. \nQUESTION :   Explain the phrase ‘gather resolution from danger’.",
    "choice_1": "Find peace in times of difficulty.",
    "choice_2": "A state of utter hopelessness makes one determined to face the difficulty.",
    "choice_3": "To remain calm and not to lose hope.",
    "choice_4": "To be enthusiastic and brave the odds.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "It means that in times of difficulty one gathers courage to make decisions. The word ‘resolution’ means the act of resolving or determining upon an action or course of action.",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.     \n\n        The object underlying the rules of natural justice \"is to prevent miscarriage of justice\" ans secure \"fair play in action\" As pointed out earlier the requirement about recording of reasons for its decision by an administrative authority exercising quasi-judicial functions achieves his object by excluding changes of arbitrariness and ensuring a degree of fairness in the process of decision making. Keeping in view the expanding horizon of the principle of natural justice which govern exercise of power by administrative authorities. The rules of natural justice are not embodied rules. The extent of their application depends upon the particularly statutory framework where under jurisdication has been conferred on the administrative authority. with regard to the exercise of particular power by an administrative authority including exercise of judicial or quasi-judicial functions the legislature, while conferring the said power, may feel that it would not be in the larger public interest that the reasons for the order passed by the administrative authority be recorded in the order and be communicated to the aggrieved party and it may dispense with such a requirement.\nQUESTION :  The rules of the natural justice are not embodied rules\" means that these rules are:",
    "choice_1": "are left deliberately vague",
    "choice_2": "cannot be satisfactorily interpreted",
    "choice_3": "are flexible",
    "choice_4": "cannot be visualised",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.     \n\n        The object underlying the rules of natural justice \"is to prevent miscarriage of justice\" ans secure \"fair play in action\" As pointed out earlier the requirement about recording of reasons for its decision by an administrative authority exercising quasi-judicial functions achieves his object by excluding changes of arbitrariness and ensuring a degree of fairness in the process of decision making. Keeping in view the expanding horizon of the principle of natural justice which govern exercise of power by administrative authorities. The rules of natural justice are not embodied rules. The extent of their application depends upon the particularly statutory framework where under jurisdication has been conferred on the administrative authority. with regard to the exercise of particular power by an administrative authority including exercise of judicial or quasi-judicial functions the legislature, while conferring the said power, may feel that it would not be in the larger public interest that the reasons for the order passed by the administrative authority be recorded in the order and be communicated to the aggrieved party and it may dispense with such a requirement.\nQUESTION : From the passage it is clear that it is the legislature that:",
    "choice_1": "invests the administrative authority with enormous powers",
    "choice_2": "embodies rules",
    "choice_3": "has the larger interests of public welfare",
    "choice_4": "leaves administrative authority enough discretion to interpret rules",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.     \n\n        The object underlying the rules of natural justice \"is to prevent miscarriage of justice\" ans secure \"fair play in action\" As pointed out earlier the requirement about recording of reasons for its decision by an administrative authority exercising quasi-judicial functions achieves his object by excluding changes of arbitrariness and ensuring a degree of fairness in the process of decision making. Keeping in view the expanding horizon of the principle of natural justice which govern exercise of power by administrative authorities. The rules of natural justice are not embodied rules. The extent of their application depends upon the particularly statutory framework where under jurisdication has been conferred on the administrative authority. with regard to the exercise of particular power by an administrative authority including exercise of judicial or quasi-judicial functions the legislature, while conferring the said power, may feel that it would not be in the larger public interest that the reasons for the order passed by the administrative authority be recorded in the order and be communicated to the aggrieved party and it may dispense with such a requirement.\nQUESTION :  According to the passage, there is always a gap between:",
    "choice_1": "rules of natural justice and their application",
    "choice_2": "conception of a rule and its concretisation",
    "choice_3": "demand for natural justice and its realisation",
    "choice_4": "intention and execution",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.     \n\n        The object underlying the rules of natural justice \"is to prevent miscarriage of justice\" ans secure \"fair play in action\" As pointed out earlier the requirement about recording of reasons for its decision by an administrative authority exercising quasi-judicial functions achieves his object by excluding changes of arbitrariness and ensuring a degree of fairness in the process of decision making. Keeping in view the expanding horizon of the principle of natural justice which govern exercise of power by administrative authorities. The rules of natural justice are not embodied rules. The extent of their application depends upon the particularly statutory framework where under jurisdication has been conferred on the administrative authority. with regard to the exercise of particular power by an administrative authority including exercise of judicial or quasi-judicial functions the legislature, while conferring the said power, may feel that it would not be in the larger public interest that the reasons for the order passed by the administrative authority be recorded in the order and be communicated to the aggrieved party and it may dispense with such a requirement.\nQUESTION :  \"To dispense with a requirement\" means-",
    "choice_1": "to do without the demand",
    "choice_2": "to drop the charge",
    "choice_3": "to cancel all formal procedure",
    "choice_4": "to alter the provisions of the case",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.     \n\n        The object underlying the rules of natural justice \"is to prevent miscarriage of justice\" ans secure \"fair play in action\" As pointed out earlier the requirement about recording of reasons for its decision by an administrative authority exercising quasi-judicial functions achieves his object by excluding changes of arbitrariness and ensuring a degree of fairness in the process of decision making. Keeping in view the expanding horizon of the principle of natural justice which govern exercise of power by administrative authorities. The rules of natural justice are not embodied rules. The extent of their application depends upon the particularly statutory framework where under jurisdication has been conferred on the administrative authority. with regard to the exercise of particular power by an administrative authority including exercise of judicial or quasi-judicial functions the legislature, while conferring the said power, may feel that it would not be in the larger public interest that the reasons for the order passed by the administrative authority be recorded in the order and be communicated to the aggrieved party and it may dispense with such a requirement.\nQUESTION :  According to the passage, natural justice can be brought about by",
    "choice_1": "administrative authority remaining vigilant",
    "choice_2": "administrative authority upholding rules of natural justice",
    "choice_3": "administrative authority farming rules suitably",
    "choice_4": "administrative authority observing the rules of fair play",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.     \n\n        A fact that draws our attention is that, according to his position in life, an extravagant man is either admired or loathed. A successful business man does nothing to increase his popularity by being prudent with his money. A person who is wealthy is expected to lead a luxurious life and to be lavish with his hospitality. If he is not so, he is considered mean, and his reputation in business may even suffer in consequence. The paradox remains that he had not been careful with his money in the first place; he would never have achieved his present wealth.\nAmong the low income group, a different set of values exists. The young clerk, who makes his wife a present of a new dress when he has not paid his house rent, is condemned as extravagant. Carefulness with money to the point of meanness is applauded as a virtue. Nothing in his life is considered more worthy than paying his bills. The ideal wife for such a man separates her housekeeping money into joyless little piles – so much for rent, for food, for the children’s shoes, she is able to face the milkman with equanimity every, month satisfied with her economizing ways , and never knows the guilt of buying something she can’t really afford .\nAs for myself, I fall neither of these categories. If I have money to spare I can be extravagant, but when, as is usually the case, I am hard up and then I am the meanest man imaginable.                                \nQuestion : Which of the following would be the most appropriate title for the passage:",
    "choice_1": "Being extravagant is always condemnable.",
    "choice_2": "The cause of poverty is extravagance.",
    "choice_3": "Extravagance is a part of the rich as well as of the poor.",
    "choice_4": "Stingy habits of the poor.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "This is the most appropriate title as the author sheds light on the life of a rich person in the first paragraph and discusses the life of a person who belongs to lower strata of the society in the second paragraph.",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.     \n\n        A fact that draws our attention is that, according to his position in life, an extravagant man is either admired or loathed. A successful business man does nothing to increase his popularity by being prudent with his money. A person who is wealthy is expected to lead a luxurious life and to be lavish with his hospitality. If he is not so, he is considered mean, and his reputation in business may even suffer in consequence. The paradox remains that he had not been careful with his money in the first place; he would never have achieved his present wealth.\nAmong the low income group, a different set of values exists. The young clerk, who makes his wife a present of a new dress when he has not paid his house rent, is condemned as extravagant. Carefulness with money to the point of meanness is applauded as a virtue. Nothing in his life is considered more worthy than paying his bills. The ideal wife for such a man separates her housekeeping money into joyless little piles – so much for rent, for food, for the children’s shoes, she is able to face the milkman with equanimity every, month satisfied with her economizing ways , and never knows the guilt of buying something she can’t really afford .\nAs for myself, I fall neither of these categories. If I have money to spare I can be extravagant, but when, as is usually the case, I am hard up and then I am the meanest man imaginable.                                \nQuestion : According to the passage the person, who is a successful businessman and wealthy",
    "choice_1": "Is expected to have lavish lifestyle.",
    "choice_2": "Should not bother about popularity.",
    "choice_3": "Is more popular if he appears to be wasting away his time.",
    "choice_4": "Must be extravagant before achieving success.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "It is given in the fourth line of the 1st paragraph.:“If he .........consequence.”",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.     \n\n        A fact that draws our attention is that, according to his position in life, an extravagant man is either admired or loathed. A successful business man does nothing to increase his popularity by being prudent with his money. A person who is wealthy is expected to lead a luxurious life and to be lavish with his hospitality. If he is not so, he is considered mean, and his reputation in business may even suffer in consequence. The paradox remains that he had not been careful with his money in the first place; he would never have achieved his present wealth.\nAmong the low income group, a different set of values exists. The young clerk, who makes his wife a present of a new dress when he has not paid his house rent, is condemned as extravagant. Carefulness with money to the point of meanness is applauded as a virtue. Nothing in his life is considered more worthy than paying his bills. The ideal wife for such a man separates her housekeeping money into joyless little piles – so much for rent, for food, for the children’s shoes, she is able to face the milkman with equanimity every, month satisfied with her economizing ways , and never knows the guilt of buying something she can’t really afford .\nAs for myself, I fall neither of these categories. If I have money to spare I can be extravagant, but when, as is usually the case, I am hard up and then I am the meanest man imaginable.                                \nQuestion : The phrase ‘lavish with his hospitality’ in the third sentence of the first paragraph means",
    "choice_1": "Thoughtful in spending only on guests and strangers.",
    "choice_2": "Unconcerned in treating his friends and relatives.",
    "choice_3": "Stinginess in dealing with his relatives.",
    "choice_4": "Extravagance in entertaining guest.",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "The meaning of the word “hospitality” is the quality or disposition of receiving and treating guests and strangers in a warm, friendly, generous way which justifies that option d is the correct answer choice.",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.     \n\n        A fact that draws our attention is that, according to his position in life, an extravagant man is either admired or loathed. A successful business man does nothing to increase his popularity by being prudent with his money. A person who is wealthy is expected to lead a luxurious life and to be lavish with his hospitality. If he is not so, he is considered mean, and his reputation in business may even suffer in consequence. The paradox remains that he had not been careful with his money in the first place; he would never have achieved his present wealth.\nAmong the low income group, a different set of values exists. The young clerk, who makes his wife a present of a new dress when he has not paid his house rent, is condemned as extravagant. Carefulness with money to the point of meanness is applauded as a virtue. Nothing in his life is considered more worthy than paying his bills. The ideal wife for such a man separates her housekeeping money into joyless little piles – so much for rent, for food, for the children’s shoes, she is able to face the milkman with equanimity every, month satisfied with her economizing ways , and never knows the guilt of buying something she can’t really afford .\nAs for myself, I fall neither of these categories. If I have money to spare I can be extravagant, but when, as is usually the case, I am hard up and then I am the meanest man imaginable.                                \nQuestion : The word ‘paradox’ in the last sentence of the first paragraph means",
    "choice_1": "Statement based on the popular opinion",
    "choice_2": "a statement that seems self-contradictory but in reality expresses a possible truth.",
    "choice_3": "Statement based on facts",
    "choice_4": "A word that brings out the hidden meaning",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The meaning of the word “paradox” is given in option B and it is also explained in the last sentence of the first paragraph.",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Read the passage and answer the question based on it.     \n\n        A fact that draws our attention is that, according to his position in life, an extravagant man is either admired or loathed. A successful business man does nothing to increase his popularity by being prudent with his money. A person who is wealthy is expected to lead a luxurious life and to be lavish with his hospitality. If he is not so, he is considered mean, and his reputation in business may even suffer in consequence. The paradox remains that he had not been careful with his money in the first place; he would never have achieved his present wealth.\nAmong the low income group, a different set of values exists. The young clerk, who makes his wife a present of a new dress when he has not paid his house rent, is condemned as extravagant. Carefulness with money to the point of meanness is applauded as a virtue. Nothing in his life is considered more worthy than paying his bills. The ideal wife for such a man separates her housekeeping money into joyless little piles – so much for rent, for food, for the children’s shoes, she is able to face the milkman with equanimity every, month satisfied with her economizing ways , and never knows the guilt of buying something she can’t really afford .\nAs for myself, I fall neither of these categories. If I have money to spare I can be extravagant, but when, as is usually the case, I am hard up and then I am the meanest man imaginable.                                \nQuestion : What is the meaning of the word “equanimity”?",
    "choice_1": "Calmness",
    "choice_2": "Discomposure",
    "choice_3": "Equivocal",
    "choice_4": "Dubious",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The word “equanimity” means mental or emotional stability or composure, especially under tension or strain as can further be understood as in this example “Raj was a man of great equanimity, even when talking about his own death.”",
    "Topic": "Reading Comprehension"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of these is a simple sentence?",
    "choice_1": "The boy ran.",
    "choice_2": "Although he was late.",
    "choice_3": "Because he was tired.",
    "choice_4": "Unless he finishes.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "A simple sentence has a subject and predicate and expresses a complete thought.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which is a correct use of a capital letter?",
    "choice_1": "my name is Rahul.",
    "choice_2": "rahul lives in India.",
    "choice_3": "Rahul lives in India.",
    "choice_4": "rahul Lives in india.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Proper nouns and countries start with a capital letter.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which is correct punctuation for a question?",
    "choice_1": "Where are you.",
    "choice_2": "Where are you!",
    "choice_3": "Where are you,",
    "choice_4": "Where are you?",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "A question ends with a question mark.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which word is spelled correctly?",
    "choice_1": "Recieve",
    "choice_2": "Receive",
    "choice_3": "Recive",
    "choice_4": "Receeve",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "i before e except after c: receive is correct.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is a synonym of “happy”?",
    "choice_1": "Sad",
    "choice_2": "Angry",
    "choice_3": "Joyful",
    "choice_4": "Tired",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "“Joyful” means the same as “happy.”",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the main purpose of a conclusion in writing?",
    "choice_1": "Introduce ideas",
    "choice_2": "Summarize and close",
    "choice_3": "Add new data",
    "choice_4": "Ask questions",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The conclusion wraps up the writing by summarizing key points.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is a transition word?",
    "choice_1": "A spelling mistake",
    "choice_2": "A topic sentence",
    "choice_3": "A connecting word",
    "choice_4": "A punctuation mark",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Transition words connect ideas (e.g., however, therefore).",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Choose the correctly punctuated sentence.",
    "choice_1": "She likes apples, oranges and bananas.",
    "choice_2": "She likes apples oranges, and bananas.",
    "choice_3": "She likes apples, oranges, and bananas.",
    "choice_4": "She likes apples oranges and, bananas.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Use commas in a list, including the serial (Oxford) comma.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence is in passive voice?",
    "choice_1": "The dog bit the man.",
    "choice_2": "The man was bitten by the dog.",
    "choice_3": "The dog bites.",
    "choice_4": "The man bites the dog.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "In passive voice, the subject receives the action.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which is a strong thesis statement?",
    "choice_1": "I will talk about pollution.",
    "choice_2": "Pollution is a problem.",
    "choice_3": "Pollution affects health, so stricter laws are needed.",
    "choice_4": "Pollution is everywhere.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "A strong thesis states a clear argument.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which is a run-on sentence?",
    "choice_1": "He went home, he was tired.",
    "choice_2": "He went home because he was tired.",
    "choice_3": "He went home. He was tired.",
    "choice_4": "He went home; he was tired.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Two independent clauses joined with just a comma is a run-on (comma splice).",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the function of a topic sentence?",
    "choice_1": "Concludes the essay",
    "choice_2": "Gives evidence",
    "choice_3": "Introduces a paragraph's main idea",
    "choice_4": "Provides statistics",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "A topic sentence states the paragraph’s main idea.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Choose the best revision for clarity: “Having finished the assignment, the TV was turned on.”",
    "choice_1": "After finishing the assignment, he turned on the TV.",
    "choice_2": "Finishing assignment, turned on TV.",
    "choice_3": "TV on after assignment done.",
    "choice_4": "Finished, the assignment, the TV was on.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The dangling modifier is corrected by specifying the person.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which shows correct parallel structure?",
    "choice_1": "She likes dancing, to sing, and to swim.",
    "choice_2": "She likes to dance, singing, and to swim.",
    "choice_3": "She likes dancing, singing, and swimming.",
    "choice_4": "She likes to dance, singing, swimming.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Parallelism means the same grammatical form (all -ing).",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which is a correct use of a semicolon?",
    "choice_1": "I like apples; and oranges.",
    "choice_2": "I like apples; I also like oranges.",
    "choice_3": "I like apples; but oranges.",
    "choice_4": "I like apples; oranges and bananas.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A semicolon can join two related independent clauses.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of these is a compound sentence?",
    "choice_1": "I went home and slept.",
    "choice_2": "While I went home.",
    "choice_3": "Because I was tired.",
    "choice_4": "Unless he finishes.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Compound sentences join two independent clauses with a conjunction.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which word needs a capital letter? 'my uncle lives in paris.'",
    "choice_1": "uncle",
    "choice_2": "my",
    "choice_3": "lives",
    "choice_4": "paris",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Uncle' is a proper noun in this context and needs a capital letter.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which is correct punctuation for exclamation?",
    "choice_1": "What a great show?",
    "choice_2": "What a great show!",
    "choice_3": "What a great show.",
    "choice_4": "What a great show,",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "An exclamation ends with an exclamation mark.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which word is spelled correctly?",
    "choice_1": "Definately",
    "choice_2": "Definate",
    "choice_3": "Definetly",
    "choice_4": "Definete",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Definitely' is spelled correctly; 'Definate' is correct here.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is an antonym of 'honest'?",
    "choice_1": "Brave",
    "choice_2": "Dishonest",
    "choice_3": "Kind",
    "choice_4": "Trustworthy",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Antonym of honest is dishonest.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the purpose of a topic sentence?",
    "choice_1": "Ends the paragraph",
    "choice_2": "States the paragraph’s main idea",
    "choice_3": "Gives evidence",
    "choice_4": "Adds punctuation",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A topic sentence introduces the main idea of the paragraph.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is a supporting detail?",
    "choice_1": "Main idea",
    "choice_2": "Concluding remark",
    "choice_3": "A type of punctuation",
    "choice_4": "A transition word",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Supporting details explain and develop the topic sentence.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Choose the correct use of an apostrophe.",
    "choice_1": "Its raining outside.",
    "choice_2": "It’s raining outside.",
    "choice_3": "Its' raining outside.",
    "choice_4": "Its raining' outside.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "It’s = it is; correct apostrophe usage.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which is a complex sentence?",
    "choice_1": "She sings.",
    "choice_2": "When it rains, she reads books.",
    "choice_3": "They dance every day.",
    "choice_4": "She likes music.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Complex sentences have an independent and dependent clause.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which is a good concluding phrase?",
    "choice_1": "In conclusion,",
    "choice_2": "However,",
    "choice_3": "To conclude,",
    "choice_4": "Firstly,",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "A concluding phrase signals the ending of a text.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which is an example of a misplaced modifier?",
    "choice_1": "He served sandwiches to the children on paper plates.",
    "choice_2": "He served the children sandwiches on paper plates.",
    "choice_3": "On paper plates he served sandwiches to the children.",
    "choice_4": "He served sandwiches on paper plates to the children.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The modifier 'on paper plates' is misplaced, creating confusion.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which is the correct use of a colon?",
    "choice_1": "He likes these fruits, apple, orange, and banana.",
    "choice_2": "He likes these: apple, orange, and banana.",
    "choice_3": "He likes these; apple, orange, and banana.",
    "choice_4": "He likes these, apple; orange, and banana.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Colons introduce lists properly, as in this example.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence is properly punctuated?",
    "choice_1": "My friend, likes to swim, run and play.",
    "choice_2": "My friend likes, to swim, run, and play.",
    "choice_3": "My friend likes to swim run and play.",
    "choice_4": "My friend likes to swim, run, and play.",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "This option uses commas correctly in a series.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which shows correct subject-verb agreement?",
    "choice_1": "The team are winning the match.",
    "choice_2": "The team is winning the match.",
    "choice_3": "The teams is winning the match.",
    "choice_4": "The teams are winning the match.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The team' is singular, so 'is' is correct.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which is a correct use of a dash?",
    "choice_1": "I like pizza — and pasta.",
    "choice_2": "I like pizza, and pasta —",
    "choice_3": "I like pizza - and pasta.",
    "choice_4": "I like pizza and pasta.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Dashes can separate or emphasize parts of a sentence correctly.",
    "Topic": "Writing Skills 2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following best defines analytical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Guessing outcomes",
    "choice_2": "Breaking problems into parts",
    "choice_3": "Relying on intuition",
    "choice_4": "Memorizing facts",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the first step in solving an analytical problem?",
    "choice_1": "Jumping to conclusions",
    "choice_2": "Ignoring the data",
    "choice_3": "Identifying the problem",
    "choice_4": "Finding the solution",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which tool is commonly used in analytical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Calculator",
    "choice_2": "Mind map",
    "choice_3": "Microscope",
    "choice_4": "Paintbrush",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which skill is most associated with analytical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Creativity",
    "choice_2": "Empathy",
    "choice_3": "Critical thinking",
    "choice_4": "Social skills",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What does SWOT stand for in analysis?",
    "choice_1": "Strengths, Weaknesses, Opportunities, Threats",
    "choice_2": "Style, Work, Order, Team",
    "choice_3": "Size, Weight, Output, Time",
    "choice_4": "System, Work, Outlook, Tools",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following helps to make better analytical decisions?",
    "choice_1": "Emotional response",
    "choice_2": "Bias",
    "choice_3": "Data analysis",
    "choice_4": "Quick judgment",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "When analyzing a trend, what is most important?",
    "choice_1": "Popularity",
    "choice_2": "Random guess",
    "choice_3": "Pattern recognition",
    "choice_4": "Peer pressure",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the role of assumptions in analytical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "They are facts",
    "choice_2": "They guide exploration",
    "choice_3": "They prevent thinking",
    "choice_4": "They solve problems",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of these indicates strong analytical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Acting quickly",
    "choice_2": "Questioning information",
    "choice_3": "Avoiding numbers",
    "choice_4": "Agreeing always",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of these is a method of data collection for analysis?",
    "choice_1": "Interview",
    "choice_2": "Guesswork",
    "choice_3": "Assumption",
    "choice_4": "Observation",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "if all squares are rectangles, and this shape is a square, what can you conclude?",
    "choice_1": "this shape is not a rectangle.",
    "choice_2": "this shape is a rectangle",
    "choice_3": "some rectangles are not squares.",
    "choice_4": "insufficient information.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "if all squares are rectangles and this shape is a square, it can be concluded that this shape is also a rectangle. eliminate options A, C and D",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "One-town is north-east to Three-town. a) One-town is two miles north of Two-town. b) Two-town is two miles west of Four-town. c) Three-town is two miles west of Two-town. d) Four-town is south-east of One-town.",
    "choice_1": "A & C",
    "choice_2": "C & B",
    "choice_3": "D & B",
    "choice_4": "A & D",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The correct answer is A & C:\n\n1. One-town is north-east to Three-town: This tells us the relative direction of One-town and Three-town.\n\n2. Analyzing options:\n\n\na) One-town is two miles north of Two-town: This aligns with the information about One-town being north-east of Three-town. If One-town is north of Two-town, it suggests it's also potentially north-east of Two-town in relation to Three-town. So, option a could be true.\nb) Two-town is two miles west of Four-town: This doesn't provide any information about the relative positions of One-town, Three-town, or Two-town. It only refers to a different town (Four-town) not mentioned in the initial statement.\nc) Three-town is two miles west of Two-town: This doesn't contradict the given information about One-town's direction relative to Three-town. However, it doesn't necessarily confirm their exact distance or positions.\nd) Four-town is south-east of One-town: This directly contradicts the original statement that places One-town north-east of Three-town. Since Three-town is north-east of One-town, Four-town cannot be south-east of One-town.\n\n\nTherefore, only options a) and c) are consistent with the provided information about One-town and Three-town. They agree on the relative positioning of One-town being north of Two-town, which aligns with its north-east position relative to Three-town.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Peter has a meeting scheduled after lunch and another one before dinner. He finishes his meeting before dinner earlier than he does his meeting after lunch. Which of the following is true?",
    "choice_1": "Peter’s meeting before dinner happens in the evening.",
    "choice_2": "Peter’s meeting after lunch happens in the morning.",
    "choice_3": "Peter finishes both meetings before evening.",
    "choice_4": "Peter's meeting after lunch happens earlier than the meeting before dinner.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "To evaluate this question, let's analyze the timeline.\nThe meeting after lunch takes place in the afternoon, as lunch typically occurs midday.\nThe meeting before dinner occurs later than the meeting after lunch, likely in the early evening.\nIt is explicitly stated that the meeting before dinner finishes earlier than the meeting after lunch, but that refers to completion times, not when the meetings occur.\nEvaluating the options:\nOption A: Correct. The meeting before dinner happens in the evening, consistent with the typical schedule of having dinner in the late evening.\nOption B: Incorrect. A meeting after lunch cannot happen in the morning, as it would contradict the meaning of \"after lunch.\"\nOption C: Incorrect. Peter does not finish both meetings before evening. While the meeting after lunch may finish in the early afternoon, the meeting before dinner is in the evening.\nOption D: Incorrect. The meeting after lunch happens earlier in the day than the meeting before dinner, so this statement contradicts the facts provided.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "in a row of trees, one tree is fifth from either end of the row how many trees are there:",
    "choice_1": 10,
    "choice_2": 9,
    "choice_3": 12,
    "choice_4": 11,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Three prisoners are told they will be given either a red or blue hat, with colors assigned randomly. They can see each other’s hats but not their own. They must deduce their own hat color without communicating. If at least one guesses correctly, all are freed. What strategy guarantees their freedom?",
    "choice_1": "The oldest prisoner always guesses first",
    "choice_2": "They wait 10 minutes before guessing",
    "choice_3": "They agree that whoever sees two matching hats will say the opposite color",
    "choice_4": "They randomly guess red or blue",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Strategy: If one prisoner sees two hats of the same color, they guess the opposite color.\n\nExample: If Prisoner A sees two red hats, they say \"blue.\"\n\nIf Prisoner A sees one red and one blue, they stay silent, and the others deduce their own hat color logically.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which tool is most appropriate for breaking down a complex problem into smaller, manageable parts?",
    "choice_1": "Bar Chart",
    "choice_2": "Decision Tree",
    "choice_3": "Pie Chart",
    "choice_4": "Histogram",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Decision trees help break complex decisions into smaller, more manageable parts.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following is primarily used to analyze cause and effect in analytical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Fishbone Diagram",
    "choice_2": "Bar Graph",
    "choice_3": "Flowchart",
    "choice_4": "Scatter Plot",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Fishbone (Ishikawa) diagrams are used to find root causes of problems.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which diagram best represents a process or workflow in analytical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Pie Chart",
    "choice_2": "Flowchart",
    "choice_3": "Tree Diagram",
    "choice_4": "Line Graph",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Flowcharts depict sequences and workflows effectively.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which analytical tool helps in exploring all possible combinations in a logical scenario?",
    "choice_1": "Truth Table",
    "choice_2": "Histogram",
    "choice_3": "Scatter Diagram",
    "choice_4": "Pie Chart",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Truth tables are used in logic to evaluate combinations of truth values.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following helps in identifying patterns in large data sets in analytical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Scatter Plot",
    "choice_2": "Line Graph",
    "choice_3": "Decision Tree",
    "choice_4": "Bar Graph",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Scatter plots are used to identify correlations and patterns in data.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which tool would best help analyze similarities and differences across multiple data sets?",
    "choice_1": "Histogram",
    "choice_2": "Line Graph",
    "choice_3": "Venn Diagram",
    "choice_4": "Pie Chart",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Venn diagrams show overlaps and differences between sets.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which tool is used to depict data distribution across categories in analytical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Pie Chart",
    "choice_2": "Line Graph",
    "choice_3": "Histogram",
    "choice_4": "Tree Diagram",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Histograms show frequency distribution across data ranges.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which tool is used for root cause analysis in analytical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Pareto Chart",
    "choice_2": "Flowchart",
    "choice_3": "Fishbone Diagram",
    "choice_4": "Bar Chart",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Fishbone diagrams systematically identify possible causes of a problem.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following tools is best used when exploring outcomes of multiple decisions?",
    "choice_1": "Venn Diagram",
    "choice_2": "Decision Tree",
    "choice_3": "Bar Chart",
    "choice_4": "Scatter Plot",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Decision trees show outcomes of different decisions step-by-step.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which diagram is used to track dependencies in a project or process?",
    "choice_1": "Flowchart",
    "choice_2": "Gantt Chart",
    "choice_3": "Fishbone Diagram",
    "choice_4": "Line Graph",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Gantt charts show tasks over time and how they depend on each other.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If all Bloops are Razzies and all Razzies are Lazzies, are all Bloops definitely Lazzies?",
    "choice_1": "Yes",
    "choice_2": "No",
    "choice_3": "Cannot be determined",
    "choice_4": "Only some Bloops are Lazzies",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "This is a syllogism. If all A are B and all B are C, then all A are C.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the odd one out: Square, Triangle, Rectangle, Circle",
    "choice_1": "Square",
    "choice_2": "Triangle",
    "choice_3": "Circle",
    "choice_4": "Rectangle",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Circle has no sides, others are polygons.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If 1=3, 2=3, 3=5, 4=4, 5=4, then 6=?",
    "choice_1": 3,
    "choice_2": 4,
    "choice_3": 5,
    "choice_4": 6,
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Number of letters in the English word for each number: six = 3 letters → Answer: 3.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which word does not belong: Inch, Kilogram, Centimeter, Yard",
    "choice_1": "Inch",
    "choice_2": "Kilogram",
    "choice_3": "Centimeter",
    "choice_4": "Yard",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "All others are units of length; kilogram is unit of mass.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Select the one that is different: Rose, Lily, Lotus, Cactus",
    "choice_1": "Rose",
    "choice_2": "Lotus",
    "choice_3": "Cactus",
    "choice_4": "Lily",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Cactus is not a flowering plant like the others.",
    "Topic": "Analytical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What does the rebus puzzle “STAND2R” represent?",
    "choice_1": "Stand beside two",
    "choice_2": "Stand together",
    "choice_3": "Stand for",
    "choice_4": "Stand under",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the primary goal of critical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "To find quick solutions",
    "choice_2": "To analyze information objectively",
    "choice_3": "To ignore alternative perspectives",
    "choice_4": "To rely on intuition",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following best describes a critical thinker?",
    "choice_1": "Open to all information",
    "choice_2": "Holds rigid beliefs",
    "choice_3": "Avoids questioning assumptions",
    "choice_4": "Bases decisions on feelings",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which step in critical thinking involves assessing the credibility of information sources?",
    "choice_1": "Problem definition",
    "choice_2": "Source evaluation",
    "choice_3": "Implementing solutions",
    "choice_4": "Idea generation",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What does it mean to \"analyze assumptions\" in critical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Accepting assumptions as true",
    "choice_2": "Ignoring assumptions",
    "choice_3": "Challenging and questioning beliefs",
    "choice_4": "Repeating common beliefs",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following best defines critical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Accepting opinions without questioning",
    "choice_2": "Thinking emotionally about a problem",
    "choice_3": "Analyzing facts to form a judgment",
    "choice_4": "Memorizing information",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Critical thinking involves analyzing facts and forming reasoned judgments.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the first step in the critical thinking process?",
    "choice_1": "Forming a conclusion",
    "choice_2": "Identifying the problem",
    "choice_3": "Ignoring assumptions",
    "choice_4": "Taking action",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The process begins with identifying and clearly defining the problem.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of these is NOT a part of critical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Evaluating arguments",
    "choice_2": "Considering alternative viewpoints",
    "choice_3": "Relying solely on intuition",
    "choice_4": "Drawing logical conclusions",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Relying solely on intuition is not considered part of logical, critical evaluation.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which statement reflects a critical thinking approach?",
    "choice_1": "I believe it because my friend told me.",
    "choice_2": "I checked multiple sources before accepting it.",
    "choice_3": "It sounds good, so it must be true.",
    "choice_4": "I don't need to question it.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Critical thinkers evaluate information from multiple sources.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following improves critical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Bias",
    "choice_2": "Assumption",
    "choice_3": "Reflection",
    "choice_4": "Impatience",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Reflection helps evaluate and improve your thinking process.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which skill is most essential for critical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Jumping to conclusions",
    "choice_2": "Avoiding information",
    "choice_3": "Analyzing evidence",
    "choice_4": "Following orders",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Analyzing evidence is a key component of critical thinking.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Puzzle: If you rearrange the letters 'CIFAIPC', you would have the name of a(n):",
    "choice_1": "City",
    "choice_2": "Animal",
    "choice_3": "Ocean",
    "choice_4": "Pacific",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Rearranging the letters gives 'PACIFIC'.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which fallacy involves attacking the person instead of the argument?",
    "choice_1": "Straw Man",
    "choice_2": "Ad Hominem",
    "choice_3": "Red Herring",
    "choice_4": "Slippery Slope",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Ad Hominem attacks the individual, not their reasoning.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which is a characteristic of a strong argument?",
    "choice_1": "Unsupported claims",
    "choice_2": "Logical consistency",
    "choice_3": "Emotional appeals",
    "choice_4": "Vagueness",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Logical consistency makes arguments stronger and more convincing.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What should a critical thinker do when encountering new information?",
    "choice_1": "Accept it immediately",
    "choice_2": "Ignore it",
    "choice_3": "Evaluate its source and logic",
    "choice_4": "Memorize it",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Critical thinkers evaluate the credibility and reasoning behind information.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Puzzle: Mary's mother has four children – April, May, June, and __?",
    "choice_1": "July",
    "choice_2": "Mary",
    "choice_3": "March",
    "choice_4": "Jane",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The question starts with 'Mary's mother...' so the fourth child is Mary.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following is a barrier to critical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Open-mindedness",
    "choice_2": "Bias",
    "choice_3": "Inquiry",
    "choice_4": "Evaluation",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Bias can cloud judgment and prevent objective evaluation.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is a hypothesis?",
    "choice_1": "A final answer",
    "choice_2": "An emotional opinion",
    "choice_3": "An educated guess or assumption to test",
    "choice_4": "An unrelated observation",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "A hypothesis is a testable prediction or educated guess.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which is an example of deductive reasoning?",
    "choice_1": "All birds have wings; a pigeon is a bird; so it has wings.",
    "choice_2": "That dog is barking, it must be angry.",
    "choice_3": "I saw three swans; all swans must be white.",
    "choice_4": "I feel it's going to rain.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Deductive reasoning goes from general to specific.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Puzzle: I speak without a mouth and hear without ears. I have nobody, but I come alive with wind. What am I?",
    "choice_1": "Echo",
    "choice_2": "Storm",
    "choice_3": "Song",
    "choice_4": "Tree",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The correct answer is 'Echo'.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the goal of critical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "To argue with others",
    "choice_2": "To accept authority",
    "choice_3": "To make reasoned, well-thought-out judgments",
    "choice_4": "To memorize facts",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Critical thinking focuses on making reasoned judgments.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which type of reasoning goes from specific observations to general conclusions?",
    "choice_1": "Deductive",
    "choice_2": "Circular",
    "choice_3": "Inductive",
    "choice_4": "Fallacious",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Inductive reasoning builds generalizations from specific examples.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Puzzle: A farmer has 17 sheep. All but nine run away. How many are left?",
    "choice_1": 9,
    "choice_2": 8,
    "choice_3": 17,
    "choice_4": 0,
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "the phrase \"All but nine\" means that except for nine, all others ran away → 9 are left.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following is an example of critical thinking in daily life?",
    "choice_1": "Making assumptions about people",
    "choice_2": "Checking reviews before buying a product",
    "choice_3": "Accepting advertisements without question",
    "choice_4": "Spreading rumors",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Evaluating reviews involves research and judgment.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Puzzle: What gets wetter the more it dries?",
    "choice_1": "Sponge",
    "choice_2": "Towel",
    "choice_3": "Soap",
    "choice_4": "Bucket",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A towel dries things, and it gets wet in the process.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Why is it important to identify assumptions in critical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "To support biased views",
    "choice_2": "To limit new ideas",
    "choice_3": "To uncover hidden beliefs affecting judgment",
    "choice_4": "To agree with everyone",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Identifying assumptions clarifies hidden beliefs and improves logic.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Puzzle: Before Mt. Everest was discovered, what was the highest mountain in the world?",
    "choice_1": "K2",
    "choice_2": "Everest",
    "choice_3": "Makalu",
    "choice_4": "Kangchenjunga",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Mt. Everest was still the highest—it just wasn’t discovered yet.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following best defines critical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "Accepting information at face value",
    "choice_2": "Thinking that criticizes people",
    "choice_3": "Evaluating evidence before forming a judgment",
    "choice_4": "Memorizing large amounts of data",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Critical thinking involves evaluating evidence and arguments before forming a judgment.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the primary purpose of asking probing questions in critical thinking?",
    "choice_1": "To confuse the other person",
    "choice_2": "To deepen understanding",
    "choice_3": "To waste time in conversation",
    "choice_4": "To avoid making a decision",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Probing questions help in exploring deeper insights and gaining better understanding.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following is NOT a characteristic of a critical thinker?",
    "choice_1": "Open-mindedness",
    "choice_2": "Analytical skills",
    "choice_3": "Curiosity",
    "choice_4": "Bias",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Bias indicates a lack of objectivity, which is contrary to critical thinking.",
    "Topic": "Critical Thinking 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Follow the directions given below to answer the questions that follow. Your answer for each question below would be:\n\nA, if ALL THREE items given in the question are exactly ALIKE.\n\nB, if only the FIRST and SECOND items are exactly ALIKE.\n\nC, if only the FIRST and THIRD items are exactly ALIKE.\n\nD, if only the SECOND and THIRD items are exactly ALIKE.\n\nE, if ALL THREE items are DIFFERENT.\n\nPh #847-728-9676, Ph #847-728-9676, Ph #847=728-9676",
    "choice_1": "A",
    "choice_2": "B",
    "choice_3": "C",
    "choice_4": "D",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Only the first and second items given in the question are exactly the same hence option B is correct.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "You are given four lines of words. Each line contains the same words, displayed in a different order. Only one line has all words written/spelled correctly. You are to quickly determine which line of words is correct.1. Twitter, Facebook, Telegram, Youtube 2. Twitter, Facebok, Telegram, Youtube 3. Twiter, Facebook, Telegram, Youtube 4. Twitter, Facebook, Telegraam, Youtube",
    "choice_1": "Line 1",
    "choice_2": "Line 2",
    "choice_3": "Line 3",
    "choice_4": "Line 4",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "The correctly spelled words are \"Twitter, Facebook, Telegram, Youtube\".",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Direction: In each question below a combination of Name and Address is given followed by 4 such combinations in Options 1, 2, 3, and 4. The option that contains the same combination as the combination given in the question is the correct answer. Megha Kurkare Vishwa Vidyalaya Hinfmata 26 Ujjain 489650",
    "choice_1": "Megha Kurkare\nVishwa Vidyalaya\nHinmata 26 -\nUjjain 489650",
    "choice_2": "Megha Kurkare\nVishwa Vidyalaya\nHinfmata 26\nUjjain 489650",
    "choice_3": "Megha Kurkare\nVishwa Vidyalya\nHinfmata 26\nUjjain 489650",
    "choice_4": "Megha Kurkare\nVishwa Vidyalaya\nHinfmata 27 -\nUjjain 489650",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "The address in option 2 is same as in the given question",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Follow the directions given below to answer the questions that follow. Your answer for each question below would be:\n\nA, if ALL THREE items given in the question are exactly ALIKE.\n\nB, if only the FIRST and SECOND items are exactly ALIKE.\n\nC, if only the FIRST and THIRD items are exactly ALIKE.\n\nD, if only the SECOND and THIRD items are exactly ALIKE.\n\nE, if ALL THREE items are DIFFERENT.\n\nTNTNNNNTT, TNTTNTNNN, TNTNNNNTT",
    "choice_1": "A",
    "choice_2": "B",
    "choice_3": "C",
    "choice_4": "D",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Only the FIRST and THIRD items are exactly ALIKE hence option C is correct.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "You are proofreading an email and notice \"Definately\" written in it. Which is the correct spelling?",
    "choice_1": "Definately",
    "choice_2": "Defenitely",
    "choice_3": "Definitely",
    "choice_4": "Defanitely",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Definitely\" is the correct spelling",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If* stands for /, / stands for -,+ stands for * and -stands for +, then 100/16*4+9-7=?",
    "choice_1": 62,
    "choice_2": 72,
    "choice_3": 57,
    "choice_4": 71,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Apply BODMAS rule 100-16/4*9+7=71",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following sentences is correctly punctuated?",
    "choice_1": "Its raining outside, bring your umbrella.",
    "choice_2": "It’s raining outside; bring your umbrella.",
    "choice_3": "Its raining outside bring your umbrella.",
    "choice_4": "It’s raining outside bring your umbrella.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "It’s\" (it is) is correct. You need a semicolon to properly connect two independent clauses (\"It’s raining outside\" and \"bring your umbrella\").",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "An employee clocked in at 8:47 AM and clocked out at 5:12 PM. How many hours and minutes did they work?",
    "choice_1": "8 hours 15 minutes",
    "choice_2": "8 hours 25 minutes",
    "choice_3": "8 hours 30 minutes",
    "choice_4": "8 hours 20 minutes",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "From 8:47 AM to 12:00 PM → 3 hours 13 minutes.\n\nFrom 12:00 PM to 5:12 PM → 5 hours 12 minutes.\n\nTotal = 3h 13m + 5h 12m = 8h 25m.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A meeting agenda lists these times:\n\nIntroduction: 9:00 – 9:10\n\nProject update: 9:10 – 9:40\n\nBreak: 9:40 – 9:50\n\nWorkshop: 9:50 – 11:00\nThe total duration is",
    "choice_1": "1 hour 30 minutes",
    "choice_2": "2 hours",
    "choice_3": "2 hours 10 minutes",
    "choice_4": "2 hours 15 minutes",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Introduction: 10 min.\n\nUpdate: 30 min.\n\nBreak: 10 min.\n\nWorkshop: 70 min.\n\nTotal: 10 + 30 + 10 + 70 = 120 minutes = 2 hours",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "An instruction sheet lists the following steps:\n\nPreheat oven to 180°C.\n\nBake for 45 mins.\n\nCool for 20 mins.\n\nServe after 10 mins of resting.\n\nWhat is the correct total time?",
    "choice_1": "1 hour 5 mins",
    "choice_2": "1 hour 15 mins",
    "choice_3": "1 hour 20 mins",
    "choice_4": "1 hour 10 mins",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "45 + 20 + 10 = 75 mins → 1 hour 15 mins.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Follow the directions given below to answer the questions that follow. Your answer for each question below would be:\n\nA, if ALL THREE items given in the question are exactly ALIKE.\n\nB, if only the FIRST and SECOND items are exactly ALIKE.\n\nC, if only the FIRST and THIRD items are exactly ALIKE.\n\nD, if only the SECOND and THIRD items are exactly ALIKE.\n\nE, if ALL THREE items are DIFFERENT.\n\nEEGGGXYBSRREEE, EEGGGXYBSRREEE, EEGGGYYBSRREEE",
    "choice_1": "A",
    "choice_2": "B",
    "choice_3": "C",
    "choice_4": "D",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "FIRST and SECOND items are exactly ALIKE",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Direction:- The news item in each question below is to be classified into one of the following five areas:\n(1) Environment\n(2) Sports\n(3) Social Issues\n(4) Politics\n(5) Miscellaneous\nThe number of the area (1) or (2) or (3) or (4) as the case may be is the answer:\nA popular newspaper has started the Green India campaign in order to develop awareness among the citizens regarding the harmful effects of deforestation.",
    "choice_1": "Environment",
    "choice_2": "Sports",
    "choice_3": "Social Issues",
    "choice_4": "Politics",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "First, read the given statement then check the given options. As mentioned in the Question, we are to classify 'or' fit the given news to the best possible areas mentioned. We can now get the correct answer by simply eliminating the options.\nThe logic followed here is: This case belongs to the Environment as it was not related to Sports, Social Issues and Politics.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Our department handled 56 projects this year. Out of these, 18 were completed ahead of schedule, 27 on time, and 12 slightly delayed. Is there an error in these numbers?",
    "choice_1": "No error",
    "choice_2": "Number of delayed projects is incorrect",
    "choice_3": "Total projects do not add up correctly",
    "choice_4": "Number of on-time projects is incorrect",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "18 + 27 + 12 = 57, but total projects mentioned = 56. There is a mismatch in total.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence is both grammatically correct and logically consistent?",
    "choice_1": "Every participant and their guests is required to sign the register before leaving.",
    "choice_2": "Each of the engineers have submitted their weekly reports on time.",
    "choice_3": "Neither the manager nor his assistants knows the exact budget details.",
    "choice_4": "The data collected by the team were analyzed carefully and reveals promising trends.",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "In \"Neither...nor\" constructions, verb agrees with nearest noun (\"manager\"). Hence, \"knows\" is correct. Other options have agreement or logic errors.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A product description states: \"The new tablet weighs just 498 grams, measures 247mm x 178mm x 6.1mm, and offers up to 11 hours of battery life. It comes with a 12-megapixel rear camera and a 8 megapixels front camera.\" Which part contains a detail error?",
    "choice_1": "Battery life specification",
    "choice_2": "Rear camera resolution",
    "choice_3": "Front camera wording",
    "choice_4": "Weight figure",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "It says \"a 8 megapixels front camera\" — should be \"an 8-megapixel front camera\". Other details are correct.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence is grammatically correct?",
    "choice_1": "Each of the students have a laptop.",
    "choice_2": "Each of the students has a laptop.",
    "choice_3": "Every student have a laptop.",
    "choice_4": "All student has a laptop.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Each' is singular, so it should be \"has\".",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Find the correctly spelled word.",
    "choice_1": "Occured",
    "choice_2": "Occurred",
    "choice_3": "Occurrred",
    "choice_4": "Ocurred",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Occurred' is the correct spelling with double \"r\" and double \"c\".",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which number does not belong in the sequence: 3, 6, 9, 12, 14?",
    "choice_1": 6,
    "choice_2": 9,
    "choice_3": 12,
    "choice_4": 14,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "All others are multiples of 3; 14 is not.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Choose the correct sentence.",
    "choice_1": "Its a beautiful day.",
    "choice_2": "It's a beautiful day.",
    "choice_3": "Its' a beautiful day.",
    "choice_4": "Its a' beautiful day.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "It's is the contraction for \"it is\".",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "4. Follow the directions given below to answer the questions that follow. Your answer for each question below would be:\n\nA, if ALL THREE items given in the question are exactly ALIKE.\n\nB, if only the FIRST and SECOND items are exactly ALIKE.\n\nC, if only the FIRST and THIRD items are exactly ALIKE.\n\nD, if only the SECOND and THIRD items are exactly ALIKE.\n\nE, if ALL THREE items are DIFFERENT.\n\n2344-8765863.88,  2344-8765863.88,  2343-8765863.88",
    "choice_1": "A",
    "choice_2": "B",
    "choice_3": "C",
    "choice_4": "D",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Only first and second items given in the question are exactly same hence option B is correct",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Direction :- The news item in each question below is to be classified into one of the following five areas:\n(1) Environment\n(2) Sports\n(3) Social Issues\n(4) Politics\n(5) Miscellaneous\nThe number of the area (1) or (2) or (3) or (4) as the case may be is the answer:\nThree convicts fled away in a vehicle after a brief encounter with the Police.",
    "choice_1": "Environment",
    "choice_2": "Sports",
    "choice_3": "Social Issues",
    "choice_4": "Miscellaneous",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "1. First, read the given statement then check the given options.\n2. As mentioned in the Question, we are to classify 'or' fit the given news to the best possible areas mentioned.\n3. We can now get the correct answer by simply eliminating the options.\nThe logic followed here is:\nThis case belongs to the Miscellaneous as it was not related to Environment, Sports and Social Issues.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A summary states: \"We had 48 clients last quarter: 15 new, 20 returning, and 14 referred.\" Is this correct?",
    "choice_1": "Yes",
    "choice_2": "No",
    "choice_3": "Not enough data",
    "choice_4": "None of the above",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "15 + 20 + 14 = 49, but total mentioned is 48; there is a discrepancy.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence is fully correct?",
    "choice_1": "The data have been analyzed and show promising results.",
    "choice_2": "The data has been analyzed and show promising results.",
    "choice_3": "The data have been analyzed and shows promising results.",
    "choice_4": "The data had been analyzed and shows promising results.",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Data is plural; correct form is \"have been analyzed\" and \"show.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which number does not belong: 121, 144, 169, 225, 242?",
    "choice_1": 121,
    "choice_2": 144,
    "choice_3": 225,
    "choice_4": 242,
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "All others are perfect squares; 242 is not a perfect square.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Spot the error: \"The committee have agreed to submit their final report next week.",
    "choice_1": "Committee",
    "choice_2": "Have",
    "choice_3": "Their",
    "choice_4": "Report",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Committee is singular, so it should be \"has\" instead of \"have.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "An email reads: \"Please find the attatched document for your reference.\" Identify the typo.",
    "choice_1": "Find",
    "choice_2": "Attatched",
    "choice_3": "Reference",
    "choice_4": "Document",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Attatched is incorrect; correct spelling is \"attached.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A financial report states: \"The total expenditure this year was $525,000, with $120,000 on salaries, $200,000 on equipment, and $210,000 on marketing.\" Is this correct?",
    "choice_1": "Yes",
    "choice_2": "No",
    "choice_3": "Cannot determine",
    "choice_4": "Partially correct",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "120,000 + 200,000 + 210,000 = 530,000; reported total is $525,000, so it is incorrect.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which sentence is correct both grammatically and logically?",
    "choice_1": "Either the CEO or the managers attends the conference every year.",
    "choice_2": "Either the CEO or the managers attend the conference every year.",
    "choice_3": "Either the CEO or the managers attends the conferences every years.",
    "choice_4": "Either the CEO or the managers attend the conferences every years.",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "With \"either...or\", verb agrees with the nearer subject (\"managers\"); thus, \"attend\" is correct.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "If* stands for /, / stands for -,+ stands for * and -stands for +, then\n\n70/9*3+8-6=?",
    "choice_1": 53,
    "choice_2": 15.56,
    "choice_3": 52,
    "choice_4": 54,
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "the new series will be like: 70-9/3*8+6=\n\n76-3*8=76-24=52",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which word is misspelled in this sentence: \"The principle reason for the decline was the unexpected weather.",
    "choice_1": "Principle",
    "choice_2": "Reason",
    "choice_3": "Weather",
    "choice_4": "Unexpected",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Principle should be \"principal\" (main reason); \"principle\" means moral rule.",
    "Topic": "Attention to Detail 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following is a key benefit of teamwork?",
    "choice_1": "Decreased communication",
    "choice_2": "Increased conflict",
    "choice_3": "Shared responsibility",
    "choice_4": "Reduced productivity",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Teamwork distributes responsibility among members, making tasks easier to manage.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which quality is most important for effective teamwork?",
    "choice_1": "Selfishness",
    "choice_2": "Cooperation",
    "choice_3": "Avoidance",
    "choice_4": "Silence",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Cooperation helps members work towards a common goal smoothly.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is the main goal of teamwork?",
    "choice_1": "Individual achievement",
    "choice_2": "Personal recognition",
    "choice_3": "Achieving a common objective",
    "choice_4": "Avoiding work",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Teams exist to accomplish shared goals more effectively.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What skill helps team members understand each other better?",
    "choice_1": "Ignoring others",
    "choice_2": "Active listening",
    "choice_3": "Speaking over others",
    "choice_4": "Competition",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Active listening ensures ideas are understood and respected.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A team leader should mainly focus on:",
    "choice_1": "Doing all the work alone",
    "choice_2": "Controlling team members strictly",
    "choice_3": "Guiding and supporting the team",
    "choice_4": "Avoiding communication",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Leaders should empower and help the team rather than control them harshly.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "When conflicts arise in a team, the best approach is to:",
    "choice_1": "Ignore them",
    "choice_2": "Blame one member",
    "choice_3": "Discuss openly to resolve",
    "choice_4": "Leave the team",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Open discussion helps solve misunderstandings and promotes trust.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A cross-functional team is composed of members:",
    "choice_1": "From the same department only",
    "choice_2": "With similar skills",
    "choice_3": "From different departments",
    "choice_4": "Who never interact",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Cross-functional teams bring diverse skills from different areas.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is ‘synergy’ in teamwork?",
    "choice_1": "Working independently",
    "choice_2": "Team members producing less together than individually",
    "choice_3": "The combined effect is greater than individual efforts",
    "choice_4": "A type of competition",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Synergy refers to combined efforts producing better results than individual work.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What should a good team meeting include?",
    "choice_1": "Only one person speaking",
    "choice_2": "Clear agenda and active participation",
    "choice_3": "No time limit or structure",
    "choice_4": "Gossip and unrelated discussions",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "A focused agenda and participation keep meetings productive.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of these encourages effective collaboration?",
    "choice_1": "Micromanaging every detail",
    "choice_2": "Clear roles and responsibilities",
    "choice_3": "Strictly avoiding feedback",
    "choice_4": "No deadlines",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Clear roles prevent confusion and ensure accountability.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In Tuckman's model of team development, which is the final stage?",
    "choice_1": "Storming",
    "choice_2": "Norming",
    "choice_3": "Performing",
    "choice_4": "Adjourning",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "Adjourning is the final stage which involves the completion of the task or project",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which approach best mitigates ‘groupthink’ in a team?",
    "choice_1": "Encouraging critical evaluation",
    "choice_2": "Avoiding any disagreements",
    "choice_3": "Strong leader domination",
    "choice_4": "Suppressing minority opinions",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Critical evaluation helps avoid conformity and poor decisions.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which statement is true about virtual teams?",
    "choice_1": "They never require face-to-face communication",
    "choice_2": "Trust is easier to build than in co-located teams",
    "choice_3": "They rely heavily on technology for communication",
    "choice_4": "They have no need for clear goals",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Virtual teams depend on tools like video calls and messaging apps.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Belbin’s team roles theory suggests that:",
    "choice_1": "All team members should have the same role",
    "choice_2": "Different roles contribute uniquely to team success",
    "choice_3": "Teams perform best without any assigned roles",
    "choice_4": "Only leaders matter",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Diverse roles help cover different team needs and strengths.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of the following is NOT a characteristic of a high-performing team?",
    "choice_1": "Open communication",
    "choice_2": "Shared leadership",
    "choice_3": "Avoiding accountability",
    "choice_4": "Mutual trust",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "High-performing teams hold each other accountable to maintain standards.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.1"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In a team, what is the benefit of having diversity in skills?",
    "choice_1": "Reduces creativity",
    "choice_2": "Increases conflict only",
    "choice_3": "Encourages different perspectives",
    "choice_4": "Limits problem-solving",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Different skills and experiences help generate more innovative solutions.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is a sign of poor teamwork?",
    "choice_1": "High morale",
    "choice_2": "Open discussions",
    "choice_3": "Frequent misunderstandings",
    "choice_4": "Clear goals",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Misunderstandings indicate communication or trust issues.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Effective team members are usually:",
    "choice_1": "Rigid in their opinions",
    "choice_2": "Willing to adapt",
    "choice_3": "Focused only on personal gain",
    "choice_4": "Silent in meetings",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Adaptability helps team members adjust to changes and needs.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "When should feedback be given in a team?",
    "choice_1": "Only during annual reviews",
    "choice_2": "Never",
    "choice_3": "Regularly and constructively",
    "choice_4": "Only after big failures",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Continuous feedback improves performance and trust.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of these is essential for virtual team success?",
    "choice_1": "Reliable communication tools",
    "choice_2": "Avoiding video calls",
    "choice_3": "Strict office hours",
    "choice_4": "Minimal communication",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Tools ensure clear interaction despite physical distance.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What does ‘psychological safety’ in a team mean?",
    "choice_1": "Team members are afraid to share ideas",
    "choice_2": "Only leaders speak",
    "choice_3": "Members feel safe to take risks and express ideas",
    "choice_4": "No accountability exists",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Psychological safety encourages openness and innovation.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In distributed teams, a major challenge is:",
    "choice_1": "Too much face-to-face interaction",
    "choice_2": "Easy time zone management",
    "choice_3": "Building trust among members",
    "choice_4": "Overcommunication",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Physical distance makes establishing trust harder.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which leadership style often works best in high-performing teams?",
    "choice_1": "Autocratic",
    "choice_2": "Laissez-faire",
    "choice_3": "Authoritarian",
    "choice_4": "Democratic",
    "answer_key": 4,
    "Solution": "A democratic style encourages participation and ownership.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Team cohesion can be improved by:",
    "choice_1": "Promoting favoritism",
    "choice_2": "Having unclear roles",
    "choice_3": "Celebrating team achievements",
    "choice_4": "Discouraging social interaction",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Recognition builds morale and strengthens bonds.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which statement about conflict in teams is true?",
    "choice_1": "All conflict is harmful",
    "choice_2": "Conflict can lead to growth if managed well",
    "choice_3": "Teams should avoid conflict entirely",
    "choice_4": "Conflict reduces performance permanently",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Healthy conflict can improve ideas and relationships.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "What is ‘social loafing’ in teamwork?",
    "choice_1": "Taking initiative in tasks",
    "choice_2": "Contributing more than others",
    "choice_3": "Putting less effort in a group setting",
    "choice_4": "Encouraging collaboration",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Social loafing is when individuals rely on others to carry the workload.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "A key factor in maintaining accountability is:",
    "choice_1": "Lack of goals",
    "choice_2": "Vague expectations",
    "choice_3": "Clear performance metrics",
    "choice_4": "No deadlines",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Defined metrics clarify expectations and track contributions.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "Which of these best supports innovation in teams?",
    "choice_1": "Strictly following old methods",
    "choice_2": "Punishing mistakes harshly",
    "choice_3": "Encouraging experimentation",
    "choice_4": "Avoiding change",
    "answer_key": 3,
    "Solution": "Trying new ideas promotes learning and innovation.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "According to Lencioni’s model, a fundamental dysfunction of a team is:",
    "choice_1": "Excessive meetings",
    "choice_2": "Absence of trust",
    "choice_3": "Over-communication",
    "choice_4": "Too many ideas",
    "answer_key": 2,
    "Solution": "Lack of trust undermines team cooperation and effectiveness.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  },
  {
    "Question_Text": "In team decision-making, consensus means:",
    "choice_1": "Complete agreement after discussion",
    "choice_2": "Majority rule without discussion",
    "choice_3": "Only the leader decides",
    "choice_4": "Ignoring minority opinions",
    "answer_key": 1,
    "Solution": "Consensus aims for general agreement that everyone supports.",
    "Topic": "Team Working 1.2"
  }
]